<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁俊</mainName>
    <names>[丁永利, 沈华轩, 孟七, 郭际湘, 杨隆, 李洪春, 周瑞安, 丁连升, 丁俊, 任七, 叶春, 张七, 迟月亭, 许德义, 李连仲, 李鑫甫, 李际, 杨小楼, 长明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁宝祥</mainName>
    <names>[杨紫阳, 丁宝祥, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁建中</mainName>
    <names>[丁建, 张良, 丁正洪, 韩信]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁文元</mainName>
    <names>[杨少奎, 丁文元, 张家口, 彭风林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁春荣</mainName>
    <names>[丁春荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁晓君</mainName>
    <names>[李国粹, 李蓉芳, 穆桂英, 王娜娜, 丁晓君]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁果仙</mainName>
    <names>[红行腔, 郭凤英, 丁派, 丁家, 盖天, 班赴京, 葛亮, 毕生, 牛桂英, 孙竹林, 丁果, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁正洪</mainName>
    <names>[李庆魁, 张中, 古事今, 金泉, 施星夔, 丁正洪, 丁西汉, 宋桐斌, 古, 卢醒]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁立刚</mainName>
    <names>[丁立刚, 于德云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁至云</mainName>
    <names>[丁至云, 丁至]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁赛君</mainName>
    <names>[金艳芳, 金美芳, 刘金定, 郭暧, 梁山伯, 丁西, 林话剧, 徐天红, 吕瑞英, 魏银凤, 孔雀东南飞, 越艺社, 张桂凤, 周宝奎, 曹银娣, 丁赛, 夏梦, 王文娟, 范瑞娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>丁震春</mainName>
    <names>[丁, 汤怀尽, 张大军, 杨少朋, 唐, 张玉亭, 刘鼎五, 尚, 陈金柏, 马纪良, 丁震, 李钟林, 周龙, 赵永伟, 韩玉泉, 王平, 李, 姐夫, 俞鉴老, 朱彪, 周仲博, 周啸天, 马长礼, 班世超, 王璐, 袁金凯, 孙悟, 骆宏勋, 李鸣盛, 武生, 郭金光, 师承, 洪德佑, 李兰亭, 唐韵笙, 丁震春, 刘军, 金蝉, 素亚斌, 李少春, 十一郎, 丁晨, 周仲传, 梅花奖, 刘汉臣, 云遮月, 阎逢春, 郭金, 曹艺斌, 高盛麟, 吕锁森, 周亚川, 张铁华, 周少楼, 王京剧, 孙毓堃, 苏, 杨派著, 丁光荣, 闻占萍, 王小蓉, 何辉, 张德华, 马童, 韩长宝, 王玉蓉, 郑法祥, 震春, 王玉珍, 李鲜花, 安果良, 黄云鹏, 张老汉, 母王玉蓉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>万一英</mainName>
    <names>[王晓临, 万一英, 王梦云, 李多奎, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>严凤英</mainName>
    <names>[冯素贞, 赵, 刘凤云, 严凤英, 牛郎, 胡金涛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有严耕池的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>严顺开</mainName>
    <names>[韦维]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>乔志良</mainName>
    <names>[李力平, 乔志, 乔慧杰, 寇准, 刘, 乔志良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>乔清秀</mainName>
    <names>[乔喜楼, 奉天, 梁山伯, 周璇, 金秀, 于金秀, 王二姐, 鹿巧玲, 张金忠, 乔清, 乔利元, 袁金秀, 胡同, 康元林, 袁相巽, 马上乡, 孟姜, 临清, 李玉凤, 乔利, 乔派, 张氏, 安善义, 马前, 袁双玉, 玉茗春, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>乔韵如</mainName>
    <names>[叶盛兰, 张连福, 陈, 雷喜福, 乔韵如, 梅兰芳, 陈庆增]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于万增</mainName>
    <names>[杜近芳, 刘玉麟, 班晋京, 周仁, 罗成, 辜, 茹富兰, 宋庆龄, 江世玉, 茹绍荃, 于万增, 陈盛泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于世德</mainName>
    <names>[关东, 向建, 马三立, ，, 于, 白英杰, 韩光, 张寿臣, 林青, 董必武, 师娘, 李维信, 常宝霆, 侯宝林, 张书新, 周恩来, 金, 延泽民, 郝, 于世德, 常宝华, 马伟国, 周, 康德, 马, 张老, 陈毅, 张两次, 马三爷, 张伟振]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于世文</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 艾世菊, 邴勇, 鲁廷, 于世文, 钱元通, 迟世恭, 尚小云, 马昭仪, 王志廉, 张伯驹, 荣春社, 李正森, 苏盛贵, 高庆奎, 李宝荣, 胡盛岩, 尹培玺, 尹月樵, 奚啸伯, 黄世骧, 柳迎春, 刘杰, 诸世芬, 钱宝森, 张君秋, 赵世璞, 程砚秋, 张连福, 赵继斗, 马富禄, 王吟秋, 李适可, 赵荣琛, 贺后骂, 于元龙, 刘喜益, 鲍世德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于世猷</mainName>
    <names>[刘宝瑞, 郭全宝, 马志明, 侯长喜, 赵伟洲, 刘文亨, 郭启儒, 苏文茂, 王佩元, 于世猷]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于会江</mainName>
    <names>[赵学义, 宗白, 海纳, 张伯扬, 王文玉, 刘, 江, 阎秋, 江郎才尽, 孔明, 徐世昌, 关黄, 刘宝全]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于会泳</mainName>
    <names>[西泓, 于会泳, 江青]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于佑福</mainName>
    <names>[马三立, 西谦德, 刘宝瑞, 郭瑞林, 阎笑儒, 王嘉琪, 燕乐, 于佑福, 高德明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于元海</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 于连泉, 于元海, 元龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于光</mainName>
    <names>[于光]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于宝林</mainName>
    <names>[王鸣楼, 冯其清, 张文茹, 曾率, 佟有为, 陈文彦, 郭全宝, 李文英, 李润杰, 朱相臣, 双簧, 雷玉月, 于宝林, 陈鸣志, 姚文虎, 邓继曾, 赵文浩, 赵恒, 于文海, 刘巧儿, 吴文龙, 南开宝, 马树春, 李勇, 辛克正, 宫兰欣, 张振圻, 冯宝华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于枢海</mainName>
    <names>[蒋轸庭, 帅, 吕梁, 于枢海, 马轸华, 马顺, 万恒, 李自成, 伏于案头, 陈士, 陈常杰, 马爷, 于枢, 王致久, 于爷, 张庆常, 甘一, 王五, 马, 台高级, 于母, 小马轸华, 耿树清, 李金鳌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于玉蘅</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 徐美玲, 陈淑芳, 于奉, 刘长瑜, 王瑶卿, 刁丽, 张菁华, 四郎, 杨秋玲, 于玉蘅, 孙萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于维章</mainName>
    <names>[朱元龙, 马富禄, 于维章]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于连泉</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 陈永玲, 马思远, 马旦戏, 刘盛莲, 萧长华, 梅降雪, 巴骆, 张彩林, 贺人杰, 科班解散, 杨小楼, 连泉, 李丹林, 郭际湘, 王瑶卿, 田桂凤, 陈啸云, 桂森, 崔熹云, 尚派, 曾辅佐]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>于金骅</mainName>
    <names>[于金骅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>云燕铭</mainName>
    <names>[四人帮, 李少春, 赵桐珊, 冯子和, 张春华, 李洪春, 梅兰芳, 文联, 叶盛兰, 郭隆, 孔雀胆, 罗钜壎, 江汉, 王瑶卿, 杨宝森, 吴富琴, 周啸天, 杨门女, 袁世海, 马连良, 李宗义, 赵, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>五月仙</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>井存良</mainName>
    <names>[刘姥姥, 东瞅瞅, 西瞧瞧, 李大旗, 唐学峰, 杨永树, 高淑娟, 李亦平, 刘, 张关, 宋小川, 张杰, 程派, 井存良, 赵锡宇, 钟, 张, 张萍, 赵忠祥, 张火丁, 李佳峰, 陈星星, 钟强, 井存, 陈琪, 秦勤, 马小曼, 燕守平, 陈学欣, 赵大维, 张家口, 费玉明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>从鸿逵</mainName>
    <names>[梅兰芳, 孟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>付振江</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>代华春</mainName>
    <names>[谢幕, 代, 成基, 黄桂禄, 胡须变, 代华春, 蒋介石, 洪亮, 蒋, 岳母]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>任咪咪</mainName>
    <names>[滑稽, 马永贞, 张樵侬, 张冶儿, 程笑, 朱翔, 唐笑飞, 吴语, 杨笑峰, 托, 任担当]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>任宏恩</mainName>
    <names>[刘罗锅, 任宏恩, 周恩来, 刘少奇, 高秀敏, 胡涂盆, 李先念]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>任心才</mainName>
    <names>[徐达, 鲁西南, 吴桂远, 红十二, 杨继业, 任红脸, 大郎, 五郎, 孙膑, 诸葛亮, 张集井, 梁山寿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>任志秋</mainName>
    <names>[陈少霖, 于莲仙, 太, 任志秋, 李多奎, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何云伟</mainName>
    <names>[何云伟, 郭德纲, 李菁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何冠奇</mainName>
    <names>[王振濂, 李维康, 侯喜瑞, 禄, 何冠奇, 徐向, 陈瑞生, 宋, 包公, 刘长瑜, 荣同志, 保吉蕯姆, 诺姆, 秦腔, 李鸣岩, 武打光, 翁偶虹, 宋燕玲, 耿其昌, 焦裕禄, 何氏, 谢尔盖听, 胡学礼, 董翠娜, 何冠, 曹营心, 孙悟, 燕玲, 范钧宏, 刘秀荣, 斯拉夫, 秦香, 谢尔盖, 何回答]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何凤仪</mainName>
    <names>[何凤仪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何双呆</mainName>
    <names>[沈笑亭, 沈男, 李小呆, 姚慕双, 周柏, 何收姚, 何, 何双呆, 钮再呆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何叫天</mainName>
    <names>[何叫天, 杨六郎, 黄伯贤, 李秀成, 何万泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何恕</mainName>
    <names>[黄正勤, 华圣顿, 何明原, 孙毓敏, 李开屏, 周仁, 阎一川, 四郎, 张似云, 明原, 尤, 孔雀东南, 马少良, 苏武, 何恕, 孙正阳, 尤三, 薛亚萍, 齐淑芳, 马前, 李宝春, 宇宙锋, 童芷苓]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何文基</mainName>
    <names>[陈永, 曲友, 何文基, 汤伯玉, 蓬瀛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何时希</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 梅兰芳, 何时希, 赵桐珊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何景云</mainName>
    <names>[何景云, 须生, 四郎, 何达子]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何月山</mainName>
    <names>[刘清提]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何桂山</mainName>
    <names>[黄, 刘永春, 钟馗, 谭鑫, 俞菊笙, 籍贯一, 唐永常, 何九, 裘桂仙, 刘大头]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何玉茹</mainName>
    <names>[蒋军, 荣, 雷锋, 何质臣, 何玉茹, 何庆煜, 赵样娃]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何章</mainName>
    <names>[何章, 刘备, 何博众, 苏武, 王昭君, 何家传, 寿星, 太白, 何章少]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何金海</mainName>
    <names>[詹天, 戏德, 张美娟, 江汉, 沈三玉, 李金鸿, 诸连顺, 杜近芳, 陈少五, 李洪春, 何金海, 张正芳, 陈旧俗套, 马连良, 王玉蓉, 李玉芙, 叶红珠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>何顺信</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 双弓, 张派, 张君秋, 张秀琴, 张, 习京胡, 谢世, 华丽, 赵氏, 马蹄弓, 张派剧, 王泳泉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>余叔岩</mainName>
    <names>[吴铁庵, 张传, 周长顺, 孙菊仙, 钱金福, 刘仲秋, 樊棣, 李请益, 陈子, 谢萍苏, 王文卿, 刘十, 薛风池, 薛凤池, 田单, 黄幡绰, 谭, 孙养侬著, 高庆奎, 吴, 如松, 王瑞, 梅各树, 陈彦衡, 周德, 王平, 莫不欣, 习说白, 经余, 黄润甫, 李适可, 李育庠, 孟小冬, 姚文甫, 朱家夔, 李炳莘, 左足, 李佩卿, 李少, 张辽, 孟小, 孟氏, 李永年, 李谟, 谭派, 姜妙香, 张淇林, 柯操琴, 谭小培, 桑园, 王君直, 姚玉英, 范仲禹, 程门立雪, 赵贯一, 钱培荣, 杨宝忠, 陈德霖, 王月芳, 奚啸伯, 邹功甫, 龙套, 谭真传, 马鞭, 郝寿, 谭派靠, 叶氏, 琼林, 田桂凤, 李顺亭, 谭余, 魏铁珊, 贾丽川, 邱正坚, 曾作过, 窦砚峰, 薛观澜, 太平洋, 曹, 余伯清, 刘春, 王长林, 汤勤, 李龟年, 李岩, 梅兰芳, 李陵碑, 张, 张伯驹, 吴少霞, 吴连奎, 王佐, 赵氏, 朱, 徐凌霄, 杨小楼, 吴彩霞, 神童, 谭门, 薛传曹, 李经, 李, 王庾生, 钱金, 陈少霖, 程继先, 余, 王长, 姚增禄, 王凤卿, 叔岩, 孟, 胡琴, 朱顺, 杨, 刘如松, 周郎, 终天, 刘春喜, 尚和玉, 贾洪林, 毛韵, 石破天惊, 张文涓, 江上行, 陆炳之骂, 梅兰, 王, 谭富英, 张加, 李少春, 李德伦, 谭氏, 薛, 对于尔, 鲍吉祥, 丁字步, 裘桂仙, 祝荫, 王思及, 吴彦衡, 王之琴, 陈雪南, 孟派, 郭建, 杨中, 金福, 谭鑫, 陈大濩, 杨宝森, 曾与夫, 赵培鑫, 孟腔, 李直绳, 李至繁, 马连良, 王少楼, 叶, 谭鑫培, 张业才]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>余巧云</mainName>
    <names>[王宝钏, 李爱琴, 孟遏云, 李正敏, 王文鹏, 李, 肖玉玲, 于理, 舒展, 苏育民, 于动荡, 王玉琴, 秦相莲, 吴利民]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>余洪元</mainName>
    <names>[咸宁, 汪笑侬, 洪之召, 吕月樵, 沈月, 吴天保, 金, 张松, 李彩云, 周信芳, 胡双喜, 刘备, 陈旺喜, 汪, 习余, 袁心苟, 汪天, 汪则学, 诸葛亮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>余玉琴</mainName>
    <names>[余玉琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>余紫云</mainName>
    <names>[习花旦, 周明泰, 尤精, 余叔岩, 沈氏生, 李丙莘, 余慧清, 梅巧玲, 余紫, 宇宙锋, 于光绪, 梅玉配]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>佟雨田</mainName>
    <names>[汤民一]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯丹梅</mainName>
    <names>[侯剑光, 李雯敏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯佑宗</mainName>
    <names>[胡琴, 隆咚, 张家班, 郭小庄, 徐露, 侯, 王小明, 陈美麟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯双印</mainName>
    <names>[马六明, 李建, 侯双印, 侯长清, 李五, 侯, 侯长松, 武奎斌, 侯门为, 何斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯喜瑞</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 吴铁庵, 张胤德, 法门寺, 萧长华, 梅兰芳, 刘连荣, 杨得胜, 张关正, 荀慧生, 秦腔, 王竹忱, 张金波, 马谡, 黄老来, 马踏, 国林, 高庆奎, 叶春善, 尚长荣, 赵旺, 罗春友, 杨小楼, 鸿斌, 李仁, 孙盛文, 侯梦兰, 私淑黄, 郝寿臣, 李, 南金, 杨雄, 董维贤, 秦灿, 郝世洪, 李荣威, 张德俊, 侯派, 黄边, 李连元, 黄润甫, 许德福, 袁世海, 马武, 刘瑾, 曹连孝, 马, 袁国林, 倪荣, 朱斌, 毛泽东, 孟小冬, 黄盖, 俞振庭, 刘长瑜, 曾抓哏, 林子, 黄三泰, 尚小云, 韩乐卿, 姜妙香, 李逵, 邓九公, 侯饰, 谭小培, 侯, 张飞, 李光, 连泉, 李香匀, 黄, 成科, 富连成, 蒋少奎, 侯老寓, 黄笑, 刘大昌, 欧阳芳, 程砚秋, 李吉庆, 玉青, 马连良, 黄派, 万嘱咐, 马德成, 雷喜福, 马名群, 刘鸿声, 高音来, 曹操, 曹, 杨合演, 杨德胜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯宝林</mainName>
    <names>[朱阔泉, 侯宝, 关公战, 秦琼, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯少奎</mainName>
    <names>[王瑞芝, 钟馗, 武松, 赵松, 侯少奎, 侯炳武, 侯永奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯峻山</mainName>
    <names>[吴喜, 李慈铭, 刘备, 王氏, 赵云, 张飞, 孙尚香, 徐凤珠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯永奎</mainName>
    <names>[陈出新, 安平, 侯益才, 马祥麟, 武强, 韩世昌, 荀慧生, 华容, 活林, 侯永奎, 赵志刚, 安天, 王益友, 吴越, 荣庆社, 郝振基, 陶显庭, 文成, 张文生, 侯益, 武生, 童芷苓]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯玉山</mainName>
    <names>[王益友, 魏庆林, 富于乡]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯益隆</mainName>
    <names>[许世英, 尤擅, 李逵, 侯益隆, 张飞, 颜佩韦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯耀文</mainName>
    <names>[侯耀文, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯莉君</mainName>
    <names>[蒋调, 王魁负, 文莉, 侯, 俞调, 梁祝, 钱玲, 钟擅, 徒唐, 钟月樵, 陈亚仙, 徐琴芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯长山</mainName>
    <names>[侯长松, 侯长清, 侯长山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>侯长青</mainName>
    <names>[郭启先, 侯长青]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>俞世龙</mainName>
    <names>[张连福, 王喜秀, 俞世龙, 曹, 张盛禄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>俞丽萍</mainName>
    <names>[钟爱, 杨静红, 杨, 杨一麟, 赵开生, 常熟, 朱燕屏, 俞丽萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>俞大陆</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 俞振庭, 俞参加, 俞菊笙, 俞, 茹富兰, 高盛麟, 袁世海, 俞派, 雷喜福, 俞步兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>俞平伯</mainName>
    <names>[俞铭衡, 俞平伯, 俞许, 舒元炳, 太白, 张奚若, 曹雪芹, 朱自清, 俞平, 汤显祖, 周, 叶圣陶, 陈叔通, 许宝驯, 许宝, 郑振铎, 王府]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>俞建华</mainName>
    <names>[俞建华, 王派, 何天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>俞振庭</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 俞润, 俞永兴, 俞振庭, 班当, 于1906至, 孙毓堃, 徐碧云, 徐斌寿, 俞步兰, 俞永隆, 杨宝森]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>俞粟庐</mainName>
    <names>[容挥翰, 魏以告督, 钟湘, 盛泽, 俞粟庐, 曾祖, 俞派, 洪, 朱笔作, 吴江陆, 秋碧, 吴, 吴梅撰, 明嘉, 平泉, 沈景修, 曾文, 叶堂, 李钟珏, 于音韵, 金氏, 李朝斌, 魏, 俞振飞, 韩华卿, 王氏, 孙钟, 阴营守, 张公履, 官僚东, 杨乱作]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>俞菊笙</mainName>
    <names>[黄三雄, 刘永春, 俞振庭, 张二奎, 俞菊笙, 俞毛包, 习武旦, 尚, 胡, 俞所, 俞派, 汪桂芬, 杨双喜, 尚和, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>修正宇</mainName>
    <names>[颜文敏, 郭建光, 赵义庭, 张成玉, 李贵, 许仙, 韩琪, 熊友兰, 常香玉, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>傅全香</mainName>
    <names>[孙琴文, 张榕华, 梁山伯, 胡佩娣, 田汉, 张桂莲, 孔雀东南飞, 越艺社, 何英, 尹, 桂芳, 黄花瘦, 范瑞娟, 李亚仙, 李清照, 尹桂芳, 傅全香, 张春帆, 梁祝哀, 祝, 杜十娘, 华合作, 徐玉兰, 孔雀东南, 程砚秋, 鲍金龙, 孙泉香, 洪芬飞, 毛泽东, 李娃, 刘兰芝, 范分明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>傅希如</mainName>
    <names>[倪海天, 王平, 李玉声, 松安, 李春城, 王涌石, 秦琼, 张少楼, 高宠, 胡少, 华容, 曲咏春, 王思及, 梁斌, 高盛麟, 王云樵, 童强, 章晓申, 张文涓, 李浩天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>傅德威</mainName>
    <names>[丁永利, 杨荣环, 赵晓岚, 沈三玉, 吴素秋, 杨宝森, 毛世, 纪玉良, 陈少, 李盛藻, 周啸天, 李世芳, 王和霖, 尤擅, 王玉蓉, 白家麟, 李宗义, 徐东明, 宋德珠, 杨小楼, 李遍于, 程永龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>傅艺萍</mainName>
    <names>[傅艺萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>傅锦华</mainName>
    <names>[刘三姐, 王, 雷振邦, 蔡秀英, 刘, 毛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>储金鹏</mainName>
    <names>[谢鲲, 郑兴郎, 何玉郎, 双凤飞, 梁小鸾, 黄玉华, 李玉茹, 冯蕙林, 周仁, 俞振飞, 崔澥, 薛应龙, 宋德珠, 俞氏, 玉壶冰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>全巧民</mainName>
    <names>[周恩来, 贺龙, 刘少奇, 梅兰芳, 秦腔花旦, 宋尚华, 张蝶芬, 荀慧生, 贾莲, 王天民, 陈毅, 刘建中, 蒙师田]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>全常保</mainName>
    <names>[郑小山, 郭启儒, 孙士达]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>六小龄童</mainName>
    <names>[王大闹, 荣获2000, 颜世鹏, 程志, 金鹰, 孙悟空]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关学曾</mainName>
    <names>[杨八姐, 吴长宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关德咸</mainName>
    <names>[王, 柴头, 李多奎, 宋士杰, 咸发, 咸典当, 毛朋, 俞伯牙, 王延龄, 王金璐, 关德咸, 马, 赵金, 关德, 王和, 杨素贞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关栋天</mainName>
    <names>[关正明, 李蔷华, 马派, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关正明</mainName>
    <names>[关正明, 赵燕侠, 于世, 关盛明, 杜近芳, 李玉茹, 焦裕禄, 李文骙, 李蔷华, 四郎, 杨派, 郭玉昆, 马连良, 高盛麟, 李慧芳, 宋江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关灵凤</mainName>
    <names>[黄旗, 樊粹庭, 张国利, 凤凭, 陈素真, 凤凰, 樊, 韩盛岫, 崔, 梅兰芳, 霍梅英, 朱德, 崔兰田, 金嗓, 许, 常香玉, 习仲勋, 陈素, 周恩来, 正式拜, 刘少奇, 陈派, 凤深得, 穆桂英, 白素贞, 金定]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关玉峰</mainName>
    <names>[李沛泽, 郭兰英, 张垣, 李少春, 田华, 当关玉峰, 张记, 张德春, 张, 李啸仓, 牛桂英, 姚云龄, 白翠香, 史委拟, 王维, 花淑兰, 赵艳蓉, 闻占萍, 张顺泉, 刘玉婵, 周, 赵金蓉, 袁世海, 张庚, 阎王乐, 范合, 关玉峰, 赵丽蓉, 荆轲, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关盛明</mainName>
    <names>[王帽戏, 叶盛兰, 袁世海, 李盛藻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关立铨</mainName>
    <names>[李德子, 郑小山, 孙士达]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关美利</mainName>
    <names>[马金凤, 穆桂英, 关美利]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关翠兰</mainName>
    <names>[关翠兰, 华宝, 卢沟桥, 师哥, 徐家, 毛钱]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关肃霜</mainName>
    <names>[刘明辉, 王韵武, 梅兰芳, 邢美珠, 班进京, 秦竹影, 苏盛琴, 陈秀英, 徐巧玲, 冯琪, 周, 李丽芳, 穆桂英, 杨排风, 毛泽东, 谢瑶环, 高占祥, 王旗, 戴绮霞, 徐敏, 毛云婷, 雷峰, 陈月, 江青, 叶娘, 关肃霜, 李晓玉, 白素贞, 胡淑贞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>关鹤春</mainName>
    <names>[梅, 李春霖, 吴绛秋, 梅兰芳, 张畹秋, 胡, 王少卿, 陈啸秋, 王素鸾, 关鹤春, 关俊彦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冀韵兰</mainName>
    <names>[元兰, 李元芳, 翟永奎, 王盛意, 张君秋, 程砚秋, 张连福, 陈元, 夏永龙, 班里, 刘喜益, 萧连芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯允庄</mainName>
    <names>[郭沫若, 卖油郎, 冯和仪, 苏青, 赵丹, 李娃, 贾植芳, 屈原, 胡风]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯光钰</mainName>
    <names>[赵沨, 冯光钰, 融和, 师范]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯刚毅</mainName>
    <names>[冯刚毅, 陈笑风, 罗家宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯子和</mainName>
    <names>[王灵珠, 冯子, 赵桐珊, 李少棠, 周五宝, 曾得路, 冯三喜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯宝华</mainName>
    <names>[尹凤岐, 魏文亮, 尹笑声, 魏文华, 高笑, 和田, 班德贵, 冯宝华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯巩</mainName>
    <names>[冯巩, 高文, 刘伟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯志孝</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛武, 杨门女, 冯宇兰, 马连良, 袁世海, 冯志孝, 雷喜福, 李少春, 冯蕙林, 冯金芙, 寇准, 杜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯玉增</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 陈永玲, 冯玉增, 吴素秋, 孔雀东南]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯秀娟</mainName>
    <names>[周小红, 海燕, 韩兰根, 王, 王师母, 冯秀娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯蕙林</mainName>
    <names>[冯蕙林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯超</mainName>
    <names>[卓丽, 吴金富, 安冬, 金秋, 大朗, 赵磊, 冯超, 张艺贤]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>冯金芙</mainName>
    <names>[冯金芙, 冯蕙林, 冯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘世臣</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 李万春, 刘喜益, 刘世臣, 陈富康]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘丹丹</mainName>
    <names>[刘丹丹, 沈绮琅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘乃崇</mainName>
    <names>[刘乃崇]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘云天</mainName>
    <names>[曹云金, 刘艺, 刘云天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘伯玲</mainName>
    <names>[桑派, 马派, 刘伯玲, 郑观摩, 王月英, 秦雪, 桑振君, 桑派门楣, 桑, 王月, 程七, 南菊坛, 阎派, 程咬金, 桑振, 桑先生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘俊文</mainName>
    <names>[李兰亭, 习武生, 刘俊文, ，, 杨宝森, 刘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘元彤</mainName>
    <names>[魏莲芳, 法门寺, 梅葆玖, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 张, 李世芳, 刘元彤, 盛章, 苏盛琴, 晋绥, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘元汉</mainName>
    <names>[刘元汉, 孙盛文, 刘砚亭, 袁世海, 钟馗, 谭富英, 李少春, 宋富亭, 谭世英, 叶盛章, 杨宝森, 叶盛茂]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘兰秋</mainName>
    <names>[刘兰秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘剑士</mainName>
    <names>[滑稽, 王桂英, 马屁, 杭滑, 曹操曹, 张冠, 刘笑声, 刘, 汪顺仙, 李祺生, 张慧莺, 秦剑, 王雅莺, 吴剑伟, 骆驼, 李戴, 刘剑士, 魏忠年, 姚冷鸥, 孟血儿, 朱秋僧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘吉典</mainName>
    <names>[詹天, 古谱, 郭沫, 马可, 刘吉典, 毛, 金田, 杨芝华, 孔雀胆, 崔承喜, 刘吉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘喜奎</mainName>
    <names>[东天, 曹锟, 周恩来, 刘喜, 谭鑫, 刘, 梅兰芳, 崔承炽, 田汉受, 荀慧生, 张勋, 班稍加, 程砚秋, 燕燕, 贩夫, 刘喜奎, 杨柳青, 曹棍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘宗华</mainName>
    <names>[刘宗华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘宗杨</mainName>
    <names>[范, 过继杨, 杨无子, 安天, 杨在, 刘宗华, 杨前室, 刘长瑞, 迟世恭, 蔡荣贵, 迟温媛, 丁永, 杨为, 谢世, 甘宁, 丁氏, 刘砚亭, 袁世海, 杨派风, 刘宗年, 杨仍以, 刘砚芳, 刘宗绪, 刘宗杨, 杨小楼, 刘殿魁, 范福泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘宝全</mainName>
    <names>[刘顺全, 王广福, 向石, 金慧君, 侯月秋, 宋, 宋玉昆, 胡十, 刘宝, 徐母骂, 玉昆, 韩永忠, 刘, 华容, 缪庄严, 徐疾, 李逵, 刘派, 赵云, 韩永禄, 关黄, 刘宝全, 高亭, 孙玉卿, 二本战, 谭鑫, 桑红林, 谭凤元, 王庆, 于京, 马头, 胡, 宋五, 霍连, 马, 石韵, 霍明亮, 刘能, 曾用名, 钟俊峰, 韩德荣, 曹, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘宝瑞</mainName>
    <names>[马三立, 殷文硕, 刘宝瑞, 周恩来, 唐杰忠, 正式拜, 刘宝, 韩复榘, 刘少奇, 高元钧, 张寿臣, 李洁尘, 刘, 朱德, 赵佩茹, 毛泽东, 连升, 高洪顺, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘小楼</mainName>
    <names>[刘翠霞, 刘小楼, 崔护, 柳毅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘小琴</mainName>
    <names>[叶秀榕, 张建斌, 薛家传, 孟月华, 凤仪, 梁天来, 王友道, 李小白, 林芝芳, 徐小玉, 金谷兰, 谢婉萍, 刘小琴, 谢巧星, 龙凤金, 安安, 施剑翘, 刘依灶, 柳桂英, 董小狐, 严兰贞, 张青, 黄秀春, 杨胜打, 孙传芳, 秋桂, 孙尙香, 杨粒俤, 杨师傅, 秋泪, 蒋老五]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘延广</mainName>
    <names>[刘延广, 程咬金, 韩复榘, 李三, 秦琼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘志鹏</mainName>
    <names>[刘志鹏, 张信安, 刘, 赵静波, 鲁达, 刘云龙, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘忠河</mainName>
    <names>[张子林, 红脸, 菏泽, 汤兰香, 马双枝, 唐玉成, 王柳圈]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘成基</mainName>
    <names>[刘成基, 毛延寿, 胡琏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘搏</mainName>
    <names>[郭新生, 刘习, 孔祥仁, 汪荣汉, 吴建平, 刘搏, 张少华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘文亨</mainName>
    <names>[马三立, 郭荣, 冯立权, 薛宝琨, 任文利, 庄文, 李鸣岐, 法门寺, 张嘉利, 王文玉, 秦琼, 笑昆, 于宝林, 苏文茂, 何迟, 常宝霆, 班德贵, 赵佩茹, 赵心敏, 侯宝林, 刘广文, 王文进, 田立禾, 魏文亮, 杨少奎, 刘文贞, 张宝如, 燕, 刘文亨, 范振钰, 于佑福, 于世猷, 关公战, 刘文, 魏文华, 李伯祥, 丁文元, 郭, 阎笑儒, 黄铁良, 耿宝林, 曹, 赵连升, 张振圻, 孙兴海, 冯宝华, 马敬伯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘文亮</mainName>
    <names>[杨丽花, 刘南芳, 唐美云, 刘文亮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘斌昆</mainName>
    <names>[贺氏, 法门寺, 李玉茹, 赵桐珊, 班，拜克, 吴素秋, 陆续拜, 梅兰芳, 卓别林, 周信芳, 姜妙香, 张文远, 尤, 徐凌云, 刘祥云, 李春森, 刘韵芳, 郭春山, 刘燕云, 刘二混, 刘公道, 吴国太, 刘斌昆, 俞振飞, 杨宝森, 蒋干, 贾珍, 金松, 程砚, 张三, 马连良, 班名丑, 秋配, 尤三, 周信, 琴雪芳, 刘饰演, 刘斌, 赵桐顺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘昭容</mainName>
    <names>[刘昭容]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘曾复</mainName>
    <names>[王则昭, 侯喜瑞, 钱金福, 曾受, 杨宝森, 钱宝森, 王凤卿, 华容, 刘曾复, 文武, 安居平, 杨小楼, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘木铎</mainName>
    <names>[文联, 杨得禄, 刘双楫, 李逵, 马少波, 刘艺舟, 王素云, 牛郎, 刘木铎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘桂欣</mainName>
    <names>[王玉敏, 李金泉, 刘桂欣, 刘, 徐少, 李多奎, 李派, 桂欣, 周恩来]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘梅村</mainName>
    <names>[文联, 靳慧, 张斌, 李二嫂, 刘家奎, 郭沫, 鲁剧, 吕剧团, 吕剧, 刘奇英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘梓钰</mainName>
    <names>[马三立, 陈, 吕汶, 杨磊, 陈笑暇询, 陈重点, 刘梓钰, 鲁迅, 陈笑暇, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘正辉</mainName>
    <names>[柏淼, 吴汝俊, 琴筒, 高占祥, 李慕良, 许久, 龙盘竹, 梅缔, 张敏, 姜克美, 皮京胡, 丁振春, 樊汝武, 袁庆芬, 胡演奏, 乐海, 王彩云, 宋飞, 周佳悦, 胡演, 胡琴拉, 高玉倩, 燕, 李滨, 松香, 王济夫, 周巍峙, 刘正辉, 欧阳, 胡琴, 胡制作, 杨燕毅, 长处得, 毛竹, 张瑞龄, 肖像, 王铁成]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘永春</mainName>
    <names>[刘永春, 刘万义, 沈德奎, 刘明久, 孙菊仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘汉臣</mainName>
    <names>[刘天仰, 毕庶澄, 张宗昌, 李景林, 毕庶, 赵广顺, 郑长泰, 刘汉臣, 张正义, 刘, 高, 梅兰芳, 刘天, 高立, 胡琴, 杨, 高三奎, 厉大森, 杨小楼, 刘母]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘洪元</mainName>
    <names>[刘洪元, 谢派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘洪沂</mainName>
    <names>[李国盛, 侯宝, 陈涌泉, 李立山, 侯耀华, 王谦详, 侯耀文, 李, 刘醒民, 刘, 李金斗, 姜昆, 郭德纲, 侯派, 柳活, 刘际, 石富宽, 刘一举, 刘立求, 李建华, 侯, 刘洪沂, 李嘉存, 武大郎, 赵伟洲, 陈寒柏, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘洪滨</mainName>
    <names>[六连战, 刘洪滨, 杨立德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘洵</mainName>
    <names>[曾名, 吴春奎, 刘洵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘浩鹏</mainName>
    <names>[宋桐斌, 刘浩鹏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘淑云</mainName>
    <names>[孙毓敏, 吴素秋, 刘淑云, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘淑萍</mainName>
    <names>[张淑桂, 暴风雪, 米酒歌, 马泰, 叶玉菡, 小桃红, 孙涛, 朱母, 刘淑萍, 李忆兰, 高洁, 施秀琴, 刘萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘爱音</mainName>
    <names>[张琪, 张国强, 马泰, 宋丽, 李金铭, 戴月琴, 赵丹红, 王大力, 杨八姐, 李爽, 李梓厚, 李惟铨, 周连生, 张超群, 邹海群, 王婧, 刘爱音, 张文鹏, 黄平, 屠夫, 杨三姐, 王平, 陈胜利, 马惠民, 周仁, 刘易新, 孙路阳, 高, 牛郎, 张继民, 刘文田, 王丽京, 刘德士, 刘巧儿, 吕布貂, 于海泉, 王景明, 茹桂林, 郑岚, 秦香, 刘萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘玉朋</mainName>
    <names>[刘君秋, 刘玉朋, 刘桂荣, 刘八, 刘玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘玉玲</mainName>
    <names>[刘玉玲, 李桂云, 李云卿, 王春娥, 李最为, 孙尚香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘玉麟</mainName>
    <names>[周正荣, 戴绮霞, 焦鸿英, 吕布, 张翼鹏, 刘玉麟, 李凤翔, 文武, 金素琴, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘琢瑜</mainName>
    <names>[孙权, 孙桂, 王晓波, 郑成功, 张海峰, 张连祥, 李岩, 宋小川, 张飞归, 张曼玲, 王硕, 孙权后, 王尊龙, 阎王, 杨秋玲, 耿其昌, 魏玛, 孙盛文, 董卓, 吴钰璋, 张国良, 李, 首席特, 李欣嗓, 郑子茹, 周仁, 胡雪岩, 王别姫, 杨国忠, 苏武, 袁世海, 张超, 冯志孝, 孙岳, 赵荣欣, 马小曼, 文朗, 秦香, 李广仁, 魏绛, 李维康, 李克用, 杨春霞, 刘长瑜, 魏延, 景荣庆, 李逵, 张飞, 李光, 方荣翔, 董洪松, 杜近芳, 夏韵, 王泉奎, 刘琢瑜, 黄三, 周德威, 王晶华, 刘子蔚, 何金海, 包青, 李斯特, 张洪祥, 胡雪严, 孙盛竹, 子坏, 王建男, 刘秀荣, 孟良, 阎罗梦, 刘大可]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘琦</mainName>
    <names>[刘琦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘琪</mainName>
    <names>[邱富棠, 赵桐珊, 金, 马宗慧, 宋德珠, 刘琪, 王凤朝, 宋派戏, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘百雄</mainName>
    <names>[狄青, 谢瑶, 梅花簪, 徐九, 刘百雄, 袁崇焕, 姚璇, 赵氏, 杨奇国]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘秀梅</mainName>
    <names>[刘秀, 骆玉笙, 刘秀梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘秀荣</mainName>
    <names>[梅派戏, 王瑶卿, 俞振飞, 田汉, 牛郎, 王派, 孔雀东南, 白素贞, 刘秀荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘立福</mainName>
    <names>[陈士, 张寿臣, 张健声, 陈派, 刘健英, 刘瑞森, 刘立福]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘绿萍</mainName>
    <names>[刘绿萍, 陈谊君, 郑小玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘美娟</mainName>
    <names>[刘美娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘翠霞</mainName>
    <names>[李金顺, 刘翠霞, 李师父, 高亢, 李含玲, 白玉霜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘英男</mainName>
    <names>[刘英, 冯不异, 刘英男, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘荣升</mainName>
    <names>[孙家鸿, 刘邦, 厉彦芝, 巴蜀, 刘卖座, 刘荣升, 刘, 梅兰芳, 赵小楼, 周信芳, 景韵琴, 刘奎官, 赵君玉, 王少泉, 谭派, 赵如泉, 刘去, 杨延辉, 武双林, 鲁肃, 刘搭班, 杨畹农, 卢翠兰, 朱双云, 张凤栖, 骆艳, 蒋宝印, 孙盛辅, 孙对, 刘奎童, 富连成, 孙坐科略, 孙, 杨玉华, 张义得, 雷喜福, 马, 赵荣琛, 康春京, 陈琨, 周信, 武生, 厉慧森, 刘演, 厉慧兰, 沈鸿鑫著, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘荣芝</mainName>
    <names>[杨三姐, 李宝琴, 凤仪, 皮秀英, 张郎休, 荣获金, 白清, 穆桂英, 伍桂珍, 吕咸蔚, 丁香, 刘荣芝, 李宝凤, 刘永芝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘赶三</mainName>
    <names>[王兰凤, 双奎, 张芷芳, 伊子, 刘干升, 和春, 张三元, 张子玖, 刘, 王松林, 胡五儿, 刘宅遣, 刘赶三, 王行六, 蔡六儿, 侯家后, 张喜子, 张梅五, 李高阳, 王行七, 成胜, 李保, 李二同, 胡同, 孙妇, 左足悬, 王行五, 刘赶, 梅毒, 胡琴, 王顺福, 孙大, 王长寿, 胡同文, 李敬三]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘连伦</mainName>
    <names>[王月楼, 郭元祥, 刘连仑, 梁连柱, 张建国, 萧长华, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 王俞鉴, 蒋世英, 樊富顺, 李盛荫, 苏盛琴, 张飞, 孙悟空, 刘元鹏, 陈玉贤, 马派, 侯宝, 金玉恒, 李蓉芳, 蔡宝华, 钱振义, 胡, 刘连伦, 马连良, 王和霖, 李慧芳, 孙琳, 李鸣盛, 曾用名, 穆耀, 郭金光, 栾平, 赵丽蓉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘连群</mainName>
    <names>[刘连群]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘长瑜</mainName>
    <names>[荀慧生, 姚淑芳, 尤, 陈素贞, 周长瑜, 李玉茹, 金鹰, 燕燕, 刘长瑜, 俞振飞, 江苏无, 陈伯华, 梅兰芳, 王秀兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘雪涛</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 赵燕侠, 敬竹, 刘俊亭, 仲仁, 马最良, 谭富英, 李玉芝, 白玉薇, 赵燕, 李洪春, 秋瑾, 荀慧生, 姜妙香, 徐碧云, 俞步兰, 吴彩云, 李万春, 赵晓岚, 梁小鸾, 奚啸伯, 刘雪涛, 金, 杨宝森, 李盛藻, 张君秋, 程砚秋, 马连良, 雷喜福, 李宗义, 徐斌寿, 徐东明, 迷竹, 陈盛泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘韵成</mainName>
    <names>[刘韵成, 王英, 吴彦蘅, 李世济]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘顺</mainName>
    <names>[陈寿峰, 王私班, 刘顺, 谭竹坡, 梅兰芳, 沈立, 谭鑫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>刘鸿声</mainName>
    <names>[袁, 汪各派, ，, 融入娃, 张二奎, 刘唱, 姚俊卿, 刘, 孙菊, 李素, 黄某, 辛亥革命, 赵如泉, 庞少卿饰, 袁世, 赵福, 刘派, 赵云, 谭, 张郃, 何桂山, 骂杨, 莫怀古, 杨小楼, 刘永春, 王平, 龙腔, 谭派老生, 班后, 谭鑫, 陈月, 四郎, 王福卿, 苏武, 殷虎臣, 汪, 周济, 刘鸿声, 司马昭, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>包丹庭</mainName>
    <names>[王, 祝宽, 曹心泉, 祝祖, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 顾赞忱, 钟秋岩, 叶盛兰, 张伯驹, 荣春社, 许仙, 杨慕兰, 于程, 赵啸澜, 侯氏, 袁寒云, 赵子敬, 王宅, 顾森柏, 赵子衡, 张紫仙, 于陆, 皮簧之]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>包会申</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>华世丽</mainName>
    <names>[云赞许, 李世芳, 孔雀东南飞, 李少春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有华世香的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>华传萍</mainName>
    <names>[杭, 丁兰荪, 华传萍, 杜丽娘, 姜花右]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>华慧麟</mainName>
    <names>[李琴仙, 简中, 华慧麟, 周正, 曹佛生, 华月英, 艾美君, 刘长瑜, 王瑶卿, 冯子和, 周长云, 常代师, 宋巧, 曹毅琳, 刘秀荣, 梅兰芳, 杨秋玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>华文漪</mainName>
    <names>[希拉里, 华美, 文漪, 梅花奖, 华文漪, 俞振飞, 梅兰芳, 刘厚生, 苏盛义, 朱传茗, 范蠡, 华昆, 班升格]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>华粹深</mainName>
    <names>[俞平伯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>华素琴</mainName>
    <names>[田婶, 周恩来, 杨门, 武松, 周信芳, 菊香, 周, 华素琴, 穆桂英, 琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>华香苓</mainName>
    <names>[郭少良, 荣联, 华香, 华香苓, 曾师, 巴蜀, 席上宾, 程地宇, 韩俊卿, 王世富, 王正余, 江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>单冬阳</mainName>
    <names>[刁六, 令人捧腹, 万高贵, 单冬阳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>单绍莲</mainName>
    <names>[罗焕跪, 杨八姐, 穆桂英, 穆杨]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>南奇</mainName>
    <names>[南奇]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>十三郎</mainName>
    <names>[谢君豪, 郁郁而终, 万恶之夫, 十三郎, 薛觉先]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>卢宝全</mainName>
    <names>[胡, 阎秋霞, 卢宝全, 刘宝全]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>卢德先</mainName>
    <names>[邱涣, 张仲珺, 丁​​, 法门寺, 杨淑蕊, 华文漪, 卢德先, 史洁华, 尤, 丁梅魁, 齐淑芳, 卜世英, 黄金懋, 宇宙锋, 李小春, 李, 陈同申, 高蕙兰, 张少楼, 胡, 蔡青霖, 杨门女, 曹, 李宝春, 张文涓, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>卢醒笙</mainName>
    <names>[鲁智深, 卢醒笙, 本, 李长彩, 卢宝昆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>厉彦芝</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 厉彦芝, 厉家班, 曾拜罗, 吕宋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>厉慧兰</mainName>
    <names>[厉彦芝, 周慧江, 厉慧斌, 杨延昭, 厉慧敏, 寇准, 韩凤奎, 沈福存, 四郎, 鲁肃, 孔明, 韩凤英, 厉慧良, 厉慧森, 厉慧兰, 杨家将]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>厉慧敏</mainName>
    <names>[荀, 潘奎祥, 杨家, 厉家班, 王蕙芳, 厉慧斌, 周利, 班给毛, 金碧艳, 厉老, 厉慧敏, 梅兰芳, 毛, 荀慧生, 刘玉琴, 程砚秋, 何曼清, 韩凤英, 厉慧良, 厉慧, 厉慧森, 厉慧兰, 周瑜, 陈盛泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>厉慧斌</mainName>
    <names>[李逵, 厉慧斌, 王洪奎, 张飞, 孟燮卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>双文兴</mainName>
    <names>[双文星, 李佩, 双厚坪, 杨振纲, 双文兴, 陈荫荣, 东悦轩, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培, 刘宝全, 沈小庆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>双阔亭</mainName>
    <names>[张二, 谭, 梅先生, 班中, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>史依弘</mainName>
    <names>[许美玲, 张美娟, 上海逸夫, 史依弘, 王英, 李金鸿, 杜近芳, 李玉茹, 扈三娘, 白玉兰, 于永华, 艾丽雅, 史敏, 卢文勤, 谭盾, 师华华, 史敏天, 张洵澎, 杨秋玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>史若虚</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 侯喜瑞, 贺敬之, 张春孝, 法门寺, 周扬, 苗培, 刘长瑜, 四朗, 田汉, 尚小云, 秦基伟, 姜妙香, 荀慧生, 钮骠, 张正芳, 谭小培, 艾美君, 叶少兰, 杨秋玲, 耿其昌, 林彪, 任北平, 万风妹, 宋任穷, 刘复之, 郝寿臣, 史若虚, 李, 王瑶卿, 贾桂, 江青, 彭真, 张君秋, 万汝泉, 孔雀东南, 杨门女, 曹禺, 孙岳, 贺后骂, 吕班, 刘喜奎, 李先念, 叶莲, 晋察, 刘秀荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>史行</mainName>
    <names>[刘胡兰, 鲁艺, ，, 李翰祥, 史行, 邵逸夫, 夏梦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶复润</mainName>
    <names>[周正荣, 叶树润, 徐九, 张鸿福, 叶复润, 陶所得, 李桐, 魏海敏, 曹, 徐九经一角]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶少兰</mainName>
    <names>[俞亲授, 吕布, 叶明工, 周仁, 俞振飞, 罗成, 太白, 阎庆林, 叶盛兰, 蓬, 金泰, 叶少兰, 富布赖特, 许嘉宝, 陈盛泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶德霖</mainName>
    <names>[叶德霖, 蒋干, 崔子明, 王文瑞, 曹宝禄, 刘宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶盛富</mainName>
    <names>[叶盛华, 叶盛宝, 叶盛贵, 叶春荣, 叶盛富, 舒桐, 叶盛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶盛长</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 陈绍武, 叶盛章, 王喜秀, 宋继亭, 李欣, 梅兰芳, 叶盛兰, 程砚秋, 张连福, 马连良, 雷喜福, 赵氏, 李盛荫, 叶盛长, 孙岳, 叶红珠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶福海</mainName>
    <names>[叶春善, 叶福海]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶英盛</mainName>
    <names>[叶英盛, 叶]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶蓬</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 谭正岩, 王瑞芝, 杨森, ，, 李少春, 李保良, 刘建杰, 凌科, 陈俊, 白登, 孙慧珠, 杨洁, 宋继亭, 张克, 叶盛兰, 张少春, 张火千, 谭, 李俊, 冯辉, 叶春善, 艾美君, 张远宁, 叶蓬, 赵永伟, 马力, 叶蓬自, 赵贯一, 杨家, 叶光为, 朱陆豪, 王平, 黄炳强, 李剑, 杨宝森, 四郎, 杜, 叶伯英, 于魁智, 徐滢, 范梅强, 谭小羽, 杨, 雷喜福, 赵荣琛, 尹章旭, 曹, 李宝春, 赵大维, 杜鹏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶铁森</mainName>
    <names>[叶铁森]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶鸣兰</mainName>
    <names>[叶鸣兰性, 宋宝罗, 鲍毓春, 叶喜琴, 刘云兰, 钟强, 洪, 张二鹏, 叶鸣兰, 洪云艳, 荣春, 京剧团, 叶, 张晓莺, 赵麟童, 叶家香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>叶龙章</mainName>
    <names>[叶龙章, 萧长华, 正志, 张学良, 徐树铮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>司骍</mainName>
    <names>[吴钰璋, 吴汝俊, 杜近芳, 李, 穆人智, 刘长瑜, 汪荣汉, 秦琼, 杨门女, 南锣, 满江红, 孙岳, 杨秋玲, 耿其昌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吉凤贞</mainName>
    <names>[张宝奎, 程玉英, 罗倌班, 王曾生, 须生, 田汉, 李玉琦, 安顿, 南定, 牛桂英, 杨贵仙, 刘玉富, 李景云, 刘俊英, 李, 晋中, 丁果仙, 四郎, 井陉, 万福, 刘玉婵, 晋剧, 班里, 高文翰, 刘玉, 张家口, 李宏发, 郭汉城, 四人帮, 郝珍, 李二位, 李兰亭, 王桂兰, 张垣, 李芝华, 田里, 吉风贞, 张庆云, 胡子生, 王金, 王金奎, 吉凤贞, 江汉, 刘志兰, 柳迎春, 王玉莲, 刘志海, 孙文升, 蒋伯骥, 王宝钏, 吉凤贞便, 程砚秋, 周济, 乔玉仙, 张美琴, 翟翼, 许万恒, 张北]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吉坪三</mainName>
    <names>[吉三天, 李长彩, 吉评, 秦佩贤, 吉坪三, 于万, 张佩如, 冯昆志]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吉有芳</mainName>
    <names>[梅花, 金秋, 刘秀走, 武俊英, 西厢, 张生房, 钟情, 吉有芳, 王艺华, 刘秀, 王存, 红娘凸, 贾永爰, 吉有, 崔莺莺, 红娘, 王秀兰, 王存才, 曹庄妻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吕传洪</mainName>
    <names>[苏昆, 王, 华传浩, 徐园, 吕传洪, 庄职员, 蔡传锐, 王洪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吕佳</mainName>
    <names>[吕佳, 吴美玉, 赵国珍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吕咸蔚</mainName>
    <names>[吕咸蔚, 李宝凤]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吕少明</mainName>
    <names>[施肥, 王光美, 刘少奇, 苏北县乡, 曲苑, 吕少, 终生, 文联, 小雪, 张永熙, 吕少明, 张北侯, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吕明发</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 范, 吕贵, 吕明发, 吕明, 王家班]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吕瑞英</mainName>
    <names>[王桂英, 苏娇, 梁山伯, 十一郎, 唐, 于杭, 孙智君, 张咏梅, 张, 越艺社, 刘觉, 范瑞娟, 吕派, 班）科, 刘金定, 袁派, 金采风, 吴素英, 陈辉玲, 丁赛君, 张传芳, 吕瑞英, 朱传茗, 穆桂英, 梁红玉, 张桂凤]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吕香君</mainName>
    <names>[王宝钏, 荀, 倪志秋, 吕慧君, 秋江, 张似云, 张和生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴双艺</mainName>
    <names>[滑稽, 吴双艺, 朱德, 姚慕双, 周恩来, 陈毅, 李先念, 周柏春, 董必武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴同宾</mainName>
    <names>[吴同宾, 吴小如, 何迟, 鲜灵, 欧华, ，, 吴, 杜十娘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴咏梅</mainName>
    <names>[秦琴, 郑观, 曲艺社, 方言美, 吴咏梅, 吴咏, 国华, 小燕飞, 孙大夫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴媚媚</mainName>
    <names>[沈凤喜, 滑稽, 吴一笑, 何丽娜, 王小毛, 周恩来, 吴媚媚, 张媚娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴富琴</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 孙良知, 陈朝红, 李珠明, 贺后骂, 张美华, 朱彩英, 吴富琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴小如</mainName>
    <names>[吴同宝, 卓著, 燕京]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴小楼</mainName>
    <names>[秋海棠, 小白玉, 舒展, 刘, 郑芝龙, 诸暨, 袁宝藩, 张行简, 梅剧团, 尹, 桂芳, 金育青, 吴小楼, 金三, 李, 袁雪芬, 邢竹琴, 陈孝忠, 云华, 杨同时, 安达, 金红, 贺老六, 徐兰, 上官仪, 班到, 梅花魂, 陈琴香, 陈东初]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴彦衡</mainName>
    <names>[连良, 吴彩霞, 吴荣喜, 王月芳, 谭富英, 谭鑫, 李洪, 杨宝森, 李洪春, 丁连升, 吴彦衡饰, 荀慧生, 王富刚, 赵家楼, 吴少霞, 吴彦衡, 袁世海, 杨武生, 许德义, 陈秀英, 谭嘉瑞, 班社]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴彩霞</mainName>
    <names>[吴彩霞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴春礼</mainName>
    <names>[吴春礼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴晓雷</mainName>
    <names>[吴派, 张春雷, 罗一雷, 吴晓雷, 胡琴腔, 吴, 黄精髓, 裘盛戎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴本贞</mainName>
    <names>[郭兰英, 双盛, 王桂兰, ）, 马枣林, 刘钰, 张俊祥, 史改梅, 赵汝, 金金奎, 张, 孙宝锤, 关胜斌, 刘秀, 毛毛旦, 骆驼, 盖天红, 胡闹, 牛桂英, 陈玉林, 马都教, 王玉琛, 吉凤贞, 王杰, 李, 丁果仙, 李清志, 孙膑, 郭寿山, 曹艳霞, 刘玉婵, 李胜和, 吴本贞, 班行当, 孙文生, 吴本, 王璧, 师傅, 江橹, 董士, 乔鹏飞, 荣祯, 吕桂荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴松岩</mainName>
    <names>[刘欢, 吴钰璋, 郑, 刘开基, 马韵甫, 吴松岩, 刘, 孙, 吴虹移, 吴炳璋, 随夫, 马氏, 沙淑英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴梅</mainName>
    <names>[吴梅对, 宋, 唐, 吴梅有, 卢扁, 田汉, 梅兰芳, 顾曲麈, 瞿安, 吴, 郑振铎, 李旗, 俞振飞, 李旗屯, 朱自清, 吴梅诞, 吴梅因, 曲学通, 吴梅一生, 吴林, 法曲续, 任, 曲学之明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴江秋</mainName>
    <names>[文武, 王瑶卿, 吴江秋, 吴绛秋, 江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴炳璋</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 杨荣环, 吴钰璋, 李维康, 杨宝忠, 方荣翔, 张素英, 王瑞芝, 丁至云, 王瑶卿, 徐兰沅, 马韵甫, 吴松岩, 赵建华, 于魁智, 万瑞兴, 王玉敏, 吴, 赵冬生, 杨柳青, 李光, 杨秋玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴琛</mainName>
    <names>[吴琛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴碧波</mainName>
    <names>[刘胡兰, 吴碧波, 陈素真, 赵艳蓉, 赵青和, 吴桂玲, 穆桂英, 花木兰, 田敏, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴祖光</mainName>
    <names>[莫负, 江文, 吴韶, 梅兰芳, 牛郎, 吴祖光, 吴瀛, 吴, 毛泽东, 吴召石]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴素秋</mainName>
    <names>[荀慧生, 张羽煮, 魏莲芳, 何佩华, 赵桐珊, 苏小妹, 吴素秋, 陈盛荪, 吴玉蕴, 伊帕尔罕]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴素秋</mainName>
    <names>[吴素秋, 赵, 尤见, 杨淑英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴蕙兰</mainName>
    <names>[吴蕙兰, 吴正秀]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>吴铁菴</mainName>
    <names>[吴铁菴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周云亮</mainName>
    <names>[鲍骆, 周恩来, 李砚萍, 周振海, 刘奎官, 周云亮, 徐剑豪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周亚川</mainName>
    <names>[高亮, 徐策, 武生, 朱佩兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周仲春</mainName>
    <names>[裴艳玲, 刘润林, 宗泽, 杨淑蕊, 孙毓敏, 尚小云, 周仲春, 梁山, 周毓麟, 罗长德, 赵世璞, 霍小玉, 习武生, 李紫贵, 梁红玉, 阎桂祥, 王树芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周企何</mainName>
    <names>[张采芹, 王治安, 何在戏, 宁欣, 于川剧, 张少华, 何热忱, 何经, 唐, 肖著, 周企, 罗成, 关山月, 冯灌父, 周企何, 何玉山, 安安, 张大千, 徐悲鸿, 陈书舫, 宋书田, 周海波, 秋江, 唐荫甫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周传沧</mainName>
    <names>[张铭荣, 苏, 徐亨, 易名, 沈斌泉, 张三, 周紫云, 周传沧, 施春轩, 刘铁嘴, 刘异龙, 刘唐, 朱义]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周传瑛</mainName>
    <names>[况钟, 双塔, 吕布, 唐明皇, 苏昆, 沈斌, 沈月, 赵传珺, 郑元和, 王魁, 周信芳, 徐继祖, 张君瑞, 许仙, 张飞, 王传淞, 后昆, 赵汝舟, 潘必正, 张宗祥, 洪升逝, 唐伯虎, 雷峰, 李洪基, 苏, 汪世瑜, 沙哑, 盛, 张传芳, 周传瑛, 朱传茗, 周, 张三郎, 沈月泉, 周传铮, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周信芳</mainName>
    <names>[汪笑侬, 刘邦, 冯子, 宋, 陈鹤峰, 王魁, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 杨建忠, 潘月樵, 王鸿寿, 李如春, 张扬, 徐策, 李吉瑞, 陈少云, 江青, 周少麟, 马, 陈规, 周信, 董小宛, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周凤文</mainName>
    <names>[邱凤翔, 周凤文, 周云瑞, 张氏味]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周利</mainName>
    <names>[沈健瑾, 沈世华, 郭仲英, 尚慧敏, 孙明珠, 刘世翔, 周利, 花木兰, 阎桂祥, 宋丹菊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周剑萍</mainName>
    <names>[周剑萍, 赵文华, 汤勤, 何学秋, 吴静芝, 张维桢]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周和桐</mainName>
    <names>[马连良, 王和霖, 郝寿臣, 周和桐, 谭富英, 赵氏, 宋德珠, 裘盛戎, 胡传葵, 鲍吉祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周啸天</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 吴铁庵, 丁至云, 谭富英, 李多奎, 王泉奎, 四郎, 张春华, 尚小云, 周啸, 章遏云, 周啸天, 张君秋, 张春樵, 叶盛兰, 朱玉良, 袁世海, 张少甫, 王玉蓉, 郭仲麟, 厉慧良, 金友琴, 陆文龙, 马艳云, 侯永奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周坪镇</mainName>
    <names>[张鹤瑞, 刘鹤兰, 崔鹤桐, 周八套, 李鹤仙, 王鹤轩, 于京, 于津宅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周子厚</mainName>
    <names>[谭富英, 丁至云, 金小香, 杨宝森, 毛世, 尚小云, 周德禄, 荀慧生, 周子, 荣春社, 李世芳, 汪子良, 梁慧超, 周子厚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有周少安的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周少楼</mainName>
    <names>[唐凤喜, 王芸芳, 唐韵笙, 鲍骆, 白玉昆, 刘汉臣, 继承杨, 周少, 周志杰, 夏侯淳, 赵松樵, 孙悟空, 周少楼, 周凯亭, 花荣, 孙二娘, 乌龙, 唐（韵笙, 俞华庭, 毛, 杨瑞亭, 杨乃武, 诸武生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周慰堂</mainName>
    <names>[周信芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周明泰</mainName>
    <names>[安信托, 冯维敏, 周馥嫡, 陈金雀, 周学熙, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 汤海, 汤显祖, 曹文澜, 沈流, 杨小楼, 刘宝全, 周叔迦, 易卦, 周明泰, 高亭, 陈, 陆来, 堂原, 张风翼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周曼如</mainName>
    <names>[梅, 周德宽, 关麟, 梅对周, 穆柯寨, 梅兰芳, 周曼, 周算, 周曼如, 德太郎, 周以]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周柏春</mainName>
    <names>[姚振民, 滑稽, 姚周, 马家骏, 蒋阿桂, 姚慕双, 周恩来, 黄鱼调, 周柏春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周桦</mainName>
    <names>[陈素真, 李战, 俏丽, 秦雪, 崔派, 阎派, 马, 陈（素, 周桦, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周正荣</mainName>
    <names>[周正荣, 陈斌雨, 杨, 汪, 马, 谭, 陈秀华, 刘, 刘嵩樵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周海泉</mainName>
    <names>[何海龙, 左足, 周青山, 赵公明, 周海泉, 文武, 曹操一角, 周刚, 曹操]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周玉峰</mainName>
    <names>[周玉峰, 金蛇郎, 汪精卫, 张唯一]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周玉泉</mainName>
    <names>[周玉泉, 张福, 徐翰芳, 徐云志, 周伯庵, 夏荷生, 华伯明, 周调, 蒋月泉, 徐伯菁, 文武, 薛君亚, 田习]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周瑞安</mainName>
    <names>[杨派武, 高庆奎, 周春, 周瑞安, 杨派, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周瑞深</mainName>
    <names>[胡丽泉, 曲笛不辍, 周瑞深, 周秦, 许雨香, 李受章]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周百穗</mainName>
    <names>[魏莲芳, 孙荣蕙, 苏三, 刘长瑜, 尚小云, 尚, 梅兰芳, 荀慧生, 李铁梅, 燕燕, 俞素秋, 尚长荣, 杨畹农, 杨玉环, 梅玉配, 柯湘, 周百穗, 李, 李慧娘, 周秀英, 虞姬, 朱传茗, 杨门女, 穆桂英, 白素贞, 李喜鸿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周筱芳</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 杨延, 周筱芳, 郑巧娘, 夏, 郭华, 罗瑞卿, 须生, 臧道纯, 周信芳, 闻知周, 马麟, 周庭福, 张云霞, 陈云观, 王官保, 张艳芳, 叶素娟, 唐伯虎, 卖油郎, 杨延昭, 班文武, 贾宝玉, 毛, 融会贯通, 杨二舍, 昌平, 唐伯虎点, 张云良, 顾少春, 曹锦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周越桂</mainName>
    <names>[董永, 周越, 周, 周春生, 徐如英, 周氏, 周越桂, 高腔, 周春聚, 周春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周金福</mainName>
    <names>[李洪才, 蒋干, 周金福, 周瑞安, 连升, 周二奎, 汤勤, 周斌秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周铨庵</mainName>
    <names>[周明泰, 袁寒云, 郑传鉴, 周恩来, 王纪英, 华传浩, 终生, 张传芳, 张卫东, 韩世, 后起, 朱传茗, 辛巳, 沈盘生, 谢锡, 朱复, 管怀明, 周铨庵, 仝秀兰, 沈传芷]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周锦堂</mainName>
    <names>[谭富英, 被杨, 周不忍, 唐, 梅兰芳, 董美, 黄蟒, 王朝奎, 王汉声, 李权, 李少兰, 华乐, 周锦堂, 周琼仙, 孙竹轩, 罗香圃, 范仲儒, 罗老板, 张宜伦, 惠, 罗记群, 董竹君, 马连良, 刘菊生, 汪润泉, 杨继芝, 王少楼, 董小宛, 周除, 冯子钧, 叶艳华, 白蟒]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>周雪峰</mainName>
    <names>[汪世瑜, 周雪峰, 蔡正仁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>呼少起</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>哈元章</mainName>
    <names>[周正荣, 张连福, 马连良, 李金棠, 叶盛长, 吴盛珠, 四郎, 胡盛岩, 胡少]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>唐世辛</mainName>
    <names>[李万, 唐鹤华, 唐世辛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>唐云峰</mainName>
    <names>[刘成基, 唐云峰, 周, 屈原]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>唐喜成</mainName>
    <names>[吴同保, 陈素真, 李世民, 杨藩, 唐喜成, 董暄, 罗成, 杨家赤, 双官诰, 万民, 赵王, 穆桂英, 赵云, 陈有才, 唐王, 杨延景, 魏德海]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>唐在炘</mainName>
    <names>[闵兆华, 赵燕侠, 沈家宏, 秋操琴, 唐在炘, 李世济, 谭富英, 穆铁芬, 师从, 唐, 徐, 徐兰沅, 林, 周长华, 炘, 毛, 张君秋, 程砚, 程砚秋, 毕生, 马连良, 唐在忻, 熊承旭, 叶]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>唐杰忠</mainName>
    <names>[柳堡, 刘, 唐杰忠, 刘宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>唐涤生</mainName>
    <names>[白雪, 陈锦棠, ）, 唐雪卿夫, 白驹荣, 郑孟霞, 十三郎, 马师曾, 芳艳, 薛觉清, 唐雪卿, 明清, 侯门深, 唐涤生, 郎乃唐, 于利, 红线女, 何非凡, 吴楚帆, 罗艳卿, 南海十三, 吴君丽, 谢汉扶, 薛觉先]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>唐美云</mainName>
    <names>[唐, 唐美, 蒋武童, 唐艳秋, 张慧川, 唐美云, 李祥石]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>唐韵笙</mainName>
    <names>[徐策, 刘青堤, 刘媒婆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>喜彩莲</mainName>
    <names>[李金顺, 洪深, 张菡香, 刘翠霞, 翠竹, 田汉, 马泰, 魏荣元, 杨大娘, 欧阳予, 张润时, 袁天成, 向阳, 洪亮, 付桂香, 孔雀东南, 杨乃武, 吴寿朋, 马连良, 杨母, 梁红玉, 韩世忠, 陈快腿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>固桐晟</mainName>
    <names>[李庆魁, 西门豹, 正式拜, 郭沫, 曲协, 范进, 陈士]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>国少卿</mainName>
    <names>[宋永珍, 马胜奎, 乌盆计, 陈氏, 张别古, 宋凤云, 利清楚, 王氏, 王玉蓉, 王金奎, 梁春楼, 王庆奎, 崔灵芝, 徐淑贤, 金刚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>夏文兰</mainName>
    <names>[姜昆, 夏文兰, 倪明, 相声]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>夏晓华</mainName>
    <names>[夏晓华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>夏月珊</mainName>
    <names>[汪笑侬, 夏月珊, 冯子, 周凤文, 孙菊仙, 夏月, 汪桂, 孙菊, 秋瑾, 孙中山, 拿破仑, 辛亥革命, 陈英士, 潘月樵, 陈鸦片, 周长山, 夏月润]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>夏永泉</mainName>
    <names>[杨文广, 诸葛亮, 梅兰芳, 夏永泉, 穆桂英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>夏荣庭</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 李大春, 陈永玲, 苏连汉, 夏荣庭, 唐长利, 宋富亭, 张飞, 尚小云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>夏雨田</mainName>
    <names>[夏雨田]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>夏韵龙</mainName>
    <names>[安平, 高韵, 夏, 陈俊杰, 孙履真, 龙顿, 周信芳, 夏玉龙, 谭, 韩少芳, 曹世才, 刘海蟾, 孙盛文, 李万春, 宋富亭, 孟姜, 罗长德, 陈富瑞, 王子江, 苏武, 杨燕毅, 王金龙, 裘盛戎, 程永龙, 张永贤, 康万生, 沈三玉, 鲍骆, 谭富英, 朱一戒, 叶盛章, 李洪春, 张春华, 龙, 陈世新, 徐和才, 黄彦忠, 于鸣奎, 刘庆先, 西萍乡, 王海波, 张君瑞, 李元霸, 宋昌林, 郭春山, 方荣翔, 江汉, 夏韵, 孙毓堃, 李韵章, 王泉奎, 王文祉, 富连成, 沙致和, 杨宝森, 杨元, 裘, 邓沐玮, 班初, 董鹤春, 王连平, 孟广禄, 夏永龙, 李太白, 李宗义, 张学津, 夏韵龙, 吴富友, 邓通, 高材生, 贺永祥, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>奚中路</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 奚啸伯, 杨玉娟, 贺永华, 金, 武文华, 茹元俊, 苏德贵, 梅兰芳, 梁斌, 奚延宏, 倪, 武生, 厉慧良, 黄元庆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>奚啸伯</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 奚啸伯, 法门寺, 侯玉兰, 赵德钰, 张建国, 李洪春, 四郎, 奚, 梅兰芳, 孟筱伯, 杨志刚, 徐慕云, 欧阳, 胡琴, 毕生, 苏武, 范进, 李德彬, 李伯培, 金友琴, 胡碧兰, 曹, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚世茹</mainName>
    <names>[姚世茹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚佩兰</mainName>
    <names>[替夫, 徐菊芬, 姚席珍, 姚佩秋, 徐仲熙, 徐姓, 双兰英, 徐母骂, 易名, 姚佩兰, 梅兰芳, 姚荫, 于新明, 徐菊华, 王毓楼, 双兰, 许德义, 王明华, 曹, 杨小楼, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚慕双</mainName>
    <names>[硬朗, 周, 姚慕双, 周柏, 于育, 姚锡祺, 周柏春, 姚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚撼岳</mainName>
    <names>[姚撼岳, 秦香, 包龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚月芝</mainName>
    <names>[姚月芝, 红珊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚玉兰</mainName>
    <names>[杜月, 荣, 姚长海, 鲁肃, 王伯当, 姚玉英, 姚玉兰, 周瑜, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚玉英</mainName>
    <names>[姚玉英, 姚玉兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚迅</mainName>
    <names>[姚迅, 梁荫堂, 后台, 罗伞, 马, 林月玲, 小武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姚长海</mainName>
    <names>[姚长海, 姚玉英, 姚玉兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姜双喜</mainName>
    <names>[杨小朵, 姜双喜, 张天元, 贾洪, 郑秀兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姜凤山</mainName>
    <names>[四人帮, 赵燕侠, 梅, 谭富英, 曾拜, 张鑫奎, 毛世, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 叶盛兰, 姜凤山, 李福庆, 宋德珠, 杜近芳, 沈雁西, 周恩来, 孙毓堃, 梅葆玖, 正式拜, 徐兰沅, 杜奎三, 张君秋, 梅腔, 王少卿, 周, 马连良, 穆桂英, 玉轩帮, 刘宗杨, 王琴生, 程永龙, 胡同缀, 梅葆玥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姜双喜</mainName>
    <names>[杨小朵, 姜双喜, 张天元, 贾洪, 郑秀兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姜培培</mainName>
    <names>[姜培培, 王思及, 李陵碑·清官, 王珮瑜, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姜妙香</mainName>
    <names>[荀令香, 王蕙芳, 韩世杰, 冯蕙林, 夏, 陈金雀, 罗成, 梅兰芳, 茹莱卿, 田际, 姜妙香, 徐和才, 张, 田宝琳, 姜有, 马派戏, 穆天, 西皮快, 陆杏林, 高庆奎, 叶少兰, 于万增, 姜妙, 杨小卿, 南天, 闫庆林, 黄定, 陈德霖, 刘鸿升, 刘雪涛, 袁青云, 梅派, 四郎, 王凤卿, 何时希, 潘经荪, 班接纳, 千金, 王少卿, 程砚秋, 马连良, 穆桂英, 卓著, 朱素云, 江世玉, 武功, 吉祥, 周瑜, 沈曼华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姜存瑞</mainName>
    <names>[曲荟, 蒋轸庭, 吕梁, 杨柳青, 顾存德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姜昆</mainName>
    <names>[姜昆, 李文华, 张扬某, 梁左, 唐杰忠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姜铁麟</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 陈富康, 吴素秋, 毛世, 梁秀娟, 姜铁麟, 周信芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>姬少戎</mainName>
    <names>[姬少戎, 裘盛戎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>娄振奎</mainName>
    <names>[叶盛兰, 赵文奎, 冯玉增, 陈富瑞, 袁世海, 洪亮, 李德奎, 杜近芳, 李少春, 富英, 李倚重, 王泉奎, 杨宝森, 张元智, 红于津, 李盛藻, 娄振奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>嫩娘</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孔宪珠</mainName>
    <names>[孔宪珠, 孔宪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙书筠</mainName>
    <names>[玉杰, 李逵, 刘派, 赵云, 韩梅, 徐母骂, 张飞, 刘, 曹, 杨凤杰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙亮</mainName>
    <names>[米福生, 刘福生, 郑士哲, 茹元俊, 裴元庆, 马玉璋, 杨长秀, 李景德, 武功, 黄云鹏, 孙亮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙元坡</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 孙元彬, 侯喜瑞, 宋丹, 邹氏, 张秀, 宋富亭, 曹操戏, 孙元坡, 班进京, 宋丹菊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙养侬</mainName>
    <names>[孙养侬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙勇波</mainName>
    <names>[孙勇波, 习文武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙培亭</mainName>
    <names>[孙培亭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙宝才</mainName>
    <names>[赵玉贵, 周吴, 杨, 钱桌, 孙宝才, 蒋, 郑王, 李, 孙宝, 双簧, 戴花, 李宗仁, 东方红, 赵钱孙, 毛泽东, 毛, 高德亮, 太阳升]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙富琴</mainName>
    <names>[孙富琴, 王秋荣, 王秀芹, 李魁元, 李双凤, 陈素珍, 李淑兰, 梁兴, 班唱武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙怡云</mainName>
    <names>[陈德霖, 王长林, 孙怡云, 法门寺, 李, 谭鑫, 任俊峰, 王瑶卿, 全禄, 四郎, 孙菊, 庆林, 曾搭, 田宝琳, 钱秋, 玉成, 荣寿, 小生德, 汪桂芬, 桑园, 穆长久, 熊连喜, 孙双玉, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙明珠</mainName>
    <names>[孙明珠, 尚小云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙晋昆</mainName>
    <names>[孙晋昆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙晨</mainName>
    <names>[唐, 曲苑, 左权, 刘, 尹相杰, 杨蕾, 候耀华, 广泉, 李金斗, 刘流, 孙晨, 王敏, 戴志成, 唐静, 范雷, 王平, 杨少华, 王景, 侯耀文, 李, 李奎宝, 赵保乐, 李滨, 潘, 魏积安, 石富宽, 李伯祥, 戴志诚, 师胜杰, 黄玉玲, 赵, 巩汉林, 齐立强, 富宽, 朱军, 白桦, 马马杜, 黄晓娟, 李琦, 林永健, 苏文茂, 郭冬临, 姜昆, 郑健, 赵安, 高玉庆, 卓林, 洪剑涛, 曹颖, 陈连富, 李嘉存, 陈寒柏, 韩影, 刘俊杰, 李国盛, 刘惠, 贾成伯, 王馥丽, 唐杰忠, 牛成志, 纪念浦, 刘亚津, 汪洋, 孙伟, 李建华, 刘洪沂, 刘全刚, 李慎符]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙普协</mainName>
    <names>[文成, 孙普协]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙柏龄</mainName>
    <names>[李瑞来, 凤宝桐, 韩金奎, 张二鹏, 孙派, 唐, 田华, 梅兰芳, 徐碧, 周信芳, 荀慧生, 露兰春, 孟鸿茂, 汪派真, 高雪樵, 黄元庆, 路虹光, 李如春, 董卓, 孙操琴, 何月山, 小赵, 红净, 刘斌昆, 奚啸, 孙, 李桂春, 张胜奎, 周, 汪, 张英俊, 孙瑶芳, 赵, 詹世辅, 余京, 松樵, 裘盛戎, 赵燕侠, 老赵, 吕布, 唐韵笙, 张翼鹏, 冯子, 谭富英, 田记, 黄忠, 刘汉臣, 柏龄, 李长胜, 梁次珊, 谭派, 赵如泉, 朱德, 明毓昆, 赵云, 张文祥, 吴石坚, 张飞, 文武, 赵松樵, 诸葛亮, 戚艳冰, 周五宝, 孙柏龄, 刘松樵, 苏, 杨宝森, 毛, 辕门, 汪志奎, 马连良, 宋庆龄, 王少楼, 郑法祥, 欧阳德, 李宗义, 陈琳, 薛平贵, 孙是]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙毓堃</mainName>
    <names>[俞振庭, 侯喜瑞, 范宝亭, 汪悦春, 谭富英, 朱琴心, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 胡筱舟, 孙洪勋, 荀慧生, 俞菊, 赵云, 高庆奎, 宋德珠, 李光, 杨小楼, 李浩天, 杨派武, 侯喜, 李玉声, 孙挑梁, 安天, 孙毓堃, 沈宝桢, 俞菊笙, 杨宝森, 杨乃, 曾传其, 俞, 高牧坤, 杨, 马连良, 李可]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙毓敏</mainName>
    <names>[赵绮霞, 陈, 李金鸿, 孙毓敏, 孙毓, 梅兰芳, 张君秋, 荀慧生, 霍小玉, 薄情郎, 赵德勋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙玉奎</mainName>
    <names>[勾脸, 何金海, 李和, 赵永泉, 孙, 孙玉奎, 随李, 李]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙玉菊</mainName>
    <names>[杨门女, 常香玉, 孙玉菊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙瑶芳</mainName>
    <names>[张建强, 孙若英, 孙瑶芳, 梅兰芳, 孙柏龄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙甫亭</mainName>
    <names>[刘清提, 王梦云, 赵葆秀, 李氏, 梅兰芳, 王晶华, 孙甫亭, 荀慧生, 孙门, 曾替乃, 谢宝云, 朱母, 王晓临, 王树芳, 孙振才, 曾拜罗, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培, 朱痕记]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙盛云</mainName>
    <names>[李元瑞, 李玉声, 孙盛云, 宋玉庆, 茹元俊, 杨派, 王连平, 曲咏春, 潘侠风, 谭, 刘砚芳, 于富, 李光]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙盛文</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 孙棣珊, 叶氏昆, 法门寺, 谭世英, 孙棣棠, 荣庆, 蔡荣贵, 尚小云, 李欣, 荀慧生, 叶盛兰, 荣春社, 刘砚亭, 宣武, 李逵, 朱文英, 张飞, 梁秀娟, 孙盛文, 沈世启, 马名骏, 吴钰璋, 黄, 孙毓堃, 淑英, 李, 裘, 李荣威, 李盛藻, 陈世峰, 王泊生, 孙盛武, 王连平, 袁世海, 刘瑾, 马名群, 夏韵龙, 李嘉林, 李世庆, 叶福海, 赵荣欣, 曹操]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙盛武</mainName>
    <names>[叶映衬, 王德元, 谭富英, 李少春, 李少, 朱世慧, 夏美珍, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 李世芳, 尤擅, 张正治, 崔永, 高庆奎, 杨小楼, 孙盛文, 林十娘, 李诚, 孟母, 杜近芳, 蔡九, 孙毓堃, 吴素英, 李广伯, 贾桂, 杨宝森, 张别古, 蒋干, 李盛藻, 王龙, 孙盛武, 胡, 万氏, 黄德华, 袁世海, 蔡九哥, 李广]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙盛辅</mainName>
    <names>[谭富英, 王, 马最良, 孙所, 黄忠, 刘荣升, 刘奎官, 孙盛, 文天祥, 周昌, 鲁肃, 茹秀成, 诸葛亮, 赵盛璧, 孙盛辅, 马子豪, 徐策, 杨延昭, 宋士杰, 四郎, 刘玉佩, 龙化德, 蒋叔岩, 杨玉华, 刘备, 雷喜福, 赵荣琛, 康春京, 陈规, 范少康]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙翠凤</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙花满</mainName>
    <names>[杨门女, 朱德, 周恩来, 孙花满, 陈毅, 刘少奇, 岳母, 叶剑英, 金国贤, 毛泽东, 刘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙荣蕙</mainName>
    <names>[依伊, 王益禄, 尚门, 孙荣蕙, 袁德亮, 武净, 教亲自, 刘, 尚, 荀慧生, 孙荣, 叶盛兰, 孙景泉, 王少芳, 荣春, 赵永伟, 李万春, 荣蕙, 孙连春, 尚派霓, 赵和春, 王胜春, 常升社, 红珊, 小云, 王金璐, 马, 王伯党, 尚派, 唐王, 刘桂娟, 赵, 杨荣环, 王福春, 科班成, 赵砚奎, 尚派乾坤, 耿明义, 于丞相, 董圆圆, 尚小云, 孙玉奎, 周仲春, 孙宝信, 陶玉敏, 李凌枫, 于兰, 徐荣奎, 刘淑云, 王嘉春, 梅玉配, 孙瑞春, 陈兰霞, 孙明珠, 李多奎, 卢沟桥, 沈富贵, 富连成, 杨后改, 宋遇春, 黄荣俊, 孙志良, 李莉, 曹, 侯李佩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙菊仙</mainName>
    <names>[赵匡胤, 时慧宝, 汪立中, 张二奎, 孙派, 孙菊仙, 林墨青, 韩某, 汪桂, 刘, 蔡汇沧, 冯柱, 王九龄, 刘派, 金声, 谭, 骂杨, 杨隆寿, 孙饰, 李春来, 聂功庭, 姚增禄, 庚寅, 梅巧玲, 张胜奎, 庞太监, 马, 谭饰高, 爽朗, 山东登, 陈国瑞, 周春奎, 李砚, 徐, 李东园, 宫保, 孙菊, 辛亥革命, 南营, 桑园, 于庆, 洪阔有, 王八十, 怀德, 潘月, 刘为忠, 刘太监, 黄三雄, 高亮, 叶中定, 程章溥, 谭鑫, 王竹生, 徐宝成, 张两派, 李莲英, 周凤林, 余玉琴, 吴顺林, 张氏, 孙一啰, 西林, 杨贵云, 吴燕芳, 曹, 韩贵喜, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙路阳</mainName>
    <names>[景荣庆, 王永祥, 李逵, 钟馗, 陈有才, 刘巧儿, 马踏, 孙路阳, 赵宝成]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙钧卿</mainName>
    <names>[梅兰, 李玉茹, 郑传鉴, 刘, 赵培鑫, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 马立克, 赵鲁平, 杨林, 徐凌云, 马连良, 曾代, 王金璐, 汪, 吴, 孙钧卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孙鹏志</mainName>
    <names>[乔玄, 徐策, 孙鹏志]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孟丽君</mainName>
    <names>[唐韵笙, 周恩来, 华适麒, 孟喜平, 孟, 周, 雷喜福, 刘少春, 孟丽, 梁一鸣, 秦良玉, 孟丽君]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孟俊泉</mainName>
    <names>[王晓临, 李小培, 郝寿臣, 孟小冬, 孟俊泉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孟喜平</mainName>
    <names>[孟喜平, 孟丽君, 孟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孟小冬</mainName>
    <names>[李猷则, 王瑞芝, 李春恒, 法门寺, 崔富芝, 孟宅, 范秀, 黄金荣, 白玉昆, 周瑞安, 梅兰芳, 杜月, 露兰春, 孟鸿茂, 仇月, 孟幼冬, 谈天, 程门, 孟家, 王瑞, 姚玉兰, 吴彩霞, 陈彦衡, 孟母, 姨夫, 曲韵, 仇月祥, 王后饰, 孟鸿寿, 张别古, 董家巷, 四郎, 余叔岩, 孟, 张君秋, 董, 高华, 李金棠, 满春, 苏少卿, 骆宏勋, 赵, 许姬传, 张云鹤, 孟小冬, 李慧岩, 周正荣, 张少泉, 轩用功, 宋, 谭富英, 孟鸿群, 孟七, 陈秀华, 孟鸿芳, 孟向, 任莘寿, 孟小, 孟氏, 鲍吉祥, 谭派, 孟太, 法华寺, 孟学科, 桑园, 谭余迹, 诸葛亮, 王君直, 孟鸿荣, 孟鸿, 李多奎, 周恩来, 孙佐臣, 杨天, 杨宝森, 于京, 赵培鑫, 仲安, 张氏, 曾委派, 马连良, 叶复润, 孟小东, 常唱, 陈琳, 曹, 孟瑶, 杜母]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孟庆刚</mainName>
    <names>[李双双, 刘忠河, 穆桂英, 姚三元, 孟庆刚, 刁德一, 栾平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>孟筱伯</mainName>
    <names>[奚啸伯, 孟昭简, 奚, 孟筱伯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有孟鸿群的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>季砚农</mainName>
    <names>[王宝钏, 妙香, 梅派惟, 尚小云, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>安舒元</mainName>
    <names>[舒元, 李鸣岩, 马连良, 王文源, 王少楼, 金桐, 白家麟, 徐兰沅, 陈国卿, 田汉, 黄玉麟, 四郎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>安雯</mainName>
    <names>[安雯, 张静琳, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋丹菊</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 孙元, 陈永玲, 马祥麟, 班进京, 宋丹菊, 王派, 邓德芹, 于玉蘅, 穆天, 翁偶虹, 邱玲, 宋德珠, 崔莺莺, 王传蕖, 孙元彬, 穆柯寨, 邹慧兰, 宋扬, 李仙花, 魏效荀, 刘韵桐, 罗雁, 张君秋, 李慧芳, 王玉蓉, 崔荣英, 周铨庵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋凤云</mainName>
    <names>[姚祖舜, 宋永珍, 宋, 康闻之宋, 宋益, 李洪春, 宋凤云, 宋风云, 孔怀, 黄天霸, 宋紫珊, 宋门, 刘义, 梁花侬, 宋宝罗, 金翠风, 益俊, 易名, 姚, 宋遇春, 怀念恩, 宋演, 荣获之, 宋紫萍, 宋氏, 刘喜奎, 程永龙, 宋紫君, 孟丽君, 杨风云, 孟小冬, 彭秀]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋奎英</mainName>
    <names>[宋奎英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋小川</mainName>
    <names>[叶派, 李维康, 吕布, 李德斌, 梁山伯, 金桐, 杨春霞, 刘长瑜, 罗成, 宋小川, 叶少兰, 方荣翔, 张增色, 李金鸿, 杜近芳, 周仁, 王瑶卿, 张国荣, 四郎, 杜, 王晶华, 曹雪芹, 马长礼, 荣获金, 张火丁, 袁世海, 衡和华, 穆桂英, 李宗义, 张学津, 苏小妹, 万筱菊, 杨明华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋德珠</mainName>
    <names>[马旦戏, 杨柳, 法门寺, 宋派, 梅兰芳, 荀慧生, 张善亭, 李世芳, 秋授其, 朱玉康, 宋宝禄, 朱桂芳, 宋德珠, 荀慧, 阎岚秋, 郭际湘, 王瑶卿, 矫健, 辛安驿, 四郎, 余玉琴, 张君秋, 程砚, 诸茹香, 程砚秋, 贺后骂, 王丽君, 杨排风]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋昌林</mainName>
    <names>[荣翔, 王正屏, 宋昌, 李逵, 宋昌林, 方, 荣成]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋桐斌</mainName>
    <names>[宋桐斌, 陈庆禄, 宋继武, 正式拜, 丁正洪, 刘浩鹏, 梁山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋永珍</mainName>
    <names>[姚祖舜, 宋永珍, 宋, 沈玉斌, 宋益, 李洪春, 尚, 宋当, 毛毛旦, 宋紫珊, 李永利, 宋凤, 宋门, 刘义, 宋宝罗, 牛家之, 李吉瑞, 松柏庵, 田际云, 易名, 姚, 宋氏膝, 宋遇春, 怀念恩, 方愈, 马德成, 宋紫萍, 刘永奎, 大夫, 程永龙, 宋紫君, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋继亭</mainName>
    <names>[宋继亭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋转转</mainName>
    <names>[梅花奖, 杜十娘, 宋转转, 冈夫, 于山乡, 晋剧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋遇春</mainName>
    <names>[宋父, 宋为, 宋永珍, 赵匡胤, 孙荣蕙, 阎, 马少波, 宋遇, 陈子, 尚, 周信芳, 向帅, 华容, 尤, 李德, 黎元, 何佩华, 马英臣, 鲁肃, 吴, 隆和成, 宋师徒, 王鸣仲, 张氏所, 秦香莲, 孟凤仪, 荣蕙, 赵光义, 陈, 郑冰如, 赵公明, 张辽一角, 李盛斌, 张玉良, 张女, 沈宝祯, 马彦祥, 陈富瑞, 俞即将, 袁世海, 任正春, 王者乃, 马, 宋益俊, 袁金凯, 姜铁, 刘备非, 徐东明, 武生, 陈士美, 刘宗, 李万, 韩世忠, 宋急忙, 秦香, 孟丽君, 李老, 陆盛英, 阎世善, 艾世菊, 陈永玲, 孟玉亭, 魏莲芳, 文天, 戴耳环, 张辽, 马良臣, 马公, 宋凤云, 尚小云, 包裹, 张氏系, 杨掌柜, 刘砚亭, 于庆乐, 梁慧超, 伍氏, 南天, 李一车, 沈风喜, 王小四, 柏庵, 奚啸伯, 孙毓堃, 龙套, 张玉峰, 俞振飞, 鞠鑫, 杨派, 宋任, 宋遇春, 张氏, 韩秀, 黄派, 宋锋, 郑冰, 欧阳德, 梁红玉, 张嘉祥, 董小宛, 毕德林, 马公半夜, 张宝华, 法门寺, 李饰王朝, 康英, 黎明, 李宝櫆, 薛倚哥, 杨同去, 班进京, 梅兰芳, 毛毛旦, 赵起荣, 李砚秀, 王承恩, 马后, 梁秀娟, 宋国士, 孙饰, 李万春, 杨家, 胡同, 宋宝罗, 宋饰, 李, 惠良远, 董兆斌, 小宋, 孙荣蕙扮, 鞠鑫顿, 杨派武生, 杨, 关平, 刘瑾, 范文英, 赵, 陈国瑞, 宋喜, 张淑芝, 宋家, 谢小娥, 唐韵笙, 李洪爷, 刘承佑, 宋, 胡迪骂, 黄忠, 李洪, 林, 李洪春, 裴元庆, 焦维英, 贺玉, 王延龄, 张氏之头, 袁世, 宋忙, 荣春社, 吴彦衡, 高盛麟, 冯玉祥, 李元霸, 宋紫珊, 陶荣耀, 李甫春, 梅玉配, 孙瑞春, 骆马湖·问樵, 徐策, 金, 张立英, 程晓亭, 柳瑞莲, 毕, 莫成, 惟恐不清, 王乃死, 宋为继, 时荣章, 宋饰杜, 宋老, 俞, 徐荣, 韩翠珠, 饶京, 刘备, 毕生, 马连良, 崔灵, 金少春, 李饰, 张之器, 陈公公, 秋江, 黄知真]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>宋雨芳</mainName>
    <names>[江竹筠, 李娘娘, 花淑兰, 韩少云, 穆桂英, 宋丽, 宋雨芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>富少舫</mainName>
    <names>[赵景深, 富少, 富淑媛, 鲁智深, 班赴济南, 吕蒙正, 张生, 张云舫, 计新]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>富淑媛</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>封至模</mainName>
    <names>[封, 陈素真, 尚友社, ，, 刘仲秋, 于门, 仲勋, 易俗社, 霍乱, 梅兰芳, 荀慧生, 李逸生, 秦腔, 马公韬, 陈妙华, 封至模, 顾盼飞, 薄情郎, 宋上华, 常香玉, 习仲勋, 曲革新, 李, 杨令俗, 苏育民, 李应真, 南铁生, 耿善民, 马, 王天民, 李瑞芳, 何振, 陈幼韩, 李宝琴, 李正敏, 宋, 曹心泉, 张寒晖, 幽兰, 刘易平, 尚小云, 王寿山, 周伯勋, 伍富民, 孟遏云, 肖玉玲, 桑园, 刘毓, 肖若兰, 王秀兰, 刘尚达, 上林, 郭建英, 李健吾, 张咏华, 任成德, 王杰三, 姚, 秦人为, 孙玉姣, 马科, 宋朝, 张凤翙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小刘春山</mainName>
    <names>[程笑飞, 范哈哈, 张冶儿, 杨华生, 刘, 刘冶平, 俞祥明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小岚云</mainName>
    <names>[小岚, 石岚, 高腔烘托, 刘派, 刘宝, 徐母骂, 燕乐, 曹, 刘宝全]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小映霞</mainName>
    <names>[李离, 胡宝钧, 刘派, 程树棠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小杨月楼</mainName>
    <names>[杨宗保, 张国泰, 许少卿, 黄玉麟, 杨设, 周信芳, 赵君玉, 刘筱衡, 毛韵珂, 李桂芳, 杨天宝, 陈秀英, 李十]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小王彬彬</mainName>
    <names>[曹庄, 王建伟, 徐元宰, 李, 王彬彬, 陈琳, 施佾生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小王桂卿</mainName>
    <names>[柯湘, 周说, 徐策, 沈金波, 汪正华, 雷刚, 周信芳, 唐僧, 李桂春, 王强华, 王正屏, 周, 武生, 吴, 赵, 王桂卿, 李仲林, 李如春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小王玉蓉</mainName>
    <names>[王玉蓉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小白玉梅</mainName>
    <names>[金嗓子, 史济华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小白玉霜</mainName>
    <names>[秦香莲, ，, 易名, 罗汉, 李再雯, 李家, 马连良, 阎婆, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小盛春</mainName>
    <names>[董士春, 董巨川, 董玉山, 扶新]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>双杰</mainName>
    <names>[王小毛, 双杰, 宋国华, 翁双杰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>小香玉</mainName>
    <names>[金杯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚和玉</mainName>
    <names>[刘武华, 朱小义, 王, 刘仲秋, 张春华, 尚, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 李元春, 徐俊华, 娄廷玉, 李元霸, 翁偶虹, 俞之姐夫, 尚和, 杨小楼, 侯永奎, 陈德霖, 俞之内, 蔡宝华, 俞菊笙, 奚啸, 钱宝森, 章遏云, 马连良, 韩长宝, 尚和玉, 武生, 刘喜奎, 张虎山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚富霞</mainName>
    <names>[尚富霞, 李寿山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚小云</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 金桂, 鞠小苏, 尚慧敏, 王蕙芳, 孙荣蕙, 于旦角, ）, 三杰, 戴韵芳, 张派, 林, 尚小云, 孙菊, 尚, 师初, 鲍绮瑜, 王玲玉, 荣春社, 李寿山, 云京, 李际, 杨小楼, 尚小, 正乐, 赵晓岚, 陈德霖, 李春福, 孙明珠, 周百穗, 孙怡云, 李翔, 黄玉华, 周利, 王瑶卿, 杨派, 王尚可, 胡氏, 张君秋, 荣, 王昭君, 习武生, 段丽君, 马博敏, 董玉苓, 尚长麟, 李莉, 唐茂, 张芷荃, 李喜鸿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚慧敏</mainName>
    <names>[荀慧生, 尚慧, 尚慧敏, 孙荣蕙, 小赵, 董玉玲, 吴素秋, 李喜鸿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚明珠</mainName>
    <names>[方海珍, 马皇, 尚明珠, 庄秀丽, 班进京, 梅兰芳, 俞琳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚继春</mainName>
    <names>[荀, 常雨桥, 焦裕禄, 白玉兰, 尚继春, 朱元璋, 郭建光, 尚小云, 荀慧生, 杨四郎, 郭少衡, 杨波, 曹, 吕洞宾]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚荣芳</mainName>
    <names>[尚荣芳, 小云, 荣华富贵, 章驷群, 李慧娘, 荣春, 越剧团, 尚小云, 尚, 盖叫天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚长春</mainName>
    <names>[丁永利, 范宝亭, 尚慧敏, 尚长春, 宋富亭, 杨靖宇, 尚继春, 耿明义, 尚慧珠, 尚小云, 王连平, 尚东辉, 马童, 刘砚芳, 梁崭露, 尚和玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚长荣</mainName>
    <names>[杨宗保, 侯喜瑞, 尚富霞, 法门寺, 吴荣唐, 马可, 荣白天, 杨尚昆, 彭德怀, 刁光覃, 舒同, 师帮, 朱琳, 尚长荣, 荣念白, 姚雪垠, 杨四郎, 吴, 阎兴, 邓小平, 金少山, 郝寿臣, 四郎, 李克昌, 谢幕, 荣, 陈富瑞, 周, 满江红, 孙岳, 武生, 里琐碎, 朱砂痣, 袁, 张志勇, 成龙, 郭嘉早, 杨修, 刘宗敏, 耿明义, 吴素秋, 梁建, 陈富, 尚小云, 盛戎, 杨修站, 勾勒, 李勇奇, 王僚, 谢幕之曲, 荣春社, 李自成, 李逵, 尚长, 侯, 周大勇, 柳青, 张飞, 王蕊芳, 华罗庚, 荣谦逊, 苏连汉, 周恩来, 杨修月, 正式拜, 金, 长荣, 裘, 郝, 荣授课, 曹操因, 马连良, 荣都, 江畔的, 金三爷, 曹操, 曹, 成昆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尚长麟</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 梅兰, 侯瑞春, 魏慧丽, 四郎, 雷峰塔, 于迎春, 韩单, 鞠, 李凌枫, 程砚秋, 王昭君, 陶玉芝, 小云, 番, 尚长, 尚派, 马博敏, 方面拉, 朱胜富, 尚长麟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尹寿山</mainName>
    <names>[马三立, 连兴, 郭荣启, 闫笑儒, 郭荣起, 马四立, 耿宝林, 赵佩茹, 尹, 史文翰, 孙少林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尹小峰</mainName>
    <names>[尹小峰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尹桂芳</mainName>
    <names>[茅威涛, 云破月, 宋普南, 何文秀, 尹云峰, 石达, 王君安, 梁玉书, 尹派, 洪钧, 叶彩金, 尹, 桂芳, 赵志刚, 徐进, 尹桂芳, 傅全香, 袁雪芬, 邢竹琴, 弘英, 贾宝玉, 屈原, 王明珠, 尹瑞芳, 王孙公子, 张生, 竺水招, 尹派传]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>尹良俗</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 梅玉鉴, 尹良俗]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>屠世冲</mainName>
    <names>[杨香武, 王伯燕, 晋京, 张任, 刘少奇, 孙悟空, 屠世冲, 毛泽东, 陆文龙, 朱骥, 周瑜, 文龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>屠笑飞</mainName>
    <names>[赵文华, 俞会珍, 孔雀东南飞, 宋顺发, 林娘, 穆桂英, 姜诗, 黄善婆, 周惠吉, 屠笑, 王文娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>岳惠玲</mainName>
    <names>[李崇, 李翔拜, 尚小云, 岳惠玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>崇元碧</mainName>
    <names>[陈元碧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>崇天明</mainName>
    <names>[梁厚民, 李菁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>崔小田</mainName>
    <names>[崔派, 崔兰玉, 崔兰田, 崔少奎, 崔小田, 沈宝爱]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>崔德荣</mainName>
    <names>[崔德荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>崔澄田</mainName>
    <names>[狄青, 李子明, 高阳, 洪亮, 周恩来, 潘烘, 刘少奇, 崔, 高位而飞, 彭真, 潘洪, 崔澄田, 田未卸, 崔澄, 邓小平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>崔荣英</mainName>
    <names>[李克用, 谢晔华, 孙荣蕙, 于世文, 黄宇琳, 田荣芬, 孙毓敏, 金莲, 崔, 孙晓华, 尚荣芳, 俞勋, 荣春社, 富力强, 贾多才, 王张江, 高富远, 阎岚秋, 崔荣, 马清明, 郭荣珍, 杨踩, 于课徒, 徐荣, 黄字琳, 崔荣英, 马拜崔, 尚长麟, 余京]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>左大玢</mainName>
    <names>[郑福秋, 杨门女, 海燕, 田汉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>左文麟</mainName>
    <names>[郭仲春, 王, 黄忠, 赵燕, 卢芳, 陈鸿声, 双忠, 王展, 李自成, 王佐, 鲁肃, 左文麟, 孙钧卿, 乔玄, 蒯彻, 宋江, 焦裕禄, 孙均卿, 宋士杰, 寇准, 李玉和, 姚世茹, 左, 陆登, 王金璐, 雷喜福, 马, 骆宏勋, 陆门, 李鸣盛, 荀令莱]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>左清飞</mainName>
    <names>[李亚仙, 金琬, 左清飞, 秋江, 李存孝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>左胜利</mainName>
    <names>[左胜利, 吴来宝, 王少舫, 严凤英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>席宝昆</mainName>
    <names>[陈出新, 秦香莲, 魏王, 何从, 席宝昆, 陈世, 罗汉, 陈瘸子, 文成, 梅玉, 孙庞, 叶巴, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常宝丰</mainName>
    <names>[朱庆余, 周恩来, 刘少奇, 张寿臣, 张庆森, 赵佩茹, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常宝堃</mainName>
    <names>[朱德, 周恩来, 常宝, 常宝堃, 张寿臣, 赵佩茹, 毛泽东, 常氏, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常宝霆</mainName>
    <names>[吉评三, 柳活, 于俊波, 诸葛亮, 郭荣启, 常宝霆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常宝霖</mainName>
    <names>[刘文丰, 张洪, 常宝霖, 常宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常春生</mainName>
    <names>[巴渝, 方荣翔, 常春生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常澍田</mainName>
    <names>[丁, 张剑平, 刘宝, 常澍田, 王剑云, 王凤久, 法雄健, 刘修改, 全月, 罗江怨, 刘便, 刘宝全, 尤深, 刘教, 向德, 田关, 金万昌, 卓二娘, 何剑峰, 何质臣, 石韵, 利刃]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常警惕</mainName>
    <names>[樊粹庭, 刘胡兰, 吕布, 陈素贞, 王淑惠, 赵峰, 杨藩, 樊祯华, 邢枫, 李元春, 梁善德, 王佐, 吴, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常贵祥</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常香玉</mainName>
    <names>[张妙玲, 常香玉, 张福仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>常香玲</mainName>
    <names>[常香玲, 宋桂玲, 葛燕亭, 崔兰田, 张凤仙, 刘凤云, 常香玉, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>庆春圃</mainName>
    <names>[武净, 黄润甫, 尤擅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>庞焕励</mainName>
    <names>[庞焕励]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>康万生</mainName>
    <names>[荣翔, 康万生, 李长春, 张福昆, 刘少峰, 王正屏, 夏韵, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>康子林</mainName>
    <names>[胡, 彭元子, 杨素兰, 毕肖, 康子林, 陆逊, 何心田, 蒙正]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>康晓虎</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>康松广</mainName>
    <names>[王世臣, 红娃娃, 王决, 王辅庭, 王长友, 燕京, 罗荣寿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>康静</mainName>
    <names>[李奶奶, 安平, 王梦云, 赵葆秀, 李多奎, 康静, 高淑娟, 洪母骂, 梅兰芳, 毛, 王晶华, 周信芳, 李鸣岩, 孙振泉, 王玉敏, 李金泉, 王树芳, 王珮瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张世兰</mainName>
    <names>[魏莲芳, 王梦云, 张世孝, 杜近芳, 李玉茹, 张世兰, 易名, 梅兰芳, 苏雨卿, 周信芳, 姜妙香, 李世芳, 刘元彤, 李丽芳, 李慧芳, 苏盛琴, 张子, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张世年</mainName>
    <names>[陈永玲, 侯喜瑞, 刘伯扬, 谭富英, 李盛斌, 李少春, 张世年, 叶盛章, 朱光祖, 王连平, 茹富兰, 张德华, 张智兰, 张连保, 习武生, 张佩文, 毛世来, 勾顺亮, 刘喜益]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张世桐</mainName>
    <names>[阎世善, 王连平, 张世桐, 张春华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张丽华</mainName>
    <names>[张羽煮, 王少, 胡秀芝, 张蕊华, 张丽华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张义奎</mainName>
    <names>[张义奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张二鹏</mainName>
    <names>[于武, 武生, 张翼鹏, 张二鹏, 孙悟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张云溪</mainName>
    <names>[岳胜, 陈怀恺, 李兰亭, 唐韵笙, 凤凰, 徐元珊, 徐佩玲, 十一郎, 张春, 张予慧, 姚喜成, 陈秀华, 张春华, 尚小云, 周信芳, 赵如泉, 巴丘, 岳云, 张启善, 张云溪率, 迟景昆, 郑美琪, 谢锐青, 四郎, 张启正, 饰十一郎, 张启忠, 张德俊, 袁世海, 李富荣, 迟月亭, 张世桐, 梁九荣, 刘宗杨, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张伯驹</mainName>
    <names>[范秀轩, 梅兰芳, 冯耿光, 张, 张伯驹, 袁世, 李石曾, 桑园, 张倾尽, 吴, 余韵, 尚未计, 张古愚, 杨小楼, 孙回信, 王则昭, 张称袁, 衡骥尾, 袁寒云, 李克非, 程继先, 田桂凤, 四郎, 李峤, 钱宝森, 王凤卿, 张正式, 叔岩, 周郎, 张振芳, 陈鹤孙, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张俊功</mainName>
    <names>[张金福, 巩俐, 王瞎子, 张俊功, 吴蛮子, 唐传, 张俊, 李有明, 李海清, 王二, 武二郎, 韩起祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张信安</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 张信安, 小手拉, 刘志鹏, 咸阳, 刘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张健声</mainName>
    <names>[聂小倩, 陈士, 张健声, 张耀明, 张笑声, 陈少舫, 伍秋月]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张健民</mainName>
    <names>[张, 秦腔, 张健民, 尚友社, 康正绪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张元礼</mainName>
    <names>[张元礼, 张维谦, 张元智]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张兰</mainName>
    <names>[李鸣岩, 胡根萍, 杨门女, 李丽萍, 徐母, 张兰, 王晶华, 杜十娘, 吴妈]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张凯</mainName>
    <names>[张凯, 李崇善, 李文才, 李舒, 陈增堃, 李光, 四郎, 王世续, 杨派, 李甫春, 叶蓬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张剑鸣</mainName>
    <names>[张剑鸣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张双勤</mainName>
    <names>[滑稽, 张双勤, 周柏春, 王小毛, 姚慕双, 金都]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张君秋</mainName>
    <names>[张学海, 李维康, 秦香莲, 吴吟秋, 季小兰, 王婉华, 杨淑蕊, 张学浩, 张派, 毛世, 梅兰芳, 尚, 张君秋, 荀之腔, 李凌枫, 李世芳, 王蓉蓉, 张学津, 薛亚萍, 赵秀君, 宋德珠, 刘秀荣, 崔莺莺, 张学敏, 杨秋玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张君谋</mainName>
    <names>[徐雪玉, 王柏荫, 张君谋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张善亭</mainName>
    <names>[白玉薇, 张善亭, 宋德珠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张善元</mainName>
    <names>[张善元]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张娴</mainName>
    <names>[张柏生, 梁谷音, 周传瑛, 张静娴, 洪雪飞, 陈正微, 梅派, 张凤霞, 崔莺莺, 红娘, 李倩影, 周世璋, 杨小培, 张娴, 杨菊萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张子平</mainName>
    <names>[张伯孚, ，, 卓著, 吴文彬, 张子平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张学津</mainName>
    <names>[谭嗣, 陈喜光, 马, 张学津, 舒展]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张学浩</mainName>
    <names>[张学浩, 张派, 毛, 梅葆玖, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张学海</mainName>
    <names>[张学海, 李世济, 周信芳, 张君秋, 张学津]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张宏逵</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 李维康, 侯喜瑞, 李春恒, 邓敏, 宋富亭, 金, 荣庆, 刘长瑜, 张建国, 张宏逵, 武净, 刘琪, 梅兰芳, 俞, 袁慧琴, 杨门女, 袁世海, 骆连翔, 满江红, 孙岳, 赵, 杨秋玲, 赵永伟, 耿其昌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张宝昆</mainName>
    <names>[陈桐云, 刘鸿声, 徐宝芳, 张宝堃, 徐承瀚, 张宝昆, 张梅五, 王凤卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张宝申</mainName>
    <names>[刘绍棠, 高, 李金铭, 陈奔, 刘成林, 张宝申, 李惟铨, 张彦生, 文华, 文月, 王景明, 贾, 刘萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张宝荣</mainName>
    <names>[张, 何顺信, 袁庆芬, 唐, 张派, 张宝荣, 李慕良, 汪本贞, 张似云, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张少楼</mainName>
    <names>[任老生, 张月楼, 王瑞芝, 陈秀华, 章晓申, 张少楼, 李永德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张岚溪</mainName>
    <names>[张慰臣, 李正奇, 吴志子, 谢正华, 明正顺, 明清]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张巨萍</mainName>
    <names>[李丹林, 曾宝玉, 王晶, 施东岭, 李世济, 唐, 刘杰, 高远, 四郎, 张玉英, 张, 黄彦忠, 李文敏, 梅庆阳, 王吟秋, 李海清, 张巨萍, 马玉红, 刘山丽]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张常锁</mainName>
    <names>[张, 于1986, 张常锁, 张玉堂, 笑昆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张延培</mainName>
    <names>[胡, 李维康, 袁世海, 张学津, 于皮簧, 张延培, 刘长瑜, 毛泽东, 张似云, 张延, 于魁智, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张建国</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 法门寺, 金, 梅花奖, 张建国, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 张荣培, 中石, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张强</mainName>
    <names>[张, 张强, 四郎, 何德亮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张德俊</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 赵云单, 金仲仁, 梁连柱, 田汉, 巴骆, 梅兰芳, 李春, 周信芳, 赵雅枫, 荀慧生, 姜妙香, 曹将, 李永利, 谭小培, 云里翻, 花冲破, 郝寿臣, 李吉瑞, 宋富亭, 华慧, 王瑶卿, 武松, 王凤卿, 张德武, 李桂春, 张德俊, 范富喜, 马连良, 马德成, 尚和玉, 武生, 张桂轩, 李连甲, 四杰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张德发</mainName>
    <names>[张德发]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张德武</mainName>
    <names>[张文顺, 张承武, 张德武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张德福</mainName>
    <names>[杨三姐, 阮文追, 唐伯虎, 范登, 王, 张德福少, 金明, 李梦龙, 敖, 郑永刚, 千斤道白, 杨乃武, 吴国光, 苏秦, 张德福, 王善福, 孙宝亭, 刘巧儿, 宣登, 王金龙, 贾俊英, 赵柱儿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张志举</mainName>
    <names>[陈艳卿, 张志举, 曾荣华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张志奎</mainName>
    <names>[张志奎, 周恩来, 刘少奇, 贾春, 张春华, 毛泽东, 班进京]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张志奎</mainName>
    <names>[李玉和, 张志奎, 黄伯贤]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张志宽</mainName>
    <names>[张, 郭荣, 李润杰, 洪亮, 李派快, 全福, 曲协, 张志宽, 孙悟空, 毛泽东, 张志]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张惠云</mainName>
    <names>[陈, 金喉, 卓琳, 梅花奖, 陈三, 张惠云, 荀慧生, 王少, 周, 刘香玉, 范钧宏, 张凤仙, 李超, 秦香, 邓小平, 陈三两]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张惠新</mainName>
    <names>[张惠新, 王希一, 金秋, 张惠, 曲友, 史密森, 徐炎, 冯许闻, 徐炎之]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张文斌</mainName>
    <names>[张文斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张文涓</mainName>
    <names>[杨宝忠, 侯喜瑞, 张伯驹, 刘曾复, 王瑞芝, 谭富英, 陈秀华, 四郎, 曹, 张文涓, 张荣奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张文顺</mainName>
    <names>[张文顺, 佟大方]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张新芳</mainName>
    <names>[张, 陈, 张新芳, 田汉, 梅兰芳, 毛, 张新, 秦香, 陈三两]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张昆吾</mainName>
    <names>[张昆吾, 李润杰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张春华</mainName>
    <names>[鲍骆, 罗宾汉, 丁秉春, 张春, 叶盛章, 叶师除, 张春华, 郑盛厚, 张, 念白, 王斌珍, 张世明, 江汉, 后福, 武功夫, 叶氏, 郭少, 双星, 双脚夹, 郑子明, 蒋平捞, 张则迷, 娄廷]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张春奎</mainName>
    <names>[张, 马寿, 张广泰, 张春奎, 刘德智, 孙少林, 张振奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张春孝</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 谢锐青, 茹富兰, 李玉泰, 张春孝, 张世孝, 金仲仁, 钱浩梁, 罗成, 刘秀荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张春彦</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 仲仁, 张金梁, 班解散, 程, 谭鑫, 赵桐珊, 张辽, 陈少霖, 王瑶卿, 梅兰芳, 吴富琴, 张君秋, 荀慧生, 程砚, 班之初, 张少彦, 于头二牌, 习老生, 刘子明, 秋挑, 徐春明, 马富禄, 王少楼, 叶衬托, 张春彦, 贾少棠, 徐师, 范钧宏, 习丑, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张春秋</mainName>
    <names>[周恩来, 梅派, 张春秋, 梅兰芳, 朱德, 红云岗, 刘知侠, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张春雷</mainName>
    <names>[王福润, 徐龙, 陆定, 张飞闯, 谭富英, 张兴然, 孟超, 周扬, 马少波, 秦琼, 梅兰芳, 张, 荀慧生, 杨朝先, 鲁西南, 朱德, 石敬思, 杨五郎, 柳子, 邓拓, 张飞, 诸葛亮, 孙安动, 邓小平, 柳腔, 周恩来, 陈谦, 晋京, 李, 刘少奇, 毛, 孙安, 罗汉, 彭真, 张春雷, 马连良, 满京华, 郭沫若, 陈毅, 张飞拿, 徐特立, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张显锋</mainName>
    <names>[张显锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张曼玲</mainName>
    <names>[李妈一角, 陈, 李世济, 张曼君, 王瑶卿, 张金玲, 顾森柏, 洪母骂, 牛郎, 张, 王世荣, 张曼玲, 孔雀东南, 程腔, 孔雀东南飞, 王吟秋, 赵荣琛, 陈文珍, 孙岳, 贺后骂, 姚志, 王凤朝, 王吟, 程玉菁, 费玉明, 华月琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张月荣</mainName>
    <names>[秦香莲, 刘胡兰, 张月荣, 周恩来, 杨得志, 杨成武, 秦香, 常香玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张杰尧</mainName>
    <names>[辛松斌, 刘月樵, 王本林, 刘阔义, 张士奎, 王子亮, 张寿臣, 袁松麒, 田月樵, 秦琼, 高德光, 松鹏, 张葆华, 赵闻增, 汤金澄, 张, 绪德贵, 张飞打, 张杰尧, 张稽祖, 陶湘, 胡兰亭, 朱阔泉, 郭绍东, 常, 陶湘九, 刘宝全, 王文瑞, 侯宝林, 刘宝瑞, 张松青, 张逗哏, 戴少, 五杰, 韩子康, 曾赞扬, 高德明, 张武林, 关公战, 王晓松, 严嵩, 骆彩祥, 罗成戏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张杰鑫</mainName>
    <names>[金受申, 贾明, 马轸元, 金家窑, 杜轸明, 张杰鑫, 孔轸清, 王致玖, 蒋轸龚, 徐长胜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张桂凤</mainName>
    <names>[李娃传, 董柯娣, 傅全香, 张承, 吴妈, 张, 王金萍, 章海灵, 秋风, 尺调腔·二凡, 越艺社, 张桂凤, 周勤, 费禄姣, 何日, 吴群, 范瑞娟, 刘彦昌, 张国华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张梅贞</mainName>
    <names>[阎立品, 张梅贞, 盘夫索夫, 王福生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张樵侬</mainName>
    <names>[徐笑林, 滑稽, 张樵侬, 沈及, 潘, 俞祥明, 张, 程笑飞, 万生昌, 杨, 杨华生, 沈一乐, 杜宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张正芬</mainName>
    <names>[周正荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张永熙</mainName>
    <names>[刘宝瑞, 红楼书场, ，, 周恩来, 高元钧, 张永, 张寿臣, 刘, 董必武, 张, 胡, 赵世忠, 明结成, 赵少舫, 张永熙, 诸葛亮, 陶湘九, 小张, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张永禄</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 赵燕侠, 杨宝森, 赵春锦, 刘喜益, 马富禄, 张永禄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张永远</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 陈永玲, 赵桐珊, 宋金刚, 张兵, 莫稽, 王连平, 张琎, 王科科, 张永远, 王金龙, 安东, 萧连芳, 刘彦昌, 陈盛泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张活游</mainName>
    <names>[吴楚帆, 张宝坚, 张活游, 张瑛, 张活, 张干裕, 白燕, 张玉珍, 阎罗, 李清]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张浩</mainName>
    <names>[霍士云, 张浩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张淇林</mainName>
    <names>[俞菊笙, 张淇林, 陈德霖, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张玉林</mainName>
    <names>[张, 张德俊, 张玉林, 张德武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张畹秋</mainName>
    <names>[贾骏, 赵女, 陈鹤峰, 张慧敏, 梅兰芳, 张晚秋, 张畹秋, 赵子厚, 杜鹃, 贝勒宫扇, 赵松]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张盛亭</mainName>
    <names>[张四, 张盛亭, 子张]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张秀党</mainName>
    <names>[张秀党, 金, 东方红, 王矿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张秋伟</mainName>
    <names>[张秋伟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张笠媛</mainName>
    <names>[蔡英莲, 陈秀文, 王小蓉, 四郎, 沈世华, 刘罗锅, 孔雀东南飞, 关静兰, 张笠媛, 张蓉华, 陈琪, 崔氏, 薛亚萍, 马前, 张学敏, 李宝春, 宇宙锋, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张素英</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 杨宝忠, 张素英, 王瑞芝, 陈立夫, 张素, 梅葆玖, 吴华, 刘长瑜, 张学良, 张少楼, 于魁智, 辜振甫, 胡, 胡琴, 吴华合著, 胡专业, 吴炳璋, 于善民, 胡演奏, 卓著, 叶少兰, 耿其昌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张红霞</mainName>
    <names>[刘兰芳, 张红霞, ，, 刘兰凤, 胡集, 鲁豫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张继青</mainName>
    <names>[苏昆, 朱廉秀, 尤彩云, 姚传芗, 田氏, 杜丽娘, 张继青, 邬飞霞, 朱买臣, 苏州民锋, 崔氏, 窦娥, 俞锡侯, 朱卖臣, 庞氏, 杨玉环]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张胜奎</mainName>
    <names>[张胜奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张艺峰</mainName>
    <names>[胡涂, 张艺峰, 张玉妹, 温而不抑, 郭岚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张艾丁</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 赵燕侠, 汪曾祺, 谭富英, 艾丁, 张艾丁, 张君秋, 张梦庚, 马连良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张芷荃</mainName>
    <names>[张云亭, 张文斌, 张芷荃, 朱双喜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张荣培</mainName>
    <names>[张荣培, 刘备, 李克用, 杨继业, 奚啸伯, 张建国, 诸葛亮, 蔡荣贵, 王少芬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张荣奎</mainName>
    <names>[李德成, 王, 李少春, 孙佐臣, 张荣奎, 贾丽川, 刘曾复, 刘春喜, 叶庸方, 高庆奎, 刘砚芳, 李鑫甫, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培, 曾辅佐, 张文涓]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张菁华</mainName>
    <names>[张艳芳, 张菁华, 吕慧君]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张蝶芬</mainName>
    <names>[梁小鸾, 张门, 于宝, 张慧珠, 奚啸伯, 李玉茹, 张长海, 金, 朱孔扬之孙, 杨宝森, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 薛, 刘连荣, 张云仙, 谢虹雯, 李德彬, 朱, 徐东明, 梅逝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张达发</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 赵文奎, 张达发, 陈富瑞, 马宝刚, 王正屏, 李慧芳, 李玉茹, 李, 赵德钰, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张连升</mainName>
    <names>[张连升]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张连宝</mainName>
    <names>[张连宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张连庭</mainName>
    <names>[张, 丁俊, 范富喜, 茹富兰, 叶福海学, 高盛麟, 骆连翔, 何连涛, 武汉京, 贾顺成, 张飞, 董凤启, 赵连升, 苏富恩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张连福</mainName>
    <names>[王月, 张连福]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张通金</mainName>
    <names>[张通金, 平梁乡]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张醉地</mainName>
    <names>[滑稽, 骆驼, 苏武, 尤擅, 王, 籍贯, 张醉地, 王一飞, 唐笑飞, 海燕, 杨笑峰, 龚张, 张呆儿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张采林</mainName>
    <names>[张采林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张金梁</mainName>
    <names>[李军, 郭和涌, 苏三, 李玉茹, ，, 法门寺, 张脸, 焦菊隐, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 梁山, 荀慧生, 张, 顾问, 梁侥幸, 王蓉蓉, 苏丑, 唐槐秋, 唐若青, 杜, 张君秋, 王龙, 孔雀东南, 周, 王金璐, 胡画, 李金泉, 金刚, 四人帮, 张金梁, 谭富英, 张冠, 金鹏, 吴素秋, 梁亲眼, 尚小云, 李世芳, 平津京, 冯玉祥, 李戴, 翁偶虹, 梁乘船, 宋德珠, 梅香, 张金, 侯宝林, 侯宝, 史若虚, 卢沟桥, 杨宝森, 王昭君, 马连良, 马富禄, 张老, 勾脸, 尚长麟, 李玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张金波</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 李万春, 侯喜瑞, 奚啸伯, 周恩来, 李金声, 张金波, 罗慧兰, 郭少衡, 宋德珠, 张金]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张鑫海</mainName>
    <names>[徐鸿培, 张鑫海, 周信芳, 王燮元]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张铁华</mainName>
    <names>[张世麟, 甘宁, 唐韵, 薛刚, 杨赤, 张铁华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张静</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 李鸣岩, 孔燕, 穆桂英, 王玉敏, 岳母, 刘长瑜, 张静, 刘秀荣, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>张鸣禄</mainName>
    <names>[武净, 张鸣禄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>彭俐侬</mainName>
    <names>[江汉, 吴绍芝, 彭菊生, 赵, 陈爱珠, 彭俐侬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>彭子富</mainName>
    <names>[王天豹, 彭振林, 尹士兴, 彭子, 魏喜奎, 陈世夺, 梅翠娥, 白卷, 张桂蓉, 赵学艺, 刘吉典, 彭老生, 杜三宝, 柳春江, 韩燕, 董永, 骆驼, 钱宝生, 彭士增, 曲剧, 王江, 崔大庆, 尹福来, 赵志刚, 富, 周恩来, 曹宝禄, 王三, 双簧, 刘少奇, 太平年, 彭子富, 周强, 罗汉, 杨乃武, 赵小兰, 顾荣甫, 毛泽东, 王老虎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>彭林刚</mainName>
    <names>[陈, 张慧珠, 彭林刚饰, 李蔷华, 李砚萍, 王春娥, 程派, 彭林刚, 荣, 张氏, 陈吟秋, 薛保, 钟荣, 徐秀芳, 王恢, 薛湘灵, 习得]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>彭炽权</mainName>
    <names>[罗品, 凤仪, 罗品超, 彭炽权, 陈姑追, 文觉非]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>律承荣</mainName>
    <names>[朱少亭, 李志鹏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐世光</mainName>
    <names>[袁汉云, 许翰英, 唐韵笙, 徐世光, 袁灵云, 袁美云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐丽仙</mainName>
    <names>[徐丽仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐元珊</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 梅, 徐元珊, 梅兰, 姨夫, 徐佩玲, 谭富英, 十一郎, 梅葆玖, 沈宝桢, 徐, 沈富贵, 徐兰沅, 梅派, 武松, 宋继亭, 杨宝森, 杨派, 王连平, 茹富兰, 习武生, 李玉芙, 徐家, 宋喜珠, 元珊, 穆桂英, 毛世来, 徐嘉瑞, 李玉, 陆文龙, 李宝春, 史文恭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐卓呆</mainName>
    <names>[卓别麟, 徐曾, 黄鱼调, 徐卓呆, 徐所编, 曾留学, 李阿毛, 徐博霖, 万宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐双飞</mainName>
    <names>[徐双飞, 蒋福根, 张超, 周庆阳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐和才</mainName>
    <names>[徐和才, 李慧芳, 江新]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐天红</mainName>
    <names>[张仪, 刘彦, 红星越, 赵景深, 徐策, 尹桂芳, 袁雪芬, 贾政, 徐天红, 屈原, 祝, 徐玉兰, 红楼梦, 余姚, 赵瑞花, 石榴红, 梁祝, 华越, 赵礼, 尹, 纪晓岚, 桂芳, 张广才]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐孟珂</mainName>
    <names>[郑维金, 马增寿, 孟珂, 法门寺, 徐, 张春华, 钮骠, 徐孟珂, 张文远, 郑岩, 孙正阳, 方小亚, 刘异龙, 武大郎, 夏慧, 寇春华, 李爱莲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐宝芳</mainName>
    <names>[徐宝芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐德亮</mainName>
    <names>[白奉霖, 张文顺, 赵俊, 徐德亮, 徐亮, 安得]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐思佳</mainName>
    <names>[李亚仙, 吴江, 龚隐雷, 朱买臣, 崔氏, 徐思佳, 白素贞, 胡锦芳, 李贞丽, 李桂枝, 杜丽娘, 赵京娘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐惠新</mainName>
    <names>[徐惠新, 蒋月泉, 周云, 刘丽华, 王如荪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐敏初</mainName>
    <names>[江汉, 周恩来, 徐敏初, 李少春, 李, 明毓琨, 文帅, 田汉, 四郎, 祁来发, 刘奎官, 周信芳, 穆承斌, 郭小福, 李玉龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐玉兰</mainName>
    <names>[俞传海, 李梦龙, 汪秀月, 马潮水, 徐小兰, 红楼梦, 花碧莲, 张珍, 赵云, 吴月奎, 张珙, 王杏花, 刘觉, 金美芳, 徐持平, 贾宝玉, 庄志, 钱丽亚, 徐玉兰, 赵瑞花, 吴琛, 翁荔英, 刘丽华, 钱惠丽, 袁世昌, 王文娟, 刘谌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐碧云</mainName>
    <names>[双庆社, 孟月, 习花旦, 俞振庭, 洪深, 法门寺, 李玉茹, 徐, 萧长华, 薛琼英, 梅雨田, 徐不但, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 徐为答, 徐碧, 荀慧生, 王玲玉, 杨畹侬, 曾习, 徐碧云, 徐宝芳, 毛世来, 杨隆寿, 高庆, 吴彩霞, 华香琳, 谢锐青, 花木兰, 刘雪涛, 徐门, 徐兰沅, 卢小翠, 徐之舅, 谢南通, 王宝钏, 徐鸿轩, 李薇华, 云深受, 马连良, 毕谷云, 李丽芳, 李慧芳, 徐饰, 黄桂秋, 徐斌寿, 徐氏, 徐与]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐立平</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 徐立, ，, 徐立平, 曲教文]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐艳琴</mainName>
    <names>[徐艳琴, 马金凤, 帅旦, 徐文德, 韩世, 张, 洪月娥, 阎立品, 穆桂英, 蒋文质, 文武, 陈圆圆, 常香玉, 王润枝, 班永安, 柳长青, 王福臣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐荣奎</mainName>
    <names>[唐韵笙, 杨立贝, 徐策, 于杭, 蔡荣贵, 周信芳, 江, 徐荣奎, 南唱, 周信, 徐志良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐镜清</mainName>
    <names>[徐镜清, 徐镜, 陈季常, 郁成疾, 张紫东, 雷峰, 武旦, 伏案, 俞粟庐, 俞振飞, 俞饰, 吴中曲, 张饰, 缮写昆, 徐饰, 苏州钧, 柳氏, 苏州道, 吴梅所作, 白素贞, 苏病逝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>徐露</mainName>
    <names>[张派戏, 徐露, 梁红玉, 朱琴心, 李毅清]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>德子杰</mainName>
    <names>[朱光祖, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>德珺如</mainName>
    <names>[吕布, 仲仁, 徐小香, 谭之子, 孟小茹, 罗成, 郭振川, 李辅臣, 黄唱腔, 孙菊, 谭小培, 袁子明, 谭鑫培, 庚子]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>恩子</mainName>
    <names>[李德钖, 马德禄, 陈子贞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>恩禹之</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>惠兆龙</mainName>
    <names>[卢俊义, 惠兆龙, 陈毅, 曲协]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>慈少泉</mainName>
    <names>[谭富英, 法门寺, 吴素秋, 毛世, 宋德珠, 尚小云, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>慈瑞泉</mainName>
    <names>[王, 谭鑫, 童心未泯, 萧长华, 张别古, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 樵夫, 李四广, 程砚, 巢, 张义, 程砚秋, 玉成, 谭富, 厉内荏, 乌盆, 杨小楼, 高庆, 朱痕记]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>戴雪如</mainName>
    <names>[戴雪如]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>戴韵芳</mainName>
    <names>[正乐, 戴韵芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>扎兰卿</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>敖学祺</mainName>
    <names>[南虹, 黄钟, 李兆鸿, 陈三五, 成, 黄河颂, 渝, 聂耳, 西苑, 敖学祺, 陈道谟, 李贵阳, 饶秉钧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>文亮臣</mainName>
    <names>[程砚, 赵氏一角, 秋一手, 四郎, 程倚之为]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>文荣寿</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>新凤霞</mainName>
    <names>[陈出新, 王仙舫, 张五可, 戴月琴, 张, 杨三娥, 吴祖光, 燕燕, 李满天下, 都文, 王曼玲, 杨三姐, 戴乃迭, 杨金香, 刘金定, 阮氏娟, 杨乃武, 李秀英, 刘巧儿, 邓砚臣, 赵淑华, 赵, 刘秀荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>新岚云</mainName>
    <names>[钟舜华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>新艳琴</mainName>
    <names>[魏茂, 李奶奶, 杨三姐, 刘宝忠, 梁山伯, 新艳, 新艳琴, 琴立志, 杨八姐, 刘派, 姚母, 打狗劝夫, 李派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>新韵霞</mainName>
    <names>[唐, 王淑玲, 徐秀英, 穆同颇, 刘伶, 王建梅, 王佩臣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>新马师曾</mainName>
    <names>[林树森, 邓永祥, 马师曾, 万恶淫, 薛觉先]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方传芸</mainName>
    <names>[赵景深, 段秋霞, 唐, 燕青, 史洁华, 班授课, 杨八姐, 徐凌云, 周瑞龙, 孙二娘, 丘半塘, 汪饰, 汪传钤, 苏, 俞振飞, 王芝泉, 焦光普, 李存孝, 文成, 任堂惠, 张静娴, 杭, 班及, 西游记·胖姑, 冯雄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方小亚</mainName>
    <names>[魏莲芳, 西德, ，, 梅兰芳, 小亚, 杨畹侬, 文华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方旭</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方月仿</mainName>
    <names>[方月, 邓敏, 花木兰, 邱玲, 方月仿, 曾根崎, 胡和颜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方秉忠</mainName>
    <names>[郝六, 梁同以, 李佩卿, 方宝泉, 陈嘉, 徐兰沅, 方秉忠, 刘兆奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方艳华</mainName>
    <names>[姚慕双, 辕门斩夫, 周柏春, 方艳华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方英培</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 尚小云, 胡菊琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方荣翔</mainName>
    <names>[荣翔, 王海, 方荣翔, 荣春社, 方荣, 周, 张鑫奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方连元</mainName>
    <names>[谢锐青, 王, 徐若英, 梁连柱, 宋富亭, 华慧, 刘琪, 尚小云, 巴骆, 李桂春, 张德俊, 范富喜, 许湘生, 郭锦华, 马连良, 骆连翔, 高庆奎, 朱桂芳, 梁九荣, 张桂芬, 刘秀荣, 杨小楼, 徐天元, 苏稚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>方震涛</mainName>
    <names>[方震涛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>施星夔</mainName>
    <names>[马兴田, 丁正, 施星夔俗, 李华臣, 唐, 洪准, 张作霖, 施星夔, 张华宾]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>施桂林</mainName>
    <names>[苏州百灵, 王熙春, 尤彩云, 苏, 金素雯, 于素莲, 施桂林, 张传芳, 沈盘, 吴义生, 全福, 秦剑钰, 王兰芳, 班报散, 陈剑琴, 赵翠儿, 王传蕖, 陈剑微, 尤多]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>施银花</mainName>
    <names>[赵瑞花, 王杏, 施腔]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>施雪怀</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>时世宝</mainName>
    <names>[李多奎, 谭元寿, 杨门女, 袁世海, 梁慕玲, 马富禄, 陈小茶, 岳母]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>时佩璞</mainName>
    <names>[米特朗, 和Boursicot被, 乌兰巴托]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>时慧宝</mainName>
    <names>[朱砂痣, 汪笑侬, 时慧宝, 谭鑫, 朱琴心, 姚增禄, 刘桂庆, 史料载, 陈福盛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>时炳奎</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>时白林</mainName>
    <names>[梁山伯, 安徽春, 牛郎, 严凤英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>时青山</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 王铁瑛, 曾授, 张贯珠, 吴国太, 王梦云, 郝寿臣, 谭富英, 金伯吟, 徐母骂, 陈少霖, 王鸣咏, 梅兰芳, 王晶华, 钮骠, 荀慧生, 叶盛兰, 孔雀东南飞, 李紫贵, 雷喜福, 王玉敏, 高庆奎, 李金泉, 徐和, 曹, 师从罗, 曾搭荀, 刘母]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>明毓琨</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 赵晓岚, 焦裕禄, 李少春, 徐敏初, 李, 田汉, 王魁, 周信芳, 红星京, 后台, 明海亮, 孙庞斗, 刘庆祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>易方朔</mainName>
    <names>[赵如泉, 马永贞, 郑元, 方言唱, 易方朔, 张冶儿, 张利声, 朱凤高, 郑正秋, 魏朔英, 王凤生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>春觉生</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>晓艇</mainName>
    <names>[杨广逼, 张无意]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>景孤血</mainName>
    <names>[程咬金, 樊樊山, 唐伯弢]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>景荣庆</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 丁永利, 范宝亭, 谭富英, 奚啸伯, 杜近芳, 李少春, 宋富亭, 景荣, 梅兰芳, 钱宝森, 叶盛兰, 陈富瑞, 荣春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曲咏春</mainName>
    <names>[李鸣岩, 曲咏春, 茹富兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曲素英</mainName>
    <names>[曲素英, 张春华, 穆柯寨, 秦香, 李]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹世嘉</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 黄玉华, 张凤祥, 李, 张长海, 王喜秀, 陈少五, 杨宝森, 陈少云, 南铁生, 曹瑞石, 高连奎, 曹世嘉, 荀慧生, 张光, 许翰英, 张连福, 班唱, 王凤仪, 王玉蓉, 赵荣琛, 桑园, 老生, 曹世, 厉慧良, 沈春奎, 曹明, 高晋卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹二庚</mainName>
    <names>[何昆林, 曹二庚, 罗小宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹云金</mainName>
    <names>[郭德纲, 曹云金]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹</mainName>
    <names>[曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹和雯</mainName>
    <names>[曹和雯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹威治</mainName>
    <names>[曹汝龙, 陈玉莲, 王晓燕, 陈爱珠, 田汉, 杜丽娘, 王瑞兰, 曹威治, 杨开慧, 傅艺萍, 杜鹃, 庞焕励, 黄耀华, 红书宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹宝禄</mainName>
    <names>[胡迪骂, 曹宝禄, 阎, 刘淑慧, 李芬, 白云鹏, 张辛元, 荣, 张帼英, 韩德福, 曹派, 魏金栋, 谢等, 尚福春, 常, 曹, 赵国, 刘宝全, 张玉林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹建红</mainName>
    <names>[王梦云, 李逵, 王, 曹建红, 岳母, 徐母骂, 曹, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹强</mainName>
    <names>[曹强]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹心泉</mainName>
    <names>[王琴侬, 仲仁, 陈墨香, 徐小香, 曹三爷, 班坐科, 曹心泉, 叶盛章, 小泉, 吕, 梅兰芳, 曹瑞石, 曹凤志, 姜妙香, 荀慧生, 叶盛兰, 习老生, 尤擅, 曹寿, 成科班, 李四门, 郭春山, 胡筋十八, 金兰之, 官称曹, 陈德霖, 金, 富连成, 唯曹心泉, 路南, 石即名, 傅芸子, 韩家潭, 心泉, 曹, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹毅琳</mainName>
    <names>[魏华, 赵桐珊, 曹毅琳, 梅兰芳, 张君秋, 孔雀东南飞, 乌兰夫, 程玉菁, 陈世鼐]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹汉昌</mainName>
    <names>[李宏声, 王洁良, 曹汉昌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹汝龙</mainName>
    <names>[洪常青, 李玉和, 曹汝龙, 杨修, 周恩来, 黄飞虎, 杨子荣, 赵勇刚, 郭建光, 陆长海, 薛仁贵两角, 张广才]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹溪明</mainName>
    <names>[刘湘臣, 韩子峰, 曹溪明, 张蓉华, 武生, 茹元俊, 董海川, 刘长清, 黄元庆, 曹, 李如春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹瑞石</mainName>
    <names>[陈桐云, 曹世才, 曹瑞石, 王泊生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹织云</mainName>
    <names>[曹织云, 曹啸君, 曹汉昌, 曹莉, 潘祖强]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹艺斌</mainName>
    <names>[唐韵笙, 曹宝义, 李少春, 王雁, 李洪春, 曹艺斌, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 王派, 叶盛兰, 韩慎先, 张少甫, 娄廷玉, 王鸿寿, 管韵华, 徐策, 杜近芳, 徐敏初, 李, 王庾生, 杨宝森, 钱宝森, 刘备, 杨六郎, 袁世海, 马德成, 曹善亭, 程永龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹连孝</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 唐通, 马连良, 曹合演, 曹连孝, 张春彦, 陈喜星, 雷喜, 安学海, 曹, 李盛藻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曹韵清</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 曹永清, 诸葛亮, 名邀曹, 曹韵清, 侯宪补]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曾荣华</mainName>
    <names>[曾荣华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>曾长生</mainName>
    <names>[丁兰, 苏昆, 于苏, 田氏, 施桂林, 曾长生, 苏授艺, 柳印记·访友]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱丁奇</mainName>
    <names>[梁保华, 赵贯一, 王则昭, 王少生, 熊志麟, 陈, 孙国良, 杨两派, 白玉艳, 张伟品, 张信忠, 陈少云, 朱丁奇, 谭派, 王全熹, 程双椿, 陈门, 王少良, 王琴生, 王珮瑜, 童强, 朱丁, 赵麟童]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱世奎</mainName>
    <names>[朱世奎, 朱桂芳, 杨丽花, 罗文奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱世慧</mainName>
    <names>[艾世菊, 孙盛武, 徐九, 孙正阳, 朱世慧, 梅花奖, 张哨庄, 陈鹤峰, 梅兰芳, 李四广]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱云鹏</mainName>
    <names>[朱家夔, 朱云鹏, 李玉茹, 李蔷华, 曾参加, 刘长林, 宋继亭, 杨宝森, 张春华, 尚小云, 尚, 李陵碑, 孙中山, 随姐夫, 伍子, 黄桂秋, 黄宝岩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱作舟</mainName>
    <names>[朱作舟, 王庚生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱依萍</mainName>
    <names>[陆锦娟, 朱级卿, 朱依萍, 陈少鵬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱凤桐</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 杨丽丽, 赵绮霞, 王熙凤, 樊, 苏三, 法门寺, 汪伪, 朱慧芳, 王紫苓, 吴素秋, 张派, 王多芬, 荀慧生, 徐凌云, 何玉凤, 狄云鸾, 张艳秋, 俞步兰, 朱, 刘媒婆, 朱所授, 张金, 荀, 宋巧姣, 奚啸伯, 朱凤桐, 吴富琴, 薛金莲, 王宝钏, 胡, 万氏, 程砚秋, 霍小玉, 苏武, 汪精卫, 萧太, 杨素贞, 孙玉姣, 朱老]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱啸风</mainName>
    <names>[朱啸风, ，, 俞振飞, 田汉, 朱烨, 红卫兵, 朱啸, 赵氏, 马, 吴祖光, 班里, 张飞, 贺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱复</mainName>
    <names>[潘祥生, 徐致靖, 白永宽, 陶金, 沈有鼎, 栋, 盛庆玉, 邱惠亭, 宋春舫, 王芷章, 韩世昌, 陈荣会, 樊暮雪, 刘欣万, 吴承仕, 王鹏, 俞樾, 白云生, 刘赶三, 童曼秋, 李冰, 许宝驯, 侯长治, 常, 魏熙, 周妙, 郑振铎, 薛仲斗, 徐调孚, 刘之屏, 顾曲周郎, 冯梦祯, 景师逝, 张兆和, 袁师复, 俞平伯, 文部, 汪仁溥, 侯瑞春, 赵子敬, 朱崇儒, 张长, 王季思, 俞平, 俞庆, 庞世奇, 董, 郝振基, 张仕君, 张充和, 唐兰, 朱佳, 谢佩贞, 袁敏宣, 谢绳祖, 徐炎之, 洪炳文, 周铨庵, 许姬传, 王府, 郭汉城, 张惠玲, 朱小义, 尤爱, 张引荐, 王欣甫, 王守泰, 夏承焘, 王正来, 宋威服, 韩子, 朱孝臧, 许闻佩, 戈宝, 王夏薇, 李益仲, 徐家礼, 黄殿章, 徐凌云, 宋云彬, 习老生, 许伯遒, 吴世昌, 徐鹏, 王传蕖, 高永华, 陈竹隐, 张宗祥, 刘巍, 刘骏业, 刘韧, 谭其骧, 姚雅扶, 何师曲, 钟馗, 李体扬, 王益友, 俞振飞, 张文田, 曾谒, 何金海, 朱冠瀛, 朱寿, 张元济, 张文生, 宇文, 伊克贤, 马珏, 周瑞深, 徐子权, 陈栩, 高步云, 田瑞庭, 张琦翔, 朱经畬, 袁敏, 陈盛可, 全福昆, 贾津门, 叶长海, 胡忌, 侯百朋, 朱家溍, 苏昆, 周紫垣, 沈沉, 齐森华, 马祥麟, 胡士莹, 陈禹莲, 蒋复璁, 许茹香, 张伯驹, 王鹏云, 叶仰曦, 俞派, 庄一拂, 谢锡恩, 徐希博, 陶小庭, 袁薇, 许鸿宾, 杨荫浏, 杨小楼, 赵文林, 俞腔, 惠成, 马凤彩, 侯永奎, 李伯琴, 陈少岩, 徐惠如, 若龙, 唐湜, 徐斯年, 袁寒云, 师感其诚, 何静源, 曹安和, 徐廷璧, 陈伯平, 刘长喜, 拍曲子, 戴夏, 何师, 路西, 陶显庭, 袁师嘱, 红凈, 高腔, 花】一, 刘富梁, 王西澄, 许雨香, 钱锡采, 陈延甫, 曾撰, 项馨吾, 陶光, 张宗和, 赵景深, 吴恩裕, 徐小香, 李金寿, 胡雪冈, 赵景, 陆剑霞, 陈祖东, 甘熙, 田丹丹, 荣庆, 张岱, 陈从周, 钮骠, 伊兵, 许宝騄, 翁偶虹, 费松年, 吴小如, 郭蓬莱, 侯公携子, 徐朔方, 吴宝镕, 谢锡恩（1903-1993, 马磊, 徐韶九, 侯益隆, 李福谦, 李鸿章, 陈春苗, 杨文辉, 俞派清, 何墉, 许宝騋, 王国维, 俞师, 汪健君, 李慈铭, 张允和, 顾铁华, 李承煊, 王鹏运, 许金修, 洪巍, 朱复, 曹仲陶, 汪以钫, 陆宗达, 许士箴, 俞氏, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱小义</mainName>
    <names>[郝振基, 朱小义, 王益友, 曾师事]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱少云</mainName>
    <names>[叶盛兰, 朱荣升, 奚啸伯, 叶盛章, 荣春, 梅兰芳, 朱少云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱少秋</mainName>
    <names>[朱少秋, 袁世, 沙基, 朱智新, 安重根]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱平</mainName>
    <names>[朱, 曲协, 金华, 朱平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱幼芬</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱文相</mainName>
    <names>[张庚, 朱文相, 叶盛兰, 朱文相戏, 与叶派, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱文英</mainName>
    <names>[阎岚秋, 张淇林, 黄润甫, 子朱, 朱文英, 朱小喜, 朱盛富, 俞菊笙, 朱桂芳, 武生, 富连成, 朱四十, 桂芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱斌仙</mainName>
    <names>[俞振庭, 毛庆, 李玉茹, 朱琴心, 梅兰芳, 姜妙香, 荀慧生, 张义, 刘庆义, 朱斌仙, 高庆奎, 路宽, 李万春, 赵啸澜, 黄玉华, 奚啸伯, 李多奎, 朱锦华, 孙毓堃, 朱饰, 台揍, 唐僧, 管绍华, 孔雀东南, 陈富瑞, 王玉蓉, 费世, 欧阳德, 徐斌寿, 李庆, 朱斌, 杨斌昌, 李七, 孟丽君, 孟小冬, 王维秋饰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱永康</mainName>
    <names>[朱永康, 黄腔, 徐派, 黄派, 黄桂秋, 王兰英, 朱, 尤喜, 吴汉, 黄小秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱璎媛</mainName>
    <names>[胡锦芳, 张继青, 朱璎媛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱石凤</mainName>
    <names>[王少媛, 许秀莺, 刘知远, 郑怀兴, 朱石凤, 金]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱秉谦</mainName>
    <names>[朱连荣, 马连良, 雷喜福, 穆桂英, 朱维义, 刘秀荣, 朱秉谦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱素云</mainName>
    <names>[杨小朵, 程砚秋, 三美, 孙一, 朱素云, 王瑶卿, 尚小云, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱维斌</mainName>
    <names>[刘陆娴, 仲仁, 朱瑞祥, 朱继屏, 朱文英, 徐露, 曹心泉, 朱桂芳, 朱湘泉, 朱维斌, 苏雨卿, 王陆瑶]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱翔飞</mainName>
    <names>[更生, 朱翔飞, 朱杏林, 张利利, 朱, 何双呆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱金琴</mainName>
    <names>[朱金琴, 赵燕侠, 朱文英, 吕伯奢, 朱桂芳, 程浦, 潘必正, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱金钊</mainName>
    <names>[朱亚凯, 赵德芳, 李, 张辽, 姬光, 朱金钊, 荀慧生, 黄玉若, 程敬思, 高庆奎, 陈世美]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱阔泉</mainName>
    <names>[尹凤岐, 李寿增, 叶寿亭, 朱先生, 朱蒋氏, 徐策, 王, 西单相, 李, 王宝童, 张寿臣, 于俊波, 林, 周信芳, 汤金澄, 张杰尧, 侯宝麟, 李宝麒, 朱, 朱阔泉, 西郊, 李寿清, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李万春</mainName>
    <names>[李结为, 梅兰芳, 李陵碑, 蔡鸣棻, 荀慧生, 梅演, 张春德, 徐德增, 李砚秀, 秦晋, 李永利, 李磊, 梅剧团, 石庆福, 李桐春, 景泉, 杨小楼, 郝鸣振, 刘奎, 王鸣仲, 连良, 李万春, 张春林, 蓝月春, 胡鸣忠, 李小春, 李, 王鸣咏, 常鸣莲, 四郎, 赵鸣复, 徐鸣策, 周鸣歧, 李桂春, 张德俊, 洪鸣珠, 郝鸣超, 姜铁, 李万, 马鸣喆, 朱鸣秀, 项, 岳飞, 应宝, 于德智, 俞振庭, 刘鸣恭, 张春孝, 李氏, 张鸣福, 吴素秋, 杨鸣孝, 李洪春, 尚小云, 张鸣禄, 田七郎, 张鸣宇, 李庆春, 马少良, 黄天霸, 李伯, 陈鸣彤, 赵松樵, 崔凤鸣, 刘鸣宝, 常鸣晋, 吴春奎, 董文华, 张德禄, 杨鸣庆, 刘清提, 关鸣林, 李鸣升, 徐策, 李吉瑞, 李圜春, 董鸣寿, 周桓, 赵安伯, 杨瑞亭, 刘鸣才, 马连良, 吴鸣申, 王伦, 万春, 李鸣鹤, 曹, 陆文龙, 焦鸣荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李世济</mainName>
    <names>[程砚, 马连良, 李世济, 谭富英, 赵桐珊, 王幼卿, 刘, 梅兰芳, 裘盛戎, 陈三两]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李世源</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 李世源, 张连福, 梅兰, 马连良, 李春林, 王喜秀, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李世琦</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 潘侠, 王, 李世琦, 王喜秀, 宋继亭, 顾日伦, 裘, 张盛禄, 甄洪奎, 谭小培, 富英, 沈春奎, 刘喜益, 李一车, 孙安动, 张志贤]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李世章</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 王连平, 刘备, 唐明皇, 李五, 雷喜福, 李少春, 鲁肃, 张连, 叶春善, 王喜秀, 吴素秋, 李世章, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李世芳</mainName>
    <names>[李世, 魏莲芳, 梅兰, 张世孝, 李子, 萧长华, 梅派, 姚玉芙, 毛世, 王世续, 梅兰芳, 苏雨卿, 李连贞, 张彩林, 张君秋, 李世芳, 刘元彤, 宋德珠, 班承芳, 童伶]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李丹林</mainName>
    <names>[李丹林, 赵芝香, 钟荣, 尚小云, 李佩红]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李丽芳</mainName>
    <names>[李丽芳, 李慧芳, 穆桂英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李仲林</mainName>
    <names>[帅, 张翼鹏, 班赴苏, 李, 燕青, 郑派, 武, 李逵, 金刀阵, 仲林, 杨子荣, 孙悟空, 李仲林, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李伟建</mainName>
    <names>[刘洪沂, 姜昆, 李伟建]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李伯祥</mainName>
    <names>[郑健, 王平, 李伯祥, 孙少臣, 李松泉, 戴志诚, 杜国, 曲苑, 李洁尘, 周游, 金旺, 刘松茂]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李佩卿</mainName>
    <names>[吴长顺, 李初, 王瘦生, 李佩卿, 李氏, 李, 蒲吴, 刘子璞, 姜妙香, 谭派, 琴拉得, 胡琴, 孙朗臣, 窦砚峰, 王氏, 王君直, 周折, 谭鑫培, 王君]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李元春</mainName>
    <names>[李荣升, 李元春, 李寿山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李光</mainName>
    <names>[沈健瑾, 王连平, 茹富兰, 孙毓堃, 李少春, 李, 李宗义, 李光1952年, 文武, 赵勇刚, 李光, 李岩, 李欣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李兴堂</mainName>
    <names>[李兴堂, 李春长, 李, 李福增]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李凤云</mainName>
    <names>[李凤云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李凤翔</mainName>
    <names>[李凤翔, 李砚萍, 李砚芳, 李砚秀, 李砚琴, 李砚秋, 李顺来]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李加成</mainName>
    <names>[李加成]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李吉来</mainName>
    <names>[李吉来, 威严得, 刘吉庆, 王, 李却有, 梁红玉, 刘师托, 金素琴, 韩世忠, 于板眼, 王洪寿, 王喜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李吉瑞</mainName>
    <names>[洪亮, 宋, 里11号, 李吉瑞, 孙菊仙, 田七郎, 薛凤池, 百代, 李吉瑞家, 高强, 尚和玉, 武功, 李吉, 杨小楼, 程永龙, 任正乐]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李和保</mainName>
    <names>[李和保, 习武旦, 李永, 李]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李和曾</mainName>
    <names>[鲁, 詹天, 李少春, 李和曾, 李, 鲁豫, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 王旗, 冀搭, 袁世海, 王和霖, 高庆奎, 孙安动, 高庆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李喜泉</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 李喜泉, 彭喜凤]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李喜鸿</mainName>
    <names>[尚, 刘山丽, 李喜鸿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李嘉存</mainName>
    <names>[张, 李嘉存, 高英培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李嘉林</mainName>
    <names>[南霸天, 姚刚, 杨门, 班晋京, 王文, 刘维, 王晶华, 李咏山, 巢, 杨门女, 王王文, 袁世海, 满江红, 卓著, 孙岳, 李嘉林, 张飞, 焦赞, 王凤朝, 宇宙锋, 杨秋玲, 班社, 里根]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李四广</mainName>
    <names>[步青, 张派戏, 梅派戏, 董智斌, 谭富英, 谭鑫, 俞菊笙, 李少广, 李顺亭, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 李四广, 李顺德, 张君秋, 荀慧生, 巢, 孔雀东南, 程砚秋, 马连良, 雷锋塔, 郭春山, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李国先</mainName>
    <names>[张永熙, 曲苑, 金陵, 李国先]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李国盛</mainName>
    <names>[李国盛, 侯宝, 刘宝瑞, 沙洼乡]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李增瑞</mainName>
    <names>[李增瑞, 王谦详, 穆桂英, 李, 罗成戏, 胡拴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李多奎</mainName>
    <names>[李多, 沙兼而有之, 王梦云, 李多奎, 李盛泉, 李鸣岩, 谢宝云, 高庆奎, 王玉敏, 王晓临, 李金泉, 李派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李多芬</mainName>
    <names>[李鸣盛, 李文瑛, 胡璇, 李多奎, 周信芳, 李多芬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李大春</mainName>
    <names>[李大春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李奎林</mainName>
    <names>[郝六, 梅巧玲, 杨隆寿, 李奎林, 李五, 姚增禄, 李春元, 李, 谭鑫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李奘图</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 陈永玲, 李幕良, 孙荣蕙, 于震之, 良京, 梅派青, 李宝华, 韩玉娘, 梅兰芳, 罗蕙兰, 莫须, 李长清, 许翰英, 李盛荫, 于万, 苏盛琴, 薛保, 李门为, 薛倚儿, 黄, 程鹏举, 秦士, 孟广亨, 马派老生, 李, 李少卿, 李门, 马玉和, 钟世章, 马连, 班世超, 郭元汾, 王少卿, 马玉芳, 杨, 仲帮忙, 李丽芳, 王和霖, 亨是梅, 李荣芳, 王吟秋, 李鸣盛, 曹, 李奘图, 李超昆, 李超]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李妙春</mainName>
    <names>[荀香, 演出荀, 李妙春, 班进京]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李宏</mainName>
    <names>[史玉洁, 李鸣岩, 杨门女, 赵鸣华, 于姜, 李逵, 李多奎, 李宏, 李, 岳母, 田萍, 洪母骂, 李派, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李宗义</mainName>
    <names>[正昌, 李光工, 梅兰, 李玉芝, 王泉, 田汉, 李岩, 张春华, 鲍吉祥, 姜妙香, 李光, 梁小鸾, 尤佳, 江汉, 李多奎, 李岩能, 王庾生, 郑如冰, 刁丽, 四郎, 高亢, 沈健瑾, 李欣工, 赵世璞, 诸茹香, 马诸派, 李慧芳, 孙畹华, 茹富慧, 刘鸿声, 李宗义, 曹, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李定坤</mainName>
    <names>[李定坤, 曾入]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李宝凤</mainName>
    <names>[吴汉杀, 左右, 王二英, 周恩来, 李, 赵美蓉, 皮秀英, 周信芳, 杨八姐, 吕咸蔚, 周公赶, 李宝凤]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李宝櫆</mainName>
    <names>[俞振庭, 梅兰, 李玉茹, 李少春, 李少, 李寿峰, 李宝櫆, 汪派, 梅兰芳, 李宝魁, 李奇身, 姜妙香, 秦乃英, 何佩华, 尤擅, 曾工, 梁慧超, 翁偶虹, 李寿山, 马后, 许德义, 李少筠, 尚长荣, 李奇, 诸葛亮, 杨小楼, 何以没, 汪笑依派, 李菊笙, 李奇竟, 梅葆玖, 李, 宝魁, 俞菊笙, 童红, 俞振飞, 沈郦明, 李盛藻, 章遏云, 汪派戏, 周云亮, 刘备, 九岁红, 大夫, 江世玉, 李二爷, 成名快, 张世桐, 王琴生, 俞氏, 童芷苓, 梅葆玥, 周瑜, 李老]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李宝櫆</mainName>
    <names>[俞振庭, 梅兰, 李玉茹, 李少春, 李少, 李寿峰, 李宝櫆, 汪派, 梅兰芳, 李宝魁, 李奇身, 姜妙香, 秦乃英, 何佩华, 尤擅, 曾工, 梁慧超, 翁偶虹, 李寿山, 马后, 许德义, 李少筠, 尚长荣, 李奇, 诸葛亮, 杨小楼, 何以没, 汪笑依派, 李菊笙, 李奇竟, 梅葆玖, 李, 宝魁, 俞菊笙, 童红, 俞振飞, 沈郦明, 李盛藻, 章遏云, 汪派戏, 周云亮, 刘备, 九岁红, 大夫, 江世玉, 李二爷, 成名快, 张世桐, 王琴生, 俞氏, 童芷苓, 梅葆玥, 周瑜, 李老]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李宝琴</mainName>
    <names>[李宝琴, 霍桂霞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李寿山</mainName>
    <names>[李宝, 李所授, 梅兰, 陈, 王月芳, 李菊笙, 王, 荣升, 武净, 尚小云, 寿峰, 韩乐卿, 李七儿, 罗燕臣, 李庆喜, 曾习, 李七演, 文武, 徐宝芳, 叶福海, 武生, 李奇, 李凤云, 朱文, 范福泰, 淑荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李寿峰</mainName>
    <names>[凤桐, 陈, 习老生, 李菊笙, 李盛荫, 李寿山, 谭鑫, 李寿峰, 李六, 李奇, 易名, 梅兰芳, 寿峰, 李盛藻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李小培</mainName>
    <names>[王福来, 张德华, 高长清, 孟宪达, 赵振武, 李小培, 杨振纲, 李广仁, 孟俊泉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李小春</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 朱家夔, 张世麟, 李小春, ，, 李少春, 四郎, 李晶, 曹, 李蕊未, 阎秀兰, 李继春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李小雄</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 李小雄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李少岩</mainName>
    <names>[王尔烈, 孔广山, 花淑兰, 李少岩, 苏小妹, 马淑华, 唐寅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李少春</mainName>
    <names>[丁永利, 李少春, 李少, 陈秀华, 杨派, 李桂春, 文武, 孙悟空, 曹, 宗杨]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李少楼</mainName>
    <names>[彭得怀, 宋庆龄, 金日成, 周恩来, 李少楼, 侯永奎, 邓小平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李岩</mainName>
    <names>[钱培荣, 刘罗锅, 王连平, 宰相, 茹富兰, 曹连孝, 李, 宋继亭, 李岩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李崇善</mainName>
    <names>[梅兰, 孔繁森, 王瑞芝, 梅葆玖, 陆长海, 李盛藻, 梁山, 谭派, 李崇善, 李玉芙, 马永安, 富英, 张学津, 桑园, 梅葆玥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李师斌</mainName>
    <names>[李师斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李广仁</mainName>
    <names>[鲁智深, 袁世, 后台, 李逵, 李, 杨赤, 张飞, 曹操, 李广仁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李广伯</mainName>
    <names>[黄钟大吕, 夏, 吕瑞明, 夏美珍, 林燕, 魏海敏, 曾聘, 刘学钦, 郭小庄, 尤擅, 赵氏, 杨秋玲, 吴钰璋, 胡演, 秦香莲, 唐畹华, 王杰, 李, 吴素英, 何谓, 杜, 孙盛武, 杨门女, 袁世海, 李丽芳, 满江红, 冯志孝, 白求恩, 袁国林, 孙岳, 张岚, 张庚, 李金泉, 毛泽东, 吴兴国, 马玉琪, 李维康, 张春孝, 李少春, 宋玉庆, 刘长瑜, 毛笔, 李欣, 孙洪勋, 李逵, 郭根森, 艾美君, 李光, 夏永泉, 陈白尘, 提亚, 沈玉才, 高玉倩, 杜近芳, 周恩来, 李广伯, 曲素英, 毕, 陈延龄, 郭自勤, 王晶华, 俞, 孙萍, 沈健瑾, 胡, 姚品一, 宋长荣, 叶, 李玉, 刘秀荣, 盛兰, 朱秉谦, 李广, 肖勇]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李庆喜</mainName>
    <names>[李庆喜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李庆春</mainName>
    <names>[朱光祖, 李庆春, 窦氏, 李永利, 张飞, 陆谦, 李桐春, 李修缘, 孙悟空, 李小林, 李万春, 杨香武, 蓝月春, 孙二娘, 苏连汉, 张文秀, 李小春, 刘世亭, 徐良, 李佩, 蒋平, 李圜春, 罗汉, 金松, 刘利华, 陈富瑞, 武丑, 西藏京, 万春, 曹操]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李建华</mainName>
    <names>[姜昆, 李金斗, 王平, 王援朝, 唐杰忠, 马, 李建华, 赵连甲, 刘洪沂, 郝爱民, 刘全刚, 阎月明, 大姐夫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李彦生</mainName>
    <names>[王世臣, 田立禾, 侯耀华, 李彦生, 刘文亨]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李德奎</mainName>
    <names>[周成贤, 李德奎, 娄振奎, 李幼奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李德山</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 赵燕侠, 王瑞芝, 谭富英, 任张, 谭元寿, 费文治, 李慕良, 梅兰芳, 李毓芳, 罗蕙兰, 张, 耿永清, 叶盛兰, 李凌枫, 张君秋拜, 李崇善, 吴炳璋, 后直, 王晓临, 孟俊泉, 梁小鸾, 杨宝忠, 沈玉才, 李, 胡伴奏, 李广伯, 于谦, 徐兰沅, 陈大濩, 杨宝森, 曾应, 双东, 南铁生, 彭真, 张君秋, 马长礼, 徐东霞, 吴素, 李德山, 马连良, 李玉芙, 马永安, 张学津, 李鸣盛, 徐东明, 徐氏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李德才</mainName>
    <names>[郭敬之, 黄如初, 于衷, 陈仲枢, 贾树三, 李德才, 秋江, 罗俊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李德钖</mainName>
    <names>[李德钖, 张宗昌, 莫不潸, 刘宝, 朱凤岐, 张寿臣, 张捧哏, 张, 袁世, 李德, 八德, 滑稽昔, 李改, 袁府, 王佐, 贾凫西, 孔子陈, 石头, 张飞, 姜尚, 袁消, 杨小楼, 刘宝全, 李佩亭, 胡同, 李, 袁世凯, 蔡绝粮, 张摹, 约马德禄, 任九门, 马德禄, 徐有禄, 张德泉, 李摹仿, 武丑, 万人迷, 王善耆, 李‘豆, 李广义, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李忆兰</mainName>
    <names>[吴爽, 张羽煮, 李, 忆兰, 张德福, 魏素珍, 刘巧儿, 李忆兰, 吴爽借]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李忆霞</mainName>
    <names>[张羽煮, 莫愁女, 荣冠, 张羽, 杨乃武, 红珊, 李忆霞, 刘派, 李忆兰, 梅香, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李志良</mainName>
    <names>[徐兰沅, 李志良, 李佩卿, 谭富英, 于世文]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李惠仙</mainName>
    <names>[祝文, 李惠仙, ，, 李, 平西夏, 岳夫, 李惠, 王昭君, 与其夫, 正音清, 李蜀翘, 杨家将, 叶秋枫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李慧岩</mainName>
    <names>[李慧岩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李慧芳</mainName>
    <names>[吕布, 李慧芳, 李玉龙, 梅派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李承秀</mainName>
    <names>[高世舜, 诸葛亮, 刘派, 刘文斌, 李承秀]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李政成</mainName>
    <names>[裴艳玲, 希拉克, 白玉兰, 周洪武, 李政成, 朱, 李岚清, 江泽民, 吴官正, 姚恭林, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李敏</mainName>
    <names>[王, 李敏, 尹桂芳, 李敏便, 何从, 李金凤, 王君安, 李敏姗, 芳华, 李敏先, 尹, 王文娟, 柳毅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李文华</mainName>
    <names>[姜昆, 赵世忠, 李文华, 刘宝瑞, 马志明代, 赵炎, 唐杰忠, 郝爱民, 李搭档, 爽朗, 郭启儒]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李文山</mainName>
    <names>[郝爱民, 郭全宝, 宣武, 李文贵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李明华</mainName>
    <names>[李明华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李明华</mainName>
    <names>[姚传芗, 金华, ，, 李明华, 张娴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李春恒</mainName>
    <names>[小玉成, 萧长华, 李春恒]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李春林</mainName>
    <names>[李春林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李春福</mainName>
    <names>[李春福]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李朝贵</mainName>
    <names>[李朝贵, 白登云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李树建</mainName>
    <names>[李树建, ，, 南新]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李桂芬</mainName>
    <names>[朱砂痣, 梁, 李宗, 王, 卢燕原, 李玉农, 双栖玳瑁, 李洪春, 刘, 梅兰芳, 田际, 卢家, 谭派, 刘派, 王铁珊, 海燕, 卢燕寄, 李桂, 尹, 卢家少, 杨玉环, 刘鸿升, 李春福, 云玉成, 李, 李洪福, 卢, 卢氏, 李慧琴, 卢百万, 于陆, 王幼卿, 汪派坤, 王桂卿, 居梅兰, 金香, 梅葆玥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李桐春</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 李鸣俊, 李圜, 王振, 李永利, 李蔷华, 红生, 李桐春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李桐轩</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 孙仁玉, 李桐轩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李毓芳</mainName>
    <names>[马连良, 谭富英, 李毓芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李永玲</mainName>
    <names>[巴蜀, 李永玲, 王永梭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李洁尘</mainName>
    <names>[王宝钏, 李伯祥, 李惠民, 冯立铎, 李洁尘, 隆福寺, 马文忠, 赵心敏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李洪春</mainName>
    <names>[葛文玉, 李万春, 李春才, 王金璐, 王十三, 洪杨, 李洪春, 李金声, 武定, 陆华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李海泉</mainName>
    <names>[陈铁军, 李震彪, 罗通扫, 吴宫春, 李海泉, 李满船, 廖侠怀, 李振辉, 任丑生, 于断崖, 肖丽章, 叶弗弱, 李小龙, 李满甜, 李振藩, 薛觉先, 望夫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李润杰</mainName>
    <names>[平, 李润杰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李淑君</mainName>
    <names>[马祥麟, 李淑君, 韩世昌, 严凤英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李爱琴</mainName>
    <names>[李万祥, 张渔煮, 李正敏, 刘毓中, 须生, 班进京, 秦腔, 叶盛兰, 董化清, 曹植, 孙安动, 盖叫天, 李万春, 彭艺社, 周仁, 何言答, 苏育民, 贾宝玉, 孙安, 红线女, 李爱琴, 正旦, 常新, 李三, 陈伯华, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李玉书</mainName>
    <names>[杨瑞亭, 吴铁庵, 苏武, 马连良, 张少甫, 于己, 蓬莱, 李玉书]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李玉芙</mainName>
    <names>[华世香, 梅兰芳, 李慧芳, 李玉芙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李玉芝</mainName>
    <names>[李玉芝, 李玉茹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李玉茹</mainName>
    <names>[胡凤莲, 唐赛儿, 明志, 梅兰, 谭富英, 李玉茹, 法门寺, 李少春, 赵桐珊, 叶盛章, 西欧, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 秦腔, 叶盛兰, 卢凤英, 宇宙锋, 李慧娘, 宋士杰, 王瑶卿, 百战, 俞振飞, 杨宝森, 于京, 皮黄, 郭元汾, 苏武, 马连良, 袁世海, 郭际, 冯素蕙, 马富禄, 曹禺, 董小宛, 赵, 杨素贞, 李玉, 高维廉, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李环春</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 李志奇, 李桐春, 李环春, 李志希, 沈涪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李甫春</mainName>
    <names>[叶荫章, 李春城, 李荣奎, 茹元俊, 李洪春, 尚小云, 梁山, 鲍吉祥, 叶盛兰, 高盛麟, 李逵, 周英鹏, 白家麟, 王少芳, 严慧春, 王凤朝, 周国兴, 李甫春, 宋江, 孙盛文, 李金鸿, 王玉让, 杜近芳, 吴素英, 杨韵谱, 陈福, 李盛藻, 王凤卿, 钟世章, 王林, 刘备, 马连良, 伍子, 冯志孝, 赵荣琛, 张长林, 李三娘, 唐王, 王玉敏, 岳母, 孙岳, 朱秉谦, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李百川</mainName>
    <names>[李百川]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李盛斌</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 李玉茹, 李盛斌, 李少春, 李, 武松, 于京, 李洪春, 尚, 盛, 王连平, 高盛麟, 叶春善, 李万]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李盛泉</mainName>
    <names>[田金萍, 王梦云, 李树芝, 李多奎, 李盛泉, 孙花满, 张弛, 岳母, 王玉敏, 李金泉, 胡璇]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李盛荫</mainName>
    <names>[李荣升, 孙盛辅, 荣春社, 陈, 雷喜福, 谭富英, 李盛荫, 曾随伊, 李寿山, 李寿峰, 王喜秀, 李奇, 李盛藻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李盛藻</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 刘盛莲, 沈玉, 李寿峰, 张, 高盛麟, 赵云, 李寿山, 李正平, 高庆奎, 王凤朝, 高庆, 李万春, 李凤池, 李, 刘关, 王喜秀, 于京, 高, 四郎, 李盛藻, 杜, 陈丽芳, 赵世璞, 王连平, 鲁肃一角, 刘备, 苏武, 马连良, 袁世海, 陈盛荪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李砚秀</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 孙毓堃, 李砚萍, 宋遇, 周瑞安, 李卜春, 李睿舟, 秋香, 李丹, 刘砚亭, 李淑媛, 李新喜, 李艺春, 李砚秋, 姜铁, 李顺来, 欧阳德, 李凤翔, 李砚芳, 李万, 李砚琴, 李新华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李砚萍</mainName>
    <names>[陈旭慧, 周云亮, 宋长荣, 李砚秀, 魏莲芳, 樊, 周天, 李砚秋, 李顺来, 李砚萍, 李砚芳, 李砚琴, 喻慧霞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李素芹</mainName>
    <names>[李双双, 陈素真, 马旦, 杜近芳, 桑振君, 曾亲受, 崔兰田, 李素芹, 叶]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李紫贵</mainName>
    <names>[江汉, 葛嫩娘, 田汉, 周信芳, 牛郎, 李紫贵, 盖叫天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李红梅</mainName>
    <names>[李红梅, 李维康, 蔡英莲, 李慧芳, 赵玉侠, 杨春霞, 侯素芹, 艾美君, 马小曼, 宇宙锋, 秦香, 孙婉华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李绍华</mainName>
    <names>[李翠萍, 王婉华, 郭仲丽, 陈小燕, 张派, 刘秀荣, 张敏智, 舒昌玉, 李绍华, 秦香, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李经文</mainName>
    <names>[刘中石, 杨荣环, 花旦, 华子, 穆桂英, 李经文, 四郎, 刘, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李继宗</mainName>
    <names>[吕布戏, 陈付康, 王东波, 李继宗]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李维康</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 李香匀, 荀令香, 李玉茹, 赵桐珊, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 于玉蘅, 张君秋, 张, 巢, 杨门女, 李凤姐, 宇宙锋, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李舒</mainName>
    <names>[李长春, 刘曾复, 袁世海, 李舒, 雷喜福, 叶盛, 孙岳, 宋继亭, 李枢, 李洪春, 杨秋玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李茹茵</mainName>
    <names>[刘胡兰, 吴寿朋, 孙凤岗, 陈三五, 李茹茵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李荣威</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 尚小云, 彭德怀, 徐荣奎, 李万春, 胡二, 宋宝罗, 洪亮, 黄玉华, 张志云, 李华, 李晓威, 李向荣, 宋富亭, 奚啸, 杨宝森, 李荣威, 李振奎, 周, 李秀英, 厉慧良, 班社]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李荣安</mainName>
    <names>[李荣安, 荀慧生, 荣春社, 吴三桂, 李丽芳, 李蓉芳, 李鸣盛, 沈富贵, 武大郎, 毛世来, 程继先, 罗成]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李荣岩</mainName>
    <names>[李荣岩, 杨荣环, 胡琴, 李崇善, 茹富兰, 梅兰, 李春林, 孙毓敏, 李鸣盛, 徐兰沅, 吴素秋, 杨荣楼, 宋继亭, 沈葆祯, 尚小云, 梅葆玥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李莉</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 吕布, 华子, 李慧娘, 萧太, 李莉, 四郎, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李蓉芳</mainName>
    <names>[杨宗保, 李世霖, 黄天麟, 韶华, 苏三, 李春恒, 法门寺, 韩玉娘, 迟世恭, 梅兰芳, 叶盛兰, 李砚秀, 何佩华, 吴, 李蓉, 张一然, 李菊云, 孙焕如, 李蓉芳, 李, 四郎, 孙, 虞姬, 袁世海, 周, 王和霖, 李丽芳, 班里, 马旦毛, 周素英, 刘生祥, 刘殿清, 四清, 王, 梅先生, 贺龙, 吴素秋, 闻子芳, 王燕, 李世芳, 朱妻, 廉锦枫, 四处托, 李荣安, 宋巧姣, 黄, 奚啸伯, 高玉倩, 龙套, 蔡宝华, 郭锐, 胡少安, 贺玉钦, 纪玉良, 李玉凤, 张玉英, 毛, 李盛藻, 张元奎, 马连良, 王吟秋, 梁祝, 武大郎, 武功, 杨素贞, 孙振]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李薇华</mainName>
    <names>[荀, 向荀, 时荀, 李蔷华, 张伟君, 师荀慧, 吴申年, 荀慧生, 李薇华, 苏少卿, 华直, 荀派, 孙瑶芳, 李薇, 荀门, 荀令莱, 华调]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李连伟</mainName>
    <names>[王凤山, 李连伟, 王派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李连贞</mainName>
    <names>[汪, 李连贞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李金声</mainName>
    <names>[丁永利, 贾氏, 李万春, 赵慧, 陈金彪, 刘博, 科后拜, 张绣, 谭鑫, 王磊, 朱鸿声, 王慧春, 董玉, 李金声, 李洪春, 秦琼, 李盛藻, 叶盛兰, 宋演, 燕声京, 邹氏, 雷喜福, 王少芳, 荣轩, 郭少衡, 宋德珠, 丁奖]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李金斗</mainName>
    <names>[李金斗, 侯宝, 帅, 赵振铎, 谭伯茹, 王长友]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李金棠</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 周正荣, 李金棠, 伍子, 金素琴, 胡少]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李金泉</mainName>
    <names>[刘俊峰, 李奶奶, 袁世海, 王梦云, 李逵, 李多奎, 赵葆秀, 李少春, 叶盛章, 王晓临, 李金泉, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李金鸿</mainName>
    <names>[李金鸿, 邓敏, 叶盛章, 王瑶卿, 梅兰芳, 韩世昌, 周信芳, 李海燕, 张晶, 李凌枫, 袁金锦, 诸茹香, 张火丁, 张善亭, 李世芳, 赵秀君, 刘桂娟, 李士芳, 李洁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李鑫荃</mainName>
    <names>[李鑫荃, 马连登]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李长春</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 李长春, 侯喜瑞, 郝寿臣, 李春恒, 宋富亭, 李桂春, 叶盛兰, 裘派神韵, 骆连翔, 叶少兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李门</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 曹洪义, 张春孝, 李氏, 唐, 杨春霞, 刘长瑜, 张建国, 江其虎, 秋唱腔, 梅兰芳, 梅韵, 刘本, 张舜华, 王仁武, 苏盛琴, 杨博森, 叶少兰, 李志祥, 燕守平, 李门为, 李光, 杨秋玲, 费玉明, 薛倚儿, 吴钰璋, 王艳, 杜近芳, 李, 李慧娘, 杨洪均, 梅派, 刁丽, 李门, 李门除, 王晶华, 于魁智, 张晶, 张君秋, 李谷一, 袁世海, 李丽芳, 李慧芳, 冯志孝, 马, 李玉芙, 张学津, 张君, 李鸣盛, 孙岳, 李萍, 夏京, 马小曼, 杜近, 刘秀荣, 葛彤, 李奘图, 李超, 姚明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李阳鸣</mainName>
    <names>[李磊, 李万春, 李阳鸣, 李卜春, 裴元庆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李青</mainName>
    <names>[鲁大牛, 丁阿发, 李青, 孟雄, 巴里, 鲍勃·霍甫, 周柏春, 张利音, 李万松, 姚慕双, 潘少爷, 林浩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李韵章</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 李盛, 曾名, 王盛海, 徐盛, 陈富康, 李少春, 李盛泉, 李韵章, 李寿峰, 金, 赵春瑞, 易名, 太白, 张盛禄, 李盛藻, 荣春社, 李盛荫, 马, 严嵩, 李喜璋, 刘盛通, 厉慧良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李飞龙</mainName>
    <names>[莫汝城, 刘美卿, 黎国荣, 马师, 张逸民, 仇非雄, 林, 李海培, 谢宝, 龙唱, 马师曾, 乐善, 马传菁, 王将相, 李师傅, 周恩来, 陶铸, 刘少奇, 罗家宝, 李飞, 罗汉, 红线女, 李飞龙, 何非凡, 李栽桃, 张相公, 胡不归, 马, 杨子静, 龙哥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李香匀</mainName>
    <names>[李香匀, 艾美珍, 陈德霖, 奚啸伯, 李盛斌, 夏, 陈少霖, 梅派, 于京, 李桂林, 宇宙锋, 励勇]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李鸣玉</mainName>
    <names>[李鸣玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李鸣盛</mainName>
    <names>[李军, 范, 王金亭, 宋, 刘连仑, 黄忠, 吴素秋, 费世韦, 宋继亭, 李鸣, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 谭派, 石秀, 宗余, 赵兵著, 李盛荫, 陈超, 毛世来, 孙安动, 朱小希, 杨家, 张国泰, 黄炳强, 张绣, 王洁清, 沈富贵, 徐兰沅, 杨宝森, 宋富贵, 杨派, 钱宝森, 张君秋, 李华亭, 张连福, 伍子, 雷喜福, 李鸣盛, 刘盛通, 李士琳, 李长]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李鹤谦</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 李鹤谦, 洪亮, 李, 李国安]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>李麟童</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 童15岁, 徐策, 李秉枢, 四郎, 曹艺斌, 李麟, 李麟童, 刘备, 诸葛亮, 任二, 薛平贵, 宋江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杜元田</mainName>
    <names>[杜元田, 马连良, 雷喜福, 谭, 王喜秀, 徐兰沅, 杜世良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杜国芝</mainName>
    <names>[李伯祥, 杜国芝, 耿宝林, 张庆森]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杜近芳</mainName>
    <names>[周昌泰, 谢瑶, 王, 法门寺, 李少春, 梅兰芳, 班进京, 刘玉芳, 姜妙香, 叶盛兰, 富英, 周国兴, 陈世鼐, 杜近芳, 王瑶卿, 徐兰沅, 杨宝森, 李门, 孔雀东南, 袁世海, 伍子, 穆桂英, 李超]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杜鹏</mainName>
    <names>[师陈, 刘福生, 解宝, 李金声, 秦琼, 王世续, 马玉璋, 王志廉, 吴江, 杨汝震, 李文才, 董德光, 吕锁森, 吴, 张庆良, 曹, 白元鸣, 李甫春, 叶蓬, 杜鹏, 杜奎, 尹培玺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>来宝刚</mainName>
    <names>[曹振贤, 杨志, 西门豹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨丽花</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 郑元, 吕布, 杨子葳, 凤凰, 狄珊, 杨好艺, 韩信, 王伯, ，, 梁山伯, 唐, 林, 陈清海, 薛, 孙玉郎, 何凤珠, 安安, 王文英, 史艳文, 曹玉, 李亚仙, 邱锦祥, 正声天, 杨家, 杨馥菱, 万家欢, 李靖, 康熙, 卖油郎, 王惠月, 陈三五, 张帝找, 孙膑, 曲之乔, 贾宝玉, 雷峰塔, 巢, 唐伯虎点, 陈清华, 杨丽花, 马歌, 张生, 陆文龙, 朱洪武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨云风</mainName>
    <names>[杨云风, 贾培之, 成, 马踏, 邓小平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨企雯</mainName>
    <names>[严秀英, 王凤英, 刘金定, 陈翠娥, 张弛, 沈阿焕, 杨企雯, 周翠珍, 杜丽娘, 江燕燕]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨兆利</mainName>
    <names>[杨兆利]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨凤兰</mainName>
    <names>[杨凤兰, 李正敏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨华生</mainName>
    <names>[张樵侬, 张超, 郭沫若, 杨宝康, 曲协, 杨华生, 田汉, 王汝刚, 鲍乐乐, 杨益萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨博森</mainName>
    <names>[崔馨月, 费玉策, 张胤德, 法门寺, 李和曾, 孟繁竹, 杨东虎, 裘, 马子强, 王博, 屈己, 于荣光, 张志献, 汪, 杨燕毅, 刘嘉欣, 孙岳, 杨博森, 李和, 汪本贞, 刘秀荣, 曹, 裘盛戎, 汪二老]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨双赫</mainName>
    <names>[杨双赫, 杨派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨天笑</mainName>
    <names>[王啸天, 滑稽, 杨梅继承, 徐天麟, 杨, 赵宝山, 徐长福, 徐笑亭, 袁一灵, 杨天笑]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨好</mainName>
    <names>[杨好]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨孝亭</mainName>
    <names>[沈三元, 杨宝忠, 杨毓麟, 贾立川, 王瑶卿, 杨宝森, 杨孝亭, 董魁荣, 荣蝶, 杨桂云, 吴连奎, 马旦, 刘五毓, 刘赶三, 张春彦, 朱氏, 赵仙舫, 杨宝义]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨孝芳</mainName>
    <names>[杨孝芳, 杨宝森]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨宝忠</mainName>
    <names>[杨宝忠, 王瑞芝, 金福, 杭子, 陈秀华, 杨宝森, 李慕良, 梅兰芳, 杨派, 杨小朵, 梅巧玲, 马连良, 杨, 钟德, 王鹤文, 万瑞兴, 张春彦, 许德义, 曹, 杨朵仙, 时杨, 乐理, 黄金陆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨宝森</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 俞振庭, 谭富英, 汪正华, 舒展, 陈秀华, 梁庆云, 汪派, 鲍吉祥, 荀慧生, 刘秀, 张伯驹, 谭, 桑园, 诸葛亮, 曲中有直, 叶蓬, 朱云鹏, 杨宝忠, 杨贵庆, 杨延昭, 王瑶卿, 寇准, 奚啸, 杨宝森, 伍子胥, 杨孝亭, 杨派, 王凤卿, 蒋慕萍, 马长礼, 杨桂云, 马连良, 马旦, 王伯党, 归韵, 程正泰, 李鸣盛, 平和, 杨家将, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨小楼</mainName>
    <names>[俞振庭, 法门寺, 李少春, 谭氏, 周瑞安, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 双胜, 俞振, 杨万青, 荀慧生, 张淇林, 俞菊, 隆寿, 杨月, 高庆奎, 小杨, 王楞仙, 傅得, 杨小楼, 沈华轩, 李万春, 陈德霖, 郝寿臣, 陶咏, 杨月楼, 孙毓堃, 谭鑫, 俞菊笙, 王瑶卿, 四郎, 杨派, 王福寿, 杨真传, 姚增禄, 武生传, 杨, 黄润甫, 王金璐, 武生, 厉慧良, 杨二喜, 刘宗杨, 谭鑫培, 俞氏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨少华</mainName>
    <names>[杨少华, 杨议, 马志明, 杨光, 赵伟洲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨建忠</mainName>
    <names>[唐韵笙, 高盛麟, 徐策, 刘奎童, 陈鹤峰, 董俊峰, 刘, 孟少, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 杨建忠, 李如春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨志淳</mainName>
    <names>[杨五六, 杨志淳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨明玉</mainName>
    <names>[成龙, 王奕訢, 双奎, 嵇永林, 和春, 盛成, 杨三, 李二, 杨明玉, 明玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨春霞</mainName>
    <names>[杨春霞, 张派, 四郎, 杨畹农, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨曼华</mainName>
    <names>[张三, 刘, 杨曼华, 刘派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨沔</mainName>
    <names>[杨沔, 程砚秋, 杨, 王雅文, 李恩璞, 温天, 阎珑, 钟荣, 胡颖欣, 陈学欣, 孙长军, 程派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨满元</mainName>
    <names>[唐, 秦腔, 杨满元]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨玉华</mainName>
    <names>[夏百揆, 陈鹤峰, 徐明霞, 刘荣升, 尚, 梅兰芳, 戴美琴, 杨至芳, 刘奎官, 杨正华, 梅氏, 周慧如, 薄情郎, 陈伟国, 杨府, 宋江, 荀, 桂华, 孙盛辅, 李十娘, 王婉华, 刘雪涛, 刘奎童, 李蔷华, 刘斌昆, 四郎, 张杲, 宦桂珠, 马宏良, 郭玉昆, 孔雀东南, 徐雅玲, 刘薇, 王小鸾, 马, 李春芳, 赵荣琛, 杨九华, 梁敏通, 杨菊萍, 刘敏霞, 朱世慧, 罗成, 文耀华, 宦, 杨明, 吕志明, 张文华, 叶盛茂, 邹礼姜, 赵晓岚, 舒建楚, 杨家班, 常向, 王家熙, 俞振飞, 贺玉钦, 杨玉华, 胡, 张憨生, 王明仙, 王泰祺, 汪永龙, 马博敏, 周慧, 陆文龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨瑞亭</mainName>
    <names>[杨瑞亭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨畹农</mainName>
    <names>[四人帮, 胡同, 周振芳, 李师善, 梅剧进, 谢雅柳, 杨春霞, 徐兰沅, 梅派, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 杨畹, 李炳淑, 王少卿, 张伯驹, 杨, 梅宅, 倪秋萍, 萧太, 徐叔明, 胡芝凤, 沈小梅, 向杨]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨盛春</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 杨铁虎, 谭富英, 叶盛章, 杨少春, 梅兰芳, 尚, 荀慧生, 叶盛兰, 盛春, 于太平, 杨铁柱, 叶盛长, 杨铁珠, 叶春善, 杨隆寿, 孙悟空, 杨铁嗣, 王连, 安天, 钱晓峰, 盛, 张君秋, 马连良, 韩文亭, 韩氏故, 裘盛戎, 杨盛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨秋玲</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 李少春, 赵桐珊, 王瑶卿, 梅派, 梅兰芳, 牛郎, 胡, 巢, 孔雀东南, 杨门女, 张复, 穆桂英, 王凤朝, 宇宙锋, 杨秋玲, 李广]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨秋雯</mainName>
    <names>[吴彩霞, 贾元妃, 唐韵笙, 雷峰, 王玉兰, 王瑶卿, 柏俊, 施桂林, 曹艺斌, 周信芳, 闻子芳, 李萍, 杨秋雯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨红丽</mainName>
    <names>[杨红丽, 张鸣琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨舒雯</mainName>
    <names>[白玉兰, 杨舒雯, 李隆基, 诸葛亮, 朱秉谦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨荣斌</mainName>
    <names>[唐韵笙, 徐元珊, 王, 樊珊, 王雪芳, 薛丁山, 朱鸿声, 尚小云, 李卜春, 梅兰芳, 梁山, 荀慧生, 李庆春, 赵斌, 赵王, 陆振英, 卢邦彦, 高宝贤, 高庆奎, 诸葛亮, 马永涵, 高永秋, 李甫春, 杨春等, 王泽民, 李万春, 徐兰源, 张仪, 雷振东, 奚啸伯, 李小春, 梁益鸣, 梅葆玖, 薛倚, 金, 吴光辉, 陈少五, 奚啸, 杨宝森, 唐荣昌, 陈少, 李盛藻, 屈原, 王凤卿, 张卫东, 张君秋, 蒙呼和浩特, 杨荣斌, 张连福, 杨永俊, 马, 李宝树, 钟离, 徐东明, 杨俊生, 梁一鸣, 张忠义, 王元赞, 陶麟, 赵玉民]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨荣楼</mainName>
    <names>[曾搭, 杨荣楼, 梅兰, 姜铁麟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨荣环</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 于连泉, 胡长泰, 唐韵笙, 梅派甜润, 谭富英, 奚啸伯, 杨健为, 杨宝森, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 李凌枫, 马连良, 尚派, 宇宙锋, 杨毛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨菊萍</mainName>
    <names>[郭玉琨, 杨菊萍, 杨玉华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨蒲生</mainName>
    <names>[杨蒲生, 苏武, 穆杨, 李, 刘长瑜, 刘秀荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨观复</mainName>
    <names>[石筱英, 杨乃武, 杨观复]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨觉民</mainName>
    <names>[吕布, 杨觉民, 孙玉兰, 陶乐, 洪亮, 韩信, 周仁, 秦腔, 杨觉, 赵家, 赵, 熊友兰, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨连贵</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 杨宗保, 季小兰, 丁至云, 罗成, 叶少兰, 马少, 叶像叶, 张浩一角, 宇宙锋, 葛少林, 文墨书生, 刘雪涛, 李慧娘, 袁青云, 杨乃, 四郎, 孔雀东南, 李耕涛, 杨连贵, 姜派, 马, 彭, 黄荣俊, 程正泰, 李莉, 梁桂亭, 连昌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨金凤</mainName>
    <names>[杨金凤, 叶子, 郝彩凤, 马友仙, 秦腔, 秦腔旦, 段林菊, 安安]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨金声</mainName>
    <names>[杨金声, 杨振华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨钰海</mainName>
    <names>[魏文亮, 杨钰海, 王谦祥, 苏文茂, 李]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨隆寿</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 陈塘, 范宝亭, 武老生, 双奎, 刘吉庆, 唐玉喜, 董凤岩, 杨氏手, 蔡荣贵, 武净, 王阿巧, 茹莱卿, 杨春甫, 张增明, 张淇林, 郭春翠, 孙杨, 陈寿峰, 张长保, 程春德, 迟遇泉, 姚阿奔, 谭小培, 朱玉龙, 叶春善, 张云亭, 沈景丞, 方松龄, 杨隆寿, 杨小楼, 孙春泉, 沈易成, 阎岚秋, 袁大奎, 汪大升, 冯春和, 李永泉, 俞菊笙, 郭际湘, 刘长喜, 徐兰沅, 程继先, 许福雄, 李顺亭, 姚增禄, 杨双贵, 许福英, 杨, 沈铭, 罗福喜, 小福, 黄小生, 迟月亭, 王求安, 杨福元, 刘春喜, 杨长喜, 王幼卿, 武生, 杨长林, 万春, 谭鑫培, 范福泰, 朱延贵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨雅琴</mainName>
    <names>[杨雅琴, 孙淑筠, 刘派, 孙悟空, 郝艳霞, 刘派京韵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杨飞飞</mainName>
    <names>[杨八曲, 丁国滨, 金媛, 杨派, 赵春芳, 越剧, 杨飞飞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>杭子和</mainName>
    <names>[沈华轩, 阎岚秋, 杨宝忠, 刘鸿升, 李佩卿, 李五, 王, 谭富英, 杭子, 沈宝钧, 陈少霖, 杨宝森, 梅兰芳, 王凤卿, 谭派, 刘顺, 黄润甫, 王少楼, 龚云甫, 田雨, 谭鑫培, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林家声</mainName>
    <names>[邓肖兰, 叶绍德, 袁小田, 雷鸣金, 林, 李少芸, 薛觉先, 徐子郎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林建华</mainName>
    <names>[周爱玲, 郭素真, 李二嫂, 赵玉霜, 尤以, 王, 李荣华, 王志贞, 王宝保, 王宝钏, 穆桂英, 吕剧团, 吕剧, 林建华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林懋荣</mainName>
    <names>[侯梦兰, 杨宝忠, 魏莲芳, 李玉泰, 谭富英, 朗, 梅兰芳, 孟庆惠, 姜妙香, 李崇善, 孔雀东南, 岳惠玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林树森</mainName>
    <names>[徐策, 李洪, 李洪春, 李金声, 尚小云, 高亢, 梅兰芳, 宇不凡, 周信芳, 王凤卿, 荀慧生, 李桂春, 华容, 华北文武, 华南文武, 赵云, 蒲田, 王鸿寿, 孙庞斗, 红生, 王君鸿, 王益芳, 曾收, 林宝奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林玩贞</mainName>
    <names>[袁崇焕, 万山红, 李花, 莫二娘, 薛刚, 吴母, 吕后, 刘璋, 彭湃]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林秀兰</mainName>
    <names>[傅集乡, 张宝珠, 林秀兰, 帅旦, 李玲珠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林芳锦</mainName>
    <names>[于时, 梁幼侬, 杨六郎, 柯岩乡, 林芳锦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林道修</mainName>
    <names>[秦香莲, 陈烈三, 王凤梅, 陈秀明, 韩文华, 吴发风, 王秀明, 梅兰芳, 南洋, 琼剧院, 潘辉星]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林金培</mainName>
    <names>[邓元, 正明, 储金鹏, 谭富英, 黄静波, 肖英, 李玉茹, 李旭东, 邓方, 李洪春, 尚小云, 鲍吉祥, 秦腔, 李自成, 荣生平, 翁偶虹, 徐碧云, 姚雪垠, 宋德珠, 费穆, 杨宝忠, 王君衡, 花木兰, 陈少五, 王瑶卿, 孔雀东南, 程砚秋, 钮承华, 王金璐, 王小康, 李金泉, 黄佐临, 钮淮华, 张金樑, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>柳萱图</mainName>
    <names>[赵景深, 殷震贤, 项]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>柳青</mainName>
    <names>[张月, 王金樱, 梁山伯, 柳青, 杨丽花, 孙膑, 叶青, 刘盈]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>栗桂莲</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有桂月樵的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>桑殿杰</mainName>
    <names>[桑自修, 段德, 苏, 贺后骂, 王文慧, 桑建修, 桑殿杰, 胡玉芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁一鸣</mainName>
    <names>[况钟, 岳飞, 梁, 陈胜, 王长林, 谭富英, 李玉茹, 田汉, 汪派, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 姜妙香, 李自成, 刘派, 杨小楼, 刘彦昌, 詹天, 林树森, 郝寿臣, 周恩来, 梁海涛, 寇准, 王凤卿, 张春彦, 梁一鸣, 曹操]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁国英</mainName>
    <names>[梁国英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁小鸾</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 梁小鸾, 奚啸伯, 谭富英, 雷峰, 梁益鸣, 王瑶卿, 梅派, 杨宝森, 田汉, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 毛, 管绍华, 王派, 诸茹香, 李紫贵, 李宗义]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁庆云</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 朱云鹏, 杨宝忠, 陆, （, 孟广享, 罗惠兰, 汪正华, 李蔷华, 杨宝森, 梁庆云, 杨派, 蒋慕萍, 鲍吉祥, 梁氏, 杨生前, 杨, 杨派戏, 赵荣琛, 程正泰, 李鸣盛, 琴谱, 郭少衡, 吴大少, 曹, 叶蓬, 丁存坤, 吴熹笙, 曲曲谱, 黄金陆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁慧超</mainName>
    <names>[李兰亭, 梁慧超, 李先念]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁汉威</mainName>
    <names>[陈好逑, 吴, 梁汉威, 尹飞燕]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁益鸣</mainName>
    <names>[梁大龙, 苏武, 马连良, 梁益鸣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁秀娟</mainName>
    <names>[马旦戏, 王蕙芳, 王盛如, 马祥麟, 王魁, 李洪春, 张彩林, 梁氏, 文武昆, 许仙, 梁秀娟, 阎岚秋, 诸位, 苏连汉, 雷峰, 梁雯娟, 云门下, 雷峰塔, 王宝钏, 白其龙, 周, 李玉龙, 孟丽君]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁秀秀</mainName>
    <names>[胡, 秦香莲, 梁秀秀]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁训益</mainName>
    <names>[魏海敏, 梁训益, 尚小云, 王振祖, 徐露]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梁醒波</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 波, 白雪, 谭兰卿, 高平, 梁醒波, ，, 马师, 梁广才, 南洋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梅兰珍</mainName>
    <names>[周, 文华, 梅兰珍, 叶剑英, 梅派, 王彬彬, 武进, 华丽多姿, 毛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梅兰芳</mainName>
    <names>[李湘君, 韩淑华, 李玉茹, 梅门, 李元芳, 吴若兰, 张春秋, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 徐再蓉, 王素琴, 荀慧生, 张曼玲, 李砚秀, 谢虹雯, 杨畹侬, 徐东来, 贾世珍, 毛剑秋, 朱, 叶春善, 杨隆寿, 宇宙锋, 杨秋玲, 喻志清, 张世孝, 邹慧兰, 李蔷华, 张南云, 红线女, 南铁生, 张君秋, 曹慧麟, 王佩瑜, 高华, 毕谷云, 李慧芳, 张志英, 李玉芙, 穆桂英, 许守义, 朱小霞, 吴菱仙, 汪剑耘, 班主叶, 王明华, 马小曼, 陈伯华, 舒昌玉, 谢黛琳, 沈小梅, 杨荣环, 李斐叔, 刘肖梅, 陈永玲, 焦鸿英, 明志, 胡芝风, 王蕙芳, 梅兰, 魏莲芳, 任颖华, 黄世恩, 杨玉娟, 陈正薇, 于素秋, 范玉媛, 白玉薇, 李玉芝, 毛世, 尚小云, 杨维君, 李毓芳, 李燕香, 杨慧敏, 唐富尧, 李丽, 李国粹, 胡蝶, 李世芳, 李吟香, 刘元彤, 赵文漪, 胡漱芳, 谦逊, 卢燕, 李香匀, 梁小鸾, 陈德霖, 王熙春, 郭建英, 马金凤, 李金鸿, 杜近芳, 张丽娟, 梅葆玖, 李桂云, 罗惠兰, 张淑娴, 赵慧娟, 华慧, 章遏云, 李薇华, 崔秀茹, 叶春, 李慧琴, 王慧萍, 朱素云, 梁红玉, 陈书舫, 刘淑华, 李碧慧, 沈曼华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梅绍武</mainName>
    <names>[纳博科夫, 梅绍武, 约卡伊·莫尔, 梅卫, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梅葆玖</mainName>
    <names>[梅兰, 梅葆玖, 穆桂英, 王幼卿, 林肯, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梅葆玥</mainName>
    <names>[梅饰, 马少波, 陈秀华, 梅大师, 张学良, 梅兰芳, 江新蓉, 崔护, 蒋纬国, 姜妙香, 梅剧团, 欧阳予, 张学敏, 杨宝忠, 古斯塔夫, 洪亮, 毛遂, 陈立夫, 梅葆玖, 四郎, 高亢, 杨派, 毛, 张君秋, 辜振甫, 李世英, 李桂芬, 周, 马连良, 王少楼, 穆桂英, 刘鸿声, 吉祥, 曹, 梅葆玥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梅雨田</mainName>
    <names>[陈出新, 谭派, 李春泉, 胡琴, 梅巧玲, 李五, 孙佐臣, 谭鑫, 孙云锦, 梅雨田, 贾祥瑞, 梅兰芳, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>樊景泰</mainName>
    <names>[汪桂芬, 樊景泰, 樊三, 胡琴, 樊得玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>樊金奎</mainName>
    <names>[胡琴, 琴, 樊金奎, 樊元吉, 樊金, 朱文英, 樊顺福]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>武丽娟</mainName>
    <names>[秋香, 朱顺登, 马旦, 梁山伯, 穆桂英, 赵, 林黛玉, 祝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>武俊英</mainName>
    <names>[蒲剧, 武俊, 王苗苗, 苏三, 程小荣, 武俊英, 蒲剧团, 菊兰, 项, 杨燕燕, 吉有芳, 李小芳, 王艺华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>武广江</mainName>
    <names>[李经文, 姚尚英, 周啸天, 程正泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>武正豪</mainName>
    <names>[杨宝忠, 武汉京, 慕名, 杨宝森, 呼宝忠, 杨大爷, 杨派, 周信芳, 喻子祥, 蒋慕萍, 谢幕, 胡琴, 呼宝森, 武, 宝忠, 杨, 单变, 武正豪, 杭, 台竟不克, 宝森, 杨派十]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>武正霜</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>武筱凤</mainName>
    <names>[贾玉珍, 旭东, 王贵, 张羽煮, 袁樵, 马麟童, 周筱芳, 何叫天, 李神童, 杨占魁, 洪深, 王月英, 梁山伯, 陈翠娥, 马秀英, 黄秀兰, 陈杏元, 东新, 祝, 王九林, 吴汉, 张, 师承武, 金枝玉叶, 武旭东, 王兰英, 冯秀清, 李香香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>段丽君</mainName>
    <names>[王素砚, 钟离春, 梁庆云, 王少泉, 孙雁鹏, 诸葛亮, 冯远江, 张燕, 华由汉, 张燕华, 黄素, 秋版, 黄月, 蒋叔岩, 段丽君, 穆桂英, 张君, 武生, 其夫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>殷元和</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>殷宝忠</mainName>
    <names>[殷宝忠, 李文启, 刘鸿升, 陈富康, 焦珺萍, 李玉龙学, 富连成, 李文飞, 四郎, 元德, 桂森, 张文林, 红云岗, 富英, 杭汉, 殷斌, 文林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>殷文硕</mainName>
    <names>[刘宝瑞, 师承, 曲艺纵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有殷斌奎的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>殷震贤</mainName>
    <names>[俞擞, 双璧, 殷震贤, 俞振飞, 潘岳, 梅兰芳, 殷乔醋, 汤致祥, 殷, 殷笑]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毕小洋</mainName>
    <names>[毕小洋, 王玉敏, 杨韵青, 杨门女, 赵葆秀, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毕彦涛</mainName>
    <names>[毕彦涛, 南雍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毕春芳</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 金艳芳, 唐伯虎, 杨文蔚, 卖油郎, 邢竹琴, 徐天红, 毕春芳, 秋实皆, 越艺社, 许仙, 周文宾, 王金龙, 越剧团, 王老虎, 尹, 桂芳, 王文娟, 范瑞娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毕杨</mainName>
    <names>[杨门女, 文成, 李逵, 赵葆秀, 王玉敏, 杨韵青, 王晶华, 毕杨]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毕高修</mainName>
    <names>[四人帮, 赵燕侠, 侯喜瑞, 高修, 陈真治, 叶先生, 荣宝, 毕高修, 张尧, 罗成, 刘传启, 杜富隆, 韩同仁, 郝仕鹏, 叶盛兰, 杨柳青, 叶像叶, 葛少林, 李荣安, ，籍贯, 黄定, 为史筱峰, 盛海宁, 张建强, 姚玉刚, 毕, 习叶派, 四郎, 李玉书, 温如华, 班武生, 杜滋龄, 马连良, 马永安, 董孟豪, 江世玉, 梁桂亭, 金喜, 陈盛泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毛世来</mainName>
    <names>[马思远, 毛庆, 赵砚奎, 吴宗佑, 鄂吕弓, 毛世, 陈母, 文武兼, 李洪春, 梅兰芳, 陈喜兴, 毛盛荣, 赵师, 王富刚, 李世芳, 刘元彤, 郝素玉, 何佩华, 朱斌仙, 宋德珠, 荀慧, 王连, 李万春, 艾世, 张世孝, 黄榆公社, 于鸿宾, 辛安驿, 薛金莲, 张君秋, 习小生, 王继珠, 习武生, 王玉蓉, 和平京, 郎喜润, 李万, 毛饰, 刘喜益]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毛佩卿</mainName>
    <names>[宁波越, 毛佩卿, 梁祝哀, 林黛英, 毛秀娟, 姚水娟, 张伟忠, 越剧团, 东乡灵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毛兰花</mainName>
    <names>[徐艳琴, 马金凤, 朱振家, 田运显, 南梆子, 谢世, 许贵云, 汤兰香, 张同庆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>毛剑鹏</mainName>
    <names>[唐, 唐骏骐, 毛剑鹏, 曾特, 张文祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>江世玉</mainName>
    <names>[江世玉, 茹富兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>江其虎</mainName>
    <names>[张协状, 李尔, 江其虎, 罗成, 梅兰芳, 李德彬, 江世玉, 叶少兰, 林肯, 鲁迅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>江新蓉</mainName>
    <names>[王芸芳, 程砚秋, 赵华, 沈玉才, 周恩来, 马少波, 马昭仪, 江新蓉, 江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汤乃秋</mainName>
    <names>[陈绿波, 汤乃安, 汤乃秋, 朱梅君, 朱一鸣, 陈忠英, 秋江, 秦香, 程上之]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汤伯玉</mainName>
    <names>[法门寺, 贾桂, 何文基, 贺后骂, 杨须生, 张文涓, 汤伯玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汤庆言</mainName>
    <names>[李天斗, 鲁剧院]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汤明亮</mainName>
    <names>[汤明亮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汤玉英</mainName>
    <names>[汤玉英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汤金城</mainName>
    <names>[绪德贵, 汤瞎子, 韩信, 习口技, 朱阔泉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪世瑜</mainName>
    <names>[周传瑛, 唐明皇, 国风昆, 赵文清, 汪世瑜, 张继华, 韩琦仲, 丰采]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪传钤</mainName>
    <names>[张铭荣, 周遇吉, 孙二娘, 张翼鹏, 安天, 汪传钤, 苏, 武松, 王芝泉, 鲁智深, 孙耳旁, 刘利华, 张千, 吴义生, 王益芳, 武功, 班昆, 孙悟空]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪保琦</mainName>
    <names>[郭全宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪子良</mainName>
    <names>[陈文荣, 沈宝钧, 孙文秀, 子良, 陈文兴, 张继五, 张庆云, 陈秀林, 曹文卿, 习净, 汪, 汪子良, 张元清, 秦启荣, 刘玉如, 刘国栋, 周子厚, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪庆元</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 汪庆元, 白激越, 唐, 王玉海, 冯世奎, 华容, 毕生, 李逵, 李刚毅, 唐派红, 包龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪明荃</mainName>
    <names>[汪明荃]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪景寿</mainName>
    <names>[汪景寿, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪正华</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 杨家, 范, 杨称赞, 唐明皇, 汪正华, 杨宝森, 杨派, 杨派神髓, 杨六郎, 满江红, 杨派风, 伍子, 宋江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪润泉</mainName>
    <names>[李少兰, 孙竹轩, 董美堂, 叙伦, 汪润泉, 董竹轩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪玉祥</mainName>
    <names>[王盛如, 汪玉祥, 陈永玲, 汪荣汉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪芝琳</mainName>
    <names>[汪芝琳, 汪悦春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>汪荣汉</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 阎岚秋, 于连泉, 李瑞臣, 胡幼安, 艾宝良, 法门寺, 汪永德, 叶盛章, 张启洪, 汪荣汉, 于京, 孙小华, 柳国维, 黄占生, 刘长生, 孙盛武, 叶盛兰, 赵德芝, 孔新垣, 马富禄, 贾多才, 王福民, 孔祥仁, 高富远, 刘振英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈三元</mainName>
    <names>[高庆奎, 沈三元, 沈荃奎, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈三玉</mainName>
    <names>[俞振庭, 中柏之毅, 沈三玉, 王, ，, 郭世华, 李, 韦三奎, 张玉禅, 朱琴心, 钱浩梁, 焦菊隐, 武净, 唐铁林, 梅兰芳, 荀慧生, 赵凤鸣, 王金璐, 赵三凤, 袁金凯, 武生, 尚和, 贺春泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈世华</mainName>
    <names>[王玉贞, 俞振飞, 杜丽娘, 沈世华, 朱传茗, 周传瑛, 李香君, 沈月华, 周传铮, 苏浙沪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈世启</mainName>
    <names>[沈世启, 孙盛文, 张克林, 马连良, 宋国祥, 缪传先, 黄元庆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈传锐</mainName>
    <names>[东家寿, 张紫, 沈传锐, 秦琼, 沈月泉, 沈传芷]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈孝昌</mainName>
    <names>[沈孝昌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈宝桢</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 宋遇春, 苏连汉, 诸连顺, 孙毓堃, 沈玉斌, 沈宝桢, 郑星垣, 梁山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈宝钧</mainName>
    <names>[吴永明, 刘鸿升, 李五, 杭子, 沈宝钧, 沈大, 沈韵秋, 陈氏, 李奎林, 刘永顺, 汤宗成, 郝六, 蒲阿四, 汪子良, 樊三, 王景福, 何瑞林, 方秉忠, 郭德顺, 尚泽九]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈富贵</mainName>
    <names>[刘习, 蔡荣春, 谭富英, 曾聘请, 赵春瑞, 叶盛章, 沈富贵, 董凤岩, 尚小云, 苏雨卿, 黄派武生, 荀慧生, 刚毅, 王连平, 茹富兰, 曲咏春, 刘匡捷, 荣春, 毛世来]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈小梅</mainName>
    <names>[赵女, 韩玉娘, 梅派, 陈祥云, 阎少泉, 梅兰芳, 程雪娥, 虞姬, 王宝钏, 朱传茗, 穆桂英, 刘阿环, 白素贞, 宇宙锋, 沈小梅, 沈晓梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈少亭</mainName>
    <names>[沈笑亭, 田丽丽, 海燕, 范哈哈, 沈贵鑫, 马莉莉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈星培</mainName>
    <names>[李春泉, 胡琴, 沈星培, 沈六]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈玉才</mainName>
    <names>[李春泉, 沈三元, 沈玉才, 谭富英, 沈玉, 李少春, 胡琴改, 杨宝森, 尚小云, 沈星, 荀慧生, 胡宝利, 胡琴, 袁世海, 王玉蓉, 赵荣琛, 郭根森, 王晓韶, 沈福海, 王凤朝, 琴弦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈玉斌</mainName>
    <names>[张宝华, 马金涛, 宋永珍, 赵绮霞, 王长林, 巴金陵原, 沈玉斌, 朱家红, 华闻听, 宋元斌, 梅兰芳, 方立善, 荀慧生, 王永昌, 张, 文书宁, 李燕生, 玉斌, 高庆奎, 张喜鸿, 赵德勋, 刘佩永, 杨小楼, 王福来, 郝寿臣, 沈宝瑞, 诸连顺, 梁益鸣, 武旦, 华世香, 王瑶卿, 刘永贵, 松柏庵, 沈忙, 于新民, 刘继昌, 张君秋, 双亲及, 沈说, 武丑, 袁世海, 王来发, 苏敬, 武生, 李七, 简, 赵慧英, 于连泉, 张学海, 孙家壁, 沈, 李三星, 唐芝芳, 沈氏, 谭富英, 蒋, 李少春, 罗万银, 叶盛章, 孙毓敏, 荀令文, 刘景奎, 沈听罢, 孙甫亭, 王颉竹, 李世芳, 弘翔, 王晓临, 张学济, 叶红珠, 孟俊泉, 梁小鸾, 邓友梅, 苏连汉, 陈德霖, 沈玉才, 王玉让, 于永利, 周恩来, 史若虚, 李桂云, 马仲勤, 沈只得, 陈少五, 罗文奎, 姚玉芙, 郝老, 巢, 费酬劳, 罗久明, 王仲元, 马连良, 王少楼, 贺永祥, 吴仁本, 沈宝珍, 张嘉瑞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈福存</mainName>
    <names>[程联群, 吕布, 沈铁梅, 沈福, 沈福成, 马少波, 罗成, 沈福存, 尚小云, 李晓兰, 李玉和, 周渝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈福海</mainName>
    <names>[曹玉梅, 诸桂, 曹连孝, 沈玉秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈金波</mainName>
    <names>[艾世菊, 沈金, 李, 沈金波, 焦菊隐, 孔尚任, 龙元帅, 周信芳, 高庆奎, 马陵道]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈雁西</mainName>
    <names>[荀, 马诸流, 王少卿, 王瑞芝, 尤擅, 陆柏平, 沈雁西, 梅葆玖, 方小亚, 梅派, 张南云, 梅兰芳, 梅葆玥, 周信芳, 李炳淑, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沈韵秋</mainName>
    <names>[徐虹, 蔡玉良, 王华, 倪淑英, 刘芳, 沈韵秋, 刘国华, 沈希生, 丹拼夫, 金耀, 王寻子, 项丽星, 袁萍, 袁敏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>沐居容</mainName>
    <names>[杨慧玲, 希拉克, 徐艳芳, 陈正薇, 李, 杨春霞, 刘纪良, 徐叔良, 徐少安, 马长礼, 李鸣岩, 杨门女, 冯志孝, 谦逊, 马小曼, 杨秋玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>洪云艳</mainName>
    <names>[吕布, 洪云艳, 赵桐珊, 曾拜, 刘玉琴, 朱德, 薄情郎, 窦尔敦, 张飞, 王益芳, 宋月涛, 宇宙锋, 王庆海, 焦宝奎, 周恩来, 刘少奇, 杨邦俊, 王福卿, 孔雀东南, 程少余, 毛泽东, 秦香, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>洪深</mainName>
    <names>[洪深]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>洪深</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 洪深, ，, 李秀成, 法西斯, 简照南, 孟超, 夏衍, 田汉, 南洋, 赵阎, 洪, 宋教仁, 徐汇, 国民, 李同愈, 张彭, 王余杞, 周恩来, 吴伯箫, 刘西蒙, 洪达, 王亚平, 习, 洪深自, 赵少侯, 王统照]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>海连池</mainName>
    <names>[海连池]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>温宇航</mainName>
    <names>[吕布, 凤仪杯, 传马玉森, 蔡正仁, 沈世华, 于逸夫, 王泰琪, 温宇航, 张毓文, 双语昆, 汪世瑜, 张世铮, 张洵澎, 洪雪飞, 林肯, 白兔, 朱世藕, 刘国庆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>温尚全</mainName>
    <names>[晋剧武, 包拯, 陈派, 洪亮, 王盈秋, 黄忠, 须口功, 李马, 陈宛仙, 何金章]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>潘凤霞</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 梁旦, 田汉, 毛泽东, 崔莺莺, 杜丽娘, 祝英, 王凤香, 潘凤霞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>潘月红</mainName>
    <names>[朱砂痣, 玛莉, 胡, 胡大虎, 红获颁, 张胜林, 赵兰珍, 四郎, 曹, 潘月红, 潘月]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>潘璟琍</mainName>
    <names>[潘璟, 梁山伯, 黄梅戏, 文武, 潘璟琍, 王少舫, 严凤英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>焦少海</mainName>
    <names>[焦少, 焦少海, 赵佩茹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>焦菊隐</mainName>
    <names>[毕生, 柯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>焦黎</mainName>
    <names>[胡芝风, 乌龙, 王, 胡芝, 李慧娘, 李岱江, 小李, 李利宏, 王佩璜, 焦, 后台, 卢昂, 双翼翔, 吕剧团, 焦黎唱, 吕剧院, 吕剧, 林建华, 吕演唱]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>熊剑啸</mainName>
    <names>[杨绊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>熊志麟</mainName>
    <names>[熊志麟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>燕凌</mainName>
    <names>[梁谷音, 刘彦, 马金凤, 王, 李玉琴, 双剑, 苏, 燕, 阎罗殿, 俞振飞, 王芝泉, 王魁, 燕凌, 李炳淑, 胡琴, 刘厚生, 穆桂英, 常香玉, 刘彦昌, 郭汉城]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>燕守平</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 赵燕侠, 杨宝忠, 王瑞芝, 沈玉斌, 沈玉秋, 杨春霞, 谭元寿, 徐兰沅, 李慕良, 关占奎, 张君秋, 马长礼, 胡琴, 胡交响, 马连良, 燕守平, 马小曼, 汪本贞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>爱新觉罗·溥侗</mainName>
    <names>[黄盖, 徐小香, 王又是, 王明芳, 钱金福, 唐, 张学良, 梅兰芳, 白满托, 谭派, 张伯驹, 谭大王, 叶仰曦, 李奇三角, 马踏, 鲁肃, 吴, 李后主, 王楞仙, 王楞, 李万春, 陈老夫子, 陈彦衡, 师罗, 陈德霖, 袁世凯, 陈老夫, 黄三, 蒋干, 李顺亭, 袁克文, 赵宠, 余玉琴, 向姚, 黄润甫, 罗致, 曹操, 赵逸叟, 李桂枝, 谭鑫培, 曹孟德, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>牛子厚</mainName>
    <names>[沈玉昆, 叶总其成, 梅兰, 沈, 叶家, 谭富英, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 唐宗成, 叶春善, 徐世昌, 叶回京, 富连成, 梅改, 苏雨卿, 牛, 牛子厚, 梅喜群, 马连良, 凌云寺, 康乐, 叶]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>牛得草</mainName>
    <names>[于谐, 李同宾, 李, 朱得糠, 李小顺, 卓别林, 李春芳, 张古董, 朱, 李老]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>牛淑贤</mainName>
    <names>[陈素真, 陈素, 韩素芹, 宋淑云, 桑振君, 牛受荀, 舒展, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 王宫·梳妆, 毛, 荀慧生, 红珊, 周, 郭沫若, 牛淑贤, 宇宙锋, 梁秋燕]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>狄江</mainName>
    <names>[王景明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王世续</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 王琴侬, 梅兰, 李世济, 曹心泉, 陈少霖, 王喜秀, 王瑶卿, 寇准, 陈秀华, 王世续, 张盛禄, 梅兰芳, 陈道安, 王凤卿, 罗亮生, 荀慧生, 谭派, 李白, 林润, 许翰英, 张连福, 刘曾复, 韩梁, 雷喜福, 穆桂英, 李适可, 徐碧云, 刘砚芳, 吴, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王世臣</mainName>
    <names>[马三立, 马褂, 孙宝才, 王, 李鸣岐, 闫笑儒, 张寿臣, 赵玉贵, 赵世忠, 张杰尧, 陈毅元, 刘掌柜, 侯, 赵得亮, 王长友, 侯宝林, 孟祥光, 刘宝瑞, 陈, 陈雨亭, 戴少, 张伯扬, 谭凤元, 郭启儒, 王长, 高德明, 王世臣, 马季, 郭荣启, 郭, 三位, 马大龙, 刘洪沂, 赵, 罗荣寿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王世霞</mainName>
    <names>[阎世善, 张志勇, 康健, 仲仁, 张春孝, 谭富英, 奚啸伯, 丁至云, 王紫苓, 王瑶卿, 王丽卿, 杨宝森, 李丽, 茹富兰, 李世芳, 朱玉良, 王世霞, 姬鹏, 贾德才, 王世侠, 徐东明, 杨长喜, 厉慧良, 李七]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王东红</mainName>
    <names>[王东红, 王美玲, 李新花]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王九龄</mainName>
    <names>[舒春航, 王, 张二奎, 王玉芳, 荣斋, 王朗, 汪氏, 王九龄, 马旦, 王荣, 谭鑫培, 叶中]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王书龙</mainName>
    <names>[田来顺, 王书龙, 王, 文华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王亨恺</mainName>
    <names>[俞振飞, 王亨恺, 陈, 李宝童, 张继青]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王仲华</mainName>
    <names>[罗焕跪, 王乃奎, 李家玉, 仲华, 杨凡, 王仲华, 常香玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王佩臣</mainName>
    <names>[王, 刘伶, 王佩臣, 靳遏云, 朱买臣, 靳, 王二姐, 诸葛亮, 姚雪芬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王保易</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 刘派, 刘毓, 王保易]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王元禧</mainName>
    <names>[王元禧, 王蕙芳, 王葵芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王元纲</mainName>
    <names>[王连平, 王元纲, 孙盛云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王元英</mainName>
    <names>[王连平, 王元英, 郝喜伦, 刘喜益, 苏富恩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王元赞</mainName>
    <names>[王连平, 李元瑞, 张连福, 王英华, 白婉华, 李阁华, 刘盛通, 易名, 张春华, 王元赞, 王小辫, 余京, 杨元才]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王克图</mainName>
    <names>[于玉兰, 王克图, 张永和, 吴陆君, 李金棠, 周金福, 周庆麟, 王克, 吴三泉, 陆光]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王兰英</mainName>
    <names>[刘平鸽, 谢瑶环, 孟芙蓉, 夏兰英, 薛燕, 杨旻华, 计丽静, 沈静兰, 罗氏, 王派, 戚月华, 杨若萍, 徐芳, 李菊, 张静, 崔莺莺, 陈鹰, 袁嘉兰, 郑燕萍, 王兰, 陈云霞, 花腔奇特, 陈翠娥, 肖琴, 缪秀, 顾蓓莉, 曹雅琴, 徐兰英, 倪同芳, 张素贞, 张琴芳, 窦国英, 王兰英, 梁祝, 苏小娥, 徐伟芳, 陆惠华, 董云华, 孟丽君]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王凤卿</mainName>
    <names>[华容, 贾丽川, 王则昭, 刘曾复, 陈春, 王瑶卿, 郭仲衡, 李顺亭, 汪派, 梅兰芳, 王凤卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王劼竹</mainName>
    <names>[王丙锋, 王劼竹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王升儿</mainName>
    <names>[王升儿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王又宸</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 许配, 侯喜瑞, 曾于晚, 王夫人, 王又宸, 王, 王宝臣, 李老亲, 法门寺, 王士英, 杨老板, 谭氏, 尚小云, 谭派, 荀慧生, 姜妙香, 王三爷, 谭, 李寿山, 诸葛亮, 杨小楼, 谭翠珍, 胡同, 高亭, 王与其, 李, 谭鑫, 王泉奎, 谭配, 谭腔, 四郎, 待大夫, 章遏云, 张君秋, 袁世海, 大夫, 陈盛荪, 武生, 谭鑫培, 董大夫, 刘景然, 奚氏, 茹富蕙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王双庆</mainName>
    <names>[周柏春, 王双庆, 姚慕双]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王双柏</mainName>
    <names>[王伯伯, 王双柏, 黄三, 周柏春, 姚慕双]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王喜禄</mainName>
    <names>[王喜禄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王喜秀</mainName>
    <names>[师兄文武, 法门寺, 沙世鑫, 赵春瑞, 沈富贵, 王喜秀, 王月, 吴盛珠, 须生, 金丝红, 李盛藻, 罗燕臣, 谭富, 程富, 罗得, 桑园, 刘世勋, 叶春善]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王声</mainName>
    <names>[郑文喜, 王声]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王多芬</mainName>
    <names>[朱凤桐, 李多奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王奕戈</mainName>
    <names>[阎惠昌, 孔庆珠, 王晓燕, 张派, 刘, 梅兰芳, 安国, 王奕戈, 王致和, 王永吉, 王影侠, 阎桂祥, 艾美君, 杨秋玲, 蔡英莲, 四郎, 温如华, 董翠娜, 穆桂英, 高伟春, 彭家鹏, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王好强</mainName>
    <names>[王好强, 杨凡, 曲咏春, 刘福生, 马玉璋, 吕锁森]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王婉华</mainName>
    <names>[万晓慧, 王, 王婉华, 李瑞环, 金碧艳, 陈鹤峰, 张派, 赵群, 张君秋, 刘玉琴, 刘薇, 李慧芳, 王玉蓉, 熊明霞, 姜鸿奎, 张君, 陈伯华, 秦香, 张慧芳, 杨菊萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王子江</mainName>
    <names>[苏连汉, 王长林, 王福山, 钱荣顺, 刘维秀, 赵荣鹏, 王元纲, 郭敬安, 王子江, 王德忠, 夏韵龙, 王松年]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王学义</mainName>
    <names>[王, 孙宝才, 赵霭如, 曲协, 刘司昌, 王文安, 尚小云, 孙玉奎, 赵振铎, 汪宝琦, 诸葛亮, 李家衡, 侯宝林, 贾振良, 李增瑞, 马中骥, 周恩来, 李, 殷培田, 韩云飞, 王学义, 张长, 康友纯, 于俊波, 于连仲, 廉春明, 经罗, 梁厚民, 荣寿, 史文惠, 孙宝, 毛泽东, 刘德智]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王安奎</mainName>
    <names>[王安奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王宝童</mainName>
    <names>[王, 马, 王宝童, 马敬, 王宝, 侯宝林, 马敬伯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王宪章</mainName>
    <names>[王宪章]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王家熙</mainName>
    <names>[马连良, 李玉茹, 王家熙, 张南云, 俞振飞, 杨宝森, 俞振, 裘盛戎, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王少卿</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 黄天麟, 胡有所, 沈玉才, 孙佐臣, 胡琴筒, 曹心泉, 王瑶卿, 徐兰沅, 梅派, 梅兰芳, 王凤卿, 鲍吉祥, 王实贵, 姜妙香, 胡, 梅腔, 胡琴, 王少卿, 习胡琴, 韩恩华, 倪秋萍, 王幼卿, 贾洪林, 赵, 王派琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王少媛</mainName>
    <names>[杨门女, 王少媛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王少楼</mainName>
    <names>[王顺, 谭孝, 李鸣玉, 陈彦衡, 吴幻荪, 李洪春, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 安云武, 荀慧生, 赵世璞, 李崇善, 程砚秋, 王毓, 王少楼, 雷喜福, 苏少卿, 梅宅, 文武昆, 陈鸿寿, 张学津, 文武, 王明华, 徐筱仃, 李宝春, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王少舫</mainName>
    <names>[丁永泉, 包拯, 梁山伯, 黄梅戏, 潘璟琍, 王少舫, 韩宝英, 丁老六, 潘泽海]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王巧云</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 王巧云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王平</mainName>
    <names>[郑健, 王平, 李伯祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王庾生</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 吴铁庵, 曾连载, 张英杰, 王, 丁至云, 李相心, 奚啸伯, 王庾生, 王一生, 谭氏, 吴素秋, 程继先, 田桂凤, 杨宝森, 尚小云, 曹艺斌, 谭亲授, 李英斌, 崔喜云, 吴联奎, 冯黑灯, 李宗义, 徐东明, 尚和玉, 马艳云, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培, 谭心得, 杨菊秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王德斋</mainName>
    <names>[杨纪庄, 王德斋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王志廉</mainName>
    <names>[王志廉, 于1959年, 王硕, 宋昊宇, 穆宇, 王泉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王志怡</mainName>
    <names>[李胜素, 梅, 韩冬柏, 胡文阁, 邓敏, 正式拜, 梅派, 盖玉亭, 罗玉萍, 李门, 董圆圆, 梅兰芳, 秋唱腔, 钱宝森, 张晶, 谭娜, 张君秋, 班世超, 樊富顺, 刘元彤, 穆桂英, 张君, 苏盛琴, 王幼卿, 郭金光, 李超, 许姬传, 李洁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王志涛</mainName>
    <names>[王志涛, 杨海荃]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王怀卿</mainName>
    <names>[王怀卿, 王蕙芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王惠玉</mainName>
    <names>[王瑶卿, 臧岚光, 王惠玉, 金碧艳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王敬乐</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 胡进, 秦剧, 董威, 王敬乐, 卢忠良, 牛贵, 姚氏, 梁平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王文慧</mainName>
    <names>[王文慧, 马金凤, 杨开慧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王文源</mainName>
    <names>[王文源]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王文玉</mainName>
    <names>[田立禾, 陆文庆, 魏文亮, 徐永刚, 王文玉, 刘文亨, 张振圻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王文鹏</mainName>
    <names>[石大喜, 王, 刘金荣, 王文鹏, 刘玉润, 王一, 秦腔, 凡, 辕门, 胡琴, 王曾于, 于唱, 赖子, 诸葛亮, 班须生, 陈镜民]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王新农</mainName>
    <names>[杨优长, 李铁林, 王琴生, 郭建光, 王新农, 曹, 武正豪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王无能</mainName>
    <names>[滑稽, 马永贞, 痛哭亡夫, 王, 双簧, 王无能, 于堂会, 苏州寡妇, 江笑笑, 胡琴, 马甲滑稽, 杨华, 王念祖, 王以, 裴, 范哈哈]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王晓临</mainName>
    <names>[赵绮霞, 王梦云, 李金鸿, 李多奎, 徐母骂, 王瑶卿, 王晶华, 孙甫亭, 荀慧生, 谢道清, 岳母, 王玉敏, 王晓临, 李金泉, 赵德勋, 曹, 韩英娘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王景明</mainName>
    <names>[孙有道, 杨三姐, 刘罗锅, 张嘎, 王少, 胡半疯, 吴省兰, 王景, 王景明, 李忆兰, 纪晓岚, 赵小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王晶华</mainName>
    <names>[王玉璞, 孟母, 徐母骂, 郭自勤, 孙甫亭, 王威良, 杨门女, 陈雨斌, 王玉敏, 岳母, 师靳斌, 李金泉, 曹, 徐少琪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王月芳</mainName>
    <names>[王月芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王柏荫</mainName>
    <names>[周玉泉, 蒋调, 蒋, 苏似荫, 李, 汪佳雨, 张君谋, 高美玲, 周（玉泉, 蒋月泉, 张云亭, 王柏荫, 张维桢, 王孝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王树芳</mainName>
    <names>[王玉敏, 岳母, 王树芳, 李金泉, 刘曾复, 李少春, 孙甫亭, 赵荣琛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王桂山</mainName>
    <names>[劝夫, 王, 王凤仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王梦云</mainName>
    <names>[谭嗣, 王梦云, 徐少祺, 李多奎, 李盛泉, 王玉敏, 岳母, 徐母骂, 刘斌昆, 李金泉, 洪母骂, 曹, 孙甫亭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王楞仙</mainName>
    <names>[王世荣, 徐小香, 王, 金仲仁, 周氏, 王立, 谭鑫, 陆杏林, 王松齡, 荀慧, 王楞仙, 双绝, 田不为]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王正屏</mainName>
    <names>[包拯, 江南活, 李小春, 周信芳, 张君秋, 王正屏, 李逵, 窦尔敦, 高旺, 刘唐, 裘门深]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王水花</mainName>
    <names>[邢竹琴, 万象, 姬景华, 王水花, 白艳, 古塔, 姚水娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王永昌</mainName>
    <names>[王永昌, 李万春, 王永光, 袁世海, 郝寿臣, 姚秀民, 王恩普, 罗汉斗, 尹编, 王化纯, 李七, 南洋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王永运</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王汇川</mainName>
    <names>[曹宝义, 王, 李吉瑞, 刘奎官, 王佐川, 黄天霸, 周亚川, 高庆奎, 张百增, 赵松樵, 十一杰, 安东, 杨小楼, 王汇川, 沈顺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王泉奎</mainName>
    <names>[金嗓子, 王又宸, 梅兰, 沈玉才, 谭富英, 李少春, 梅葆玖, 王泉奎, 杨宝森, 梅兰芳, 徐霖甫, 李盛藻, 周信芳, 李元春, 张君秋, 陈丽芳, 马连良, 李慧芳, 赵荣琛, 李宗义, 王凤朝, 杨小楼, 刘玉泉, 孟小冬, 张春芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王泊生</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 吴瑞燕, 夏, 周信, 南侵, 四郎, 王泊生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王泳泉</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 赵燕侠, 王瑞芝, 王凤义, 沈玉斌, 唐, 耿少峰, 离赵, 李慕良, 王维清, 李毓芳, 高宝贤, 李淑玉, 王凤朝, 沈派, 王泳泉, 周文贵, 胡演, 沈玉才, 沈玉秋, 刘雪涛, 郭少, 高文静, 沈家门, 张君秋, 朱金琴, 姚品一, 李德山, 熊承旭, 弓法来, 赵, 吉祥, 汪本贞, 赵丽秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王海玲</mainName>
    <names>[宋, 王月, 张岫云, 王海玲, 王桂仙, 马豫, 秦良玉, 韦国泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王清芬</mainName>
    <names>[宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王玉敏</mainName>
    <names>[刘俊峰, 谭富英, 奚啸伯, 李多奎, 李少春, 随李, 李, 徐母骂, 郑子茹, 郭跃进, 高淑娟, 杨宝森, 江, 叶盛兰, 杨八姐, 马连良, 袁世海, 马鸥, 金田, 王玉敏, 岳母, 甄静娴, 龚派, 曹, 裘盛戎, 谭小令]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王玉琴</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔一团, 尚友社, 王玉琴, 满口腔, 秦腔, 杨门女]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王玉璞</mainName>
    <names>[王玉璞, 李崇善, 王梦云, 梅葆玖, 孙正阳, 尚长荣, 张鑫海, 于魁智, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王玉田</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 毕其一, 宋宝罗, 谭富英, 奚啸伯, 王, 李玉茹, 孙均卿, 王玉田, 曾拜, 万事孝, 王雨田, 尚小云, 苗胜春, 古人, 周信芳, 王老先生, 张荣奎, 李克昌, 王金璐, 王琴生, 于京剧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王玉磬</mainName>
    <names>[辕门, 张敏, 王文炳, 赵氏, 王玉磬, 陈春, 陈国贤, 太白, 王派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王玉蓉</mainName>
    <names>[杨宗保, 王伸, 仲仁, 法门寺, 张正义, 荀慧生, 张, 杨主生, 顾菊英, 李宝槐, 谭富, 杨四郎, 马神庙, 茅庐, 吴彩霞, 王瑶, 王艳, 袁寒云, 赵世兴, 王瑶卿, 刘三爷, 四郎, 李晓峰, 管绍华, 程砚, 胡琴, 孔雀东南, 明德, 古瑁轩, 马, 秋在旁, 朱斌, 程玉菁, 汪逢春, 丁震春, 王, 金仲仁, 田华亭, 王佩芬, 贾松龄, 袁世, 王寓, 庞敦敏, 王艳芳, 连念白, 焦仲卿, 秦淮, 胡铁阱, 李多奎, 全本, 南京夫, 姚玉芙, 王瑶老, 王系, 王宝钏, 杨六郎, 马连良, 王氏, 王玉蓉, 俞逸芬, 王幼卿, 陈巨来, 沈曼华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王珊妹</mainName>
    <names>[李铁梅, 马惠敏, 刘若兰, 王珊妹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王琴生</mainName>
    <names>[王, 谭富英, 李多奎, 穆宇, 董金凤, 宋继亭, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 尚, 朱丁奇, 蒋慕萍, 荀慧生, 周云亮, 张连福, 刘砚亭, 马富禄, 梁慧超, 王正堃, 王琴生, 王新侬, 沈小梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王瑞芝</mainName>
    <names>[杨宝忠, 吴少霞, 小冬嫁, 李佩卿, 王瑞芝, 谭富英, 王少楼, 李少春, 陈少霖, 迟世恭, 吴, 梅雨田, 白登云, 余叔岩, 王瑞, 叔岩, 孟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王瑶卿</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 王绚云, 谢锐青, 陈德霖, 谭鑫, 汤武, 赵桐珊, 朱琴心, 张正荃, 华慧, 王瑶卿, 黄玉麟, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 王派, 章遏云, 李紫珊, 荀慧生, 孔雀东南, 程腔, 王玉蓉, 于玉衡, 刘秀荣, 南天, 谭鑫培, 荣蝶仙, 程玉菁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王璐</mainName>
    <names>[张彪, 刘福生, 陆祥, 曲永春, 辛雨歌, 马玉璋, 杨门女, 丁振春, 王璐, 江长青, 周龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王盘声</mainName>
    <names>[王盘声, 王盘, 李玉和, 丁是娥, 金明, 周萍, 林耀华, 陈秀山, 汪志超, 刘智远, 王派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王盛如</mainName>
    <names>[王, 法门寺, 王盛如, 茹绍宝, 于京, 盛氏, 黄占生, 孙盛, 寇春华, 梁秀娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王盛意</mainName>
    <names>[宋起山, 法门寺, 贾顺成, 王盛意]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王福寿</mainName>
    <names>[阎岚秋, 俞润仙, 阎金子, 彭福林为师, 朱文英, 张聊止, 董凤岩, 董夔龙, 章梅岑, 王福寿, 俞氏, 王四, 范福泰, 赵子宜, 阎岚亭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王福山</mainName>
    <names>[杨香武, 朱光祖, 王长林, 杨小楼, 马童]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王秀兰</mainName>
    <names>[阎逢春, 孙广盛, 张庆奎, 梅兰芳, 王秀兰, 王存才]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王素珍</mainName>
    <names>[陈, 王素珍, 帅旦, 常香玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王紫苓</mainName>
    <names>[荀慧生, 马旦, 尤擅, 王紫苓]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王翠芬</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王耀宇</mainName>
    <names>[王耀宇, 宋德全]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王耀宗</mainName>
    <names>[郭德纲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王艾艾</mainName>
    <names>[郭兰英, 王艾艾, 高亢]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王芸芳</mainName>
    <names>[王芸芳, 马连良, 冯子, 谭富英, 金潭, 高庆奎, 白玉昆, 易俗社, 王瑶卿, 周皇, 欧阳予, 周信芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王茂源</mainName>
    <names>[孙巧, 王茂源, 焦光普京]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王荔</mainName>
    <names>[王荔, 李尔, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王荣增</mainName>
    <names>[王又宸, 谭富英, 裴炎, 荣增, 刘介梅, 李洪春, 梅兰芳, 汪派老生, 王荣增, 习文武, 荣春, 文武, 曹彦约, 刘彦昌, 江汉, 吴起, 杨延昭, 王绶曾, 王瑶卿, 洪母骂, 王凤卿, 冯兰池, 王少卿, 茹富兰, 周传瑛, 马连良, 雷喜福, 郭, 周传铮, 王幼卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王荣山</mainName>
    <names>[王岱清, 丁英奇, 王霸, 孙春恒, 郭文生, 王, 法门寺, 唐, 王盛如, 太白, 尚小云, 尚, 梅兰芳, 王永成, 王盛意, 老旦罗, 曾亲传, 谭派, 张伯驹, 于幼, 刘曾复, 谭, 高庆奎, 王荣, 杨小楼, 王师为, 王金彦, 王则昭, 王平, 陈德霖, 李, 谭鑫, 王瑶卿, 四郎, 纪玉良, 王凤卿, 王啸松, 郭, 班中, 陈士美, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王荫秋</mainName>
    <names>[唐忆娟, 杨麟秋, 王荫秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王蕙芳</mainName>
    <names>[袁, 陈敷民, 王永利, 王蕙芳, 王琴, 王聚宝, 王天仪, 梅兰芳, 王蕙, 朱霞芬, 王天佑, 陆杏林, 王少芳, 王门, 杨小楼, 关丽英, 贾洪, 迟景昆, 田雨侬, 陈德霖, 梅氏故, 陈文良, 双璧, 王爱珠, 王天倚, 杨, 王葵芳, 刘鸿声, 吴菱仙, 刘宗, 王风卿, 王聚玉, 王蕙亭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王贯英</mainName>
    <names>[马连良, 王贯, 朱德, 王佐, 周福, 徐庶, 王贯英, 刘少奇, 曾兼任, 寇准, 李斯等, 梅兰芳, 潘杨, 邓小平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王超群</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 茹富兰, 杨乃武, 张翼鹏, 马连良, 王超群, 金刀阵, 郑法祥, 李玉茹, 李三保, 孙悟空, 盖叫天, 盖来春, 周信芳, 李仲林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王辅生</mainName>
    <names>[王辅生, 王, 罗汉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王辉荃</mainName>
    <names>[滑稽, 王辉荃, 文华, 柏春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王连平</mainName>
    <names>[杨万清, 王, 曹心泉, 叶盛章, 徐良, 萧长华, 姚增禄, 丁俊, 王连平, 罗燕臣, 李庆喜, 叶, 罗春友, 晋察, 尤多, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王连浦</mainName>
    <names>[王连浦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王选</mainName>
    <names>[王选]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王金璐</mainName>
    <names>[丁永利, 马派, 侯喜瑞, 王少生, 诸连顺, 奚啸伯, 安天, 李玉茹, 李洪, 曹心泉, 于武, 杨少春, 陈少五, 蔡荣贵, 李洪春, 鲍吉祥, 马连良, 王金璐, 马德成, 迟月亭, 尚和玉, 武功, 叶金援, 宋德珠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王铁本</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 王铁本, 何, 张韵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王长友</mainName>
    <names>[刘宝瑞, 正式拜, 赵霭如, 尚有丁, 李金斗, 玉鹏, 刘学习, 刘巧儿, 王长友, 惠麟, 谭伯如, 寇庚杰, 郭文岐, 刘德智]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王长林</mainName>
    <names>[魏锡斋, 王长林, 谭鑫, 叶盛章, 王文隆, 陈彩林, 崔禄春, 马连良, 王德忠, 马富禄, 宋成, 李连仲, 习武丑, 杨小楼, 王松年]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王雅兰</mainName>
    <names>[上光明, 杨宗保, 侯宝, 王亚（, 王伶, 费玉策, 何宝童, 王, 法门寺, 汤勤, 李, 王雅兰, 马祥麟, 四郎, 王亚, 林脑子, 马旦, 伊之艺, 刘俊文, 贾多才, 文武, 林饰, 王金龙, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王震</mainName>
    <names>[魏振山, 陈永玲, 马连良, 陈, 王, 马, 王震, 曹, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王韵通</mainName>
    <names>[王琴侬, 王韵通, 王怡]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王鸣仲</mainName>
    <names>[王鸣仲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王鹤文</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 王无道, 杨宝忠, 帅, 恨平, 王瑞芝, 梅葆玖, 谭元寿, 舒展, 寇准, 赵建华, 李慕良, 马谡正, 姜妙香, 胡琴, 红遍, 胥, 伍子, 王鹤文, 张学津, 李鸣盛, 尚长荣, 拉杨, 杨柳青, 杨宝, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>班世超</mainName>
    <names>[刘金定, 李少春, 梅兰芳, 伏契克, 班世超, 马旦, 盖叫天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>班德贵</mainName>
    <names>[刘广文, 王家琪, 马三立, 班松林, 刘宝瑞, 杨少奎, 刘文贞, 刘宝, 冯立铎, 刘玉凤, 马敬, 李洁尘, 刘文亨, 张杰, 范振钰, 于佑福, 冯立樟, 张杰尧, 曲艺杂, 刘伯奎, 班德贵, 耿宝林, 曹, 赵心敏, 冯宝华, 袁佩楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>琴雪芳</mainName>
    <names>[琴雪芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>琼霞</mainName>
    <names>[梅花奖, 赖琼霞, 金兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>甄洪奎</mainName>
    <names>[甄洪奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有田中玉的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田占义</mainName>
    <names>[袁阔, 王世臣, 李自成, 李鑫荃, 田占义, 古今通鉴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田子馥</mainName>
    <names>[刘大白, 田子馥, 曹保明, 古代常]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田宝琳</mainName>
    <names>[胡琴, 王琴侬, 田宝琳, 陈德霖, 王凤卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田敏</mainName>
    <names>[李淑芳, 秦香莲, 吴碧波, 刘桂莲, 扈三娘, 田敏, 田敏拜, 陈派, 马旦, 李云霞, 李玉梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田正武</mainName>
    <names>[田正武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田汉</mainName>
    <names>[郭沫, 田汉, 周信芳, 郁达夫, 寿昌, 宗白华, 欧阳予]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田爱云</mainName>
    <names>[张素云, 梁山伯, 李, 田爱, 田爱云, 李学义]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田立禾</mainName>
    <names>[田立禾, 张寿臣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田荣芬</mainName>
    <names>[王菊芳, 王蕙芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田连元</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 贾科, 贾科长, 唐, 王起胜, 孙膑]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>田际云</mainName>
    <names>[正乐, 双顺, 云10岁, 田自, 田际云, 班主赵, 田际]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>由奇</mainName>
    <names>[王志廉, 杨汝震, 蔡保杰, 伍子, 陈志清, 李金声, 曹, 李甫春, 叶蓬, 尹培玺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>申凤梅</mainName>
    <names>[李世民, ，, 梁山伯, 白玉兰, 李天, 马兰, 董必武, 杨尚昆, 越调科, 舌战, 华容, 越调, 阎惜姣, 李天保, 孔明, 诸葛亮, 邓小平, 周恩来, 刘少奇, 彭真, 周, 马连良, 卓著, 梁红玉, 周口, 李先念, 江泽民, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>申小梅</mainName>
    <names>[梅病危, 须生, 李天, 梅唱腔, 舌战, 师申, 杨奶奶, 越调, 梅越, 李天保, 王母, 孔明, 刘志, 诸葛亮, 温家宝, 上行李, 赵玉霞, 李, 曾庆红, 王宝钏, 高珍, 江泽民]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>申德高</mainName>
    <names>[田汉赞, 迟敬德, 朱楼科班, 毛净, 申德, 周恩来, 贺龙, 花脸五, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白云生</mainName>
    <names>[曾组, 戴爱莲, 张桐玉, 王益友, 白云生, 周思来, 梅兰芳, 韩世昌, 韩世]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白元鸣</mainName>
    <names>[万啸璞, 王盛海, 李玉茹, 黄忠, 李元芳, 谭元寿, 叶盛章, 张盛禄, 钱宝森, 王凤卿, 孟, 王连平, 李世芳, 张连福, 赵云, 李适可, 刘盛通, 李元, 谭鑫培, 王瑞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白其麟</mainName>
    <names>[白其麟, 孙毓敏, 吴纪敏, 郑太监, 刘罗锅, 梁花侬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白奉霖</mainName>
    <names>[白奉霖, 金万昌, 王佩臣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白家麟</mainName>
    <names>[李鹤亭, 吴秀媛, 在家相夫, 吴铁庵, 红净, 白家麟, 高庆奎, 李鸣盛, 吕洞宾]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白敬亭</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白文彪</mainName>
    <names>[李翰祥, 黄昏恋, 白文彪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白玉堂</mainName>
    <names>[陈艳侬, 刘美卿, ，, 唐天宝, 黄君武, 白驹荣, 乐同春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白玉昆</mainName>
    <names>[王云桥, 马超, 白玉昆, 朱光祖, 武净, 张介仁, 李洪春, 刘, 梅兰芳, 赵君玉, 荀慧生, 白玉, 刘俊文, 李永利, 白晶珠, 高庆奎, 张飞, 李奇, 郝二明, 赵胜玉, 王喜虎, 赵春, 李万春, 杨家, 蓝月春, 林树森, 陈桐云, 安京, 赵鸿林, 王适, 红风, 马连良, 甘露寺, 朱胜奎, 武生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白玉梅</mainName>
    <names>[梁祝, 王永春, 梅兰芳, 白玉玲, 朱岩铨]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白玉琼</mainName>
    <names>[胡琴, 白玉琼, 吴仪成]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白玉薇</mainName>
    <names>[叶开源, 马旦戏, 魏莲芳, 李玉茹, 李少春, 侯玉兰, 李少, 白玉薇, 李玉芝, 王瑶卿, 诸如香, 梅兰芳, 吴富琴, 韩世昌, 陈丽芳, 张金凤, 张善亭, 萧太后, 勾脸, 王幼卿, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白玉霜</mainName>
    <names>[李桂珍, 于京, 田汉, 李慧敏, 赵如泉, 孔雀东南, 洪, 欧阳予, 孙凤鸣, 袁良请, 白玉霜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白登云</mainName>
    <names>[马占元, 程子余, 李德侗, 郭中昌, 刘有林, 谭富英, ，, 李少春, 白登, 曾拜, 张春华, 梅兰芳, 刘福兴, 赵庆, 王长贵, 程腔, 王振刚, 李德启, 谭小培, 王德锐, 杨小楼, 杨鸣庆, 李万选, 马学义, 艾利仁, 吕鸿林, 谢锐青, 诸位, 黄, 侯来义, 魏希云, 郝寿臣, 李金鸿, 杜近芳, 卞振旺, 李, 金, 武松, 张继五, 杜, 王凤卿, 王燮元, 郭立昌, 鲍桂山, 阎宝泉, 袁世海, 郑奎元, 石松亭, 赵荣琛, 郭少安, 杨俊生, 张世桐, 曹奎子, 唐锡林, 苏麟熹, 周子厚, 郭德顺, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白科华</mainName>
    <names>[陈胜, 白科华, 梁饰方, 李鹤鸣, 张, 张敏, 李紫贵, 陈文, 范凡, 陈利华, 王正, 阎喜林, 魏奇元, 陈文远, 叶德凤, 徐策, 周恩来, 华亲耳, 白少华, 葛, 施洋, 周, 杨子荣, 戴景臣, 张少, 白科, 程永龙, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>白英杰</mainName>
    <names>[白英杰, 赫哲, 于世德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>盖叫天</mainName>
    <names>[黄龙, 张翼鹏, 张二鹏, 隆庆, 勾勒, 哪吒, 盖派, 燕南, 项羽, 盖叫天, 张剑鸣, 李春来]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>盖月樵</mainName>
    <names>[梅兰芳, 王鸿寿, 南天, 盖三]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>盖玉亭</mainName>
    <names>[崔湘亭, 吴汉杀, 帅, 郭雨顺, 郭月楼, 海龙, 王天柱, 崔, 张玉亭, 周信芳, 莫须, 秦腔, 樊富顺, 钱振国, 张韵楼, 高雪樵, 郭喜庆, 华东野, 廖廖无几, 隆春, 李, 郭维元, 盖玉亭, 仲曦东, 刘筱衡, 张元志, 四人帮, 海拉尔, 唐韵笙, 白袖章, 谭富英, 梁连柱, 刘汉臣, 李大, 符拉迪沃斯托克, 张纹祥, 辛集, 薛, 万姑娘, 刘松超, 安国, 舒茂林, 万金, 侯八冲, 班增奎, 郭月, 侯, 高登, 厉声喝, 离休, 李吉来, 李大麻, 李韵章, 侯八一, 郑庄公, 路滑, 富连成, 万氏, 刘海生, 王虎臣, 连成, 何茂卿, 刘昭伦, 科班只, 张殿华, 叔侄俩, 燕春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>盛小云</mainName>
    <names>[晏芝, 蒋云仙, 蒋调, 俞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>盛庆玉</mainName>
    <names>[盛三, 沈三玉, 班坐科, 盛庆玉, 刘祥茂, 班散, 刘东岩, 尚小云, 辛亥革命, 荣, 尚三, 裴荣庆, 班中德, 吴荣英, 高腔, 张荣凤, 班报散, 师昆, 张家口, 王府]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>瞿剑英</mainName>
    <names>[瞿剑英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>石富宽</mainName>
    <names>[石富宽]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>石文磊</mainName>
    <names>[姚暮双, 周, 赵开生, 李淑一, 金缕曲·周总理, 周柏春, 毛泽东, 石文磊, 毛, 秦建国, 倪迎春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>石晓亮</mainName>
    <names>[石晓亮, 郭元祥, 董文华, 张春华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>石筱英</mainName>
    <names>[石筱英, 罗湘绮, 刘若兰, 石筱, 金绣娘, 诸惠琴, 罗汉, 倪幸佳, 沈凤喜, 徐纫秋, 马, 陈甦萍, 赵丹, 和丁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>石连君</mainName>
    <names>[黄福才, 张起荣, 赵玉峰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>祁荣奎</mainName>
    <names>[王志全, 茹富华, 黄齐峰, 李国静, 梅兰, 尚富霞, 尚明珠, 四郎, 祁荣奎, 龙凤呈, 姜妙香, 王晶玉, 祁喜奎, 程式化, 侯少丞, 穆桂英, 董文华, 贾]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>祁荣雯</mainName>
    <names>[叶盛兰, 尚富霞, 谭富英, 李多奎, 祁荣, 祁荣雯, 陈盛泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>祝元昆</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 后拜, 秦英, 李世民, 祝元, 李少春, 唐, 祝元昆, 班进京, 祝, 梁山, 张秋生, 元昆, 张军, 文武, 李派, 吕洞宾]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>祝宽</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 文武, 祝宽]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>祝敏</mainName>
    <names>[杨海荃, 祝敏, 冯振声]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>秋楚笙</mainName>
    <names>[秋楚笙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>秦小梨</mainName>
    <names>[金巴仑, 白雪, 罗品, 张活游, 梅兰芳, 红线女]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>秦慧芬</mainName>
    <names>[秦亦向, 胡陆蕙, 王凤云, 梅派戏, 王爵, 王蕙芳, 李泽浩, 秦慧, 陆光, 魏海敏, 厉慧敏, 梅派, 金素琴, 四郎, 雷峰塔, 王复蓉, 赵君玉, 中正, 戴绮霞, 罗慧兰, 王复琰, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>秦湘麟</mainName>
    <names>[秦湘麟, 刘兰秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程世杰</mainName>
    <names>[沈春霞, 吉林长白, 李慧娘, 韩昌, 李洪春, 张盛禄, 阎世, 曾演, 管绍华, 李逵, 张飞, 程世杰, 刘喜益, 刘勋, 国华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程君谋</mainName>
    <names>[谭派, 陈彦衡, 胡琴, 蔡锷, 孙养侬, 马, 谭富, 程君谋, 孙岳, 四郎, 丁巳, 梅葆玥, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程正泰</mainName>
    <names>[正泰, 吴江, 杨家, 伍子, 程正泰, 陈秀华, 金榜乐, 杨对程, 杨宝森, 曹, 红旗, 钱宝森, 杨付]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程永江</mainName>
    <names>[程永江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程玉菁</mainName>
    <names>[梁雯, 范, 马旦戏, 李释勘, 邱治云, 王, 程, 法门寺, 李少, 归京, 梅兰芳, 俞振, 师林树森, 凌波, 王派, 张金凤, 王派风, 吴彦衡, 程玉美, 汪优游, 李寿山, 王门后, 梅玉配, 谢锐, 吴彩霞, 王瑶, 郎霞玉, 周凤文, 程玉, 班晋京, 王瑶卿, 杨宝森, 四郎, 薛金莲, 万松, 胡氏, 王宝钏, 韩翠珠, 诸茹香, 章逸云, 陶玉芝, 苏巧云, 萧太后, 董俊峰, 周信, 李万, 赵, 卢沟, 能仁寺, 程玉菁, 茹富蕙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程砚秋</mainName>
    <names>[习花旦, 陈桐云, 李世济, 周恩来, 赵桐珊, 侯玉兰, 李蔷华, 杨宝森, 陈啸云, 程砚, 陈丽芳, 程砚秋, 王吟秋, 吴祖光, 刘鸿声, 赵荣琛, 荣春亮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程笑飞</mainName>
    <names>[王啸天, 程笑飞, 包一飞, 张樵侬, 王, 越剧, 曹蝶飞, 徐双飞, 陈炳章, 杨华生, 刘, 俞与, 沈一乐, 俞祥明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程继先</mainName>
    <names>[朱素, 曾名德, 陈春元, 徐小香, 李, 王瑶卿, 俞振飞, 蔡荣贵, 梅兰芳, 姚增禄, 辛亥革命, 叶盛兰, 白云生, 刘春喜, 杨春圃, 杨隆寿, 邓霞姑, 王楞仙, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培, 王楞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程臻</mainName>
    <names>[朱俭, 马莉莉, 王孝, 罗汉, 程臻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程砚秋</mainName>
    <names>[习花旦, 陈桐云, 李世济, 周恩来, 赵桐珊, 侯玉兰, 李蔷华, 杨宝森, 陈啸云, 程砚, 陈丽芳, 程砚秋, 王吟秋, 吴祖光, 刘鸿声, 赵荣琛, 荣春亮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>程长庚</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 班余, 陈祥桂, 徐小香, 张二奎, 张享名, 法门寺, 钱金福, 幸得, 庚, 孙菊, 安五, 华容, 张淇林, 班老生, 索宅, 鲁肃, 庚（其舅, 诸葛亮, 米喜子, 黄, 闻翰, 陈德霖, 杨月楼, 伍子胥, 程闻檄, 胡同文, 谭鑫培, 尉迟, 宋代著]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>穆祥林</mainName>
    <names>[陈君, 穆祥林, 马三立, 郭全宝, 李文山, 王宝童, 双簧, 王济忱, 张寿臣, 郭嘉强, 于宝林, 刘继斌, 姜宝林, 谢惠, 耿伯春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>穆铁芬</mainName>
    <names>[王瑶卿, 罗瘿公, 周长华, 程, 穆铁芬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>竞华</mainName>
    <names>[沈铁梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>章传溶</mainName>
    <names>[朱传茗, 刘铁嘴, 沈月泉, 汪传钤, 王传淞, 冯雄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>章宗义</mainName>
    <names>[玉宇, 孙悟空, 毛泽东, 万里埃, 章宗义, 尤擅, 郭沫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有章宗信的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>章诒和</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>章遏云</mainName>
    <names>[朱素, 侯喜瑞, 梅兰, 李宝琴, 王, 王士英, 穆铁芬, 江顺仙, 周瑞安, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 张彩林, 邵佩瑜, 叶盛兰, 王派神髓, 习老生, 黄天霸, 李寿山, 鲁肃, 高庆奎, 胡碧兰, 杨小楼, 邓氏, 王庾生, 陈少霖, 王瑶卿, 蒋干, 四郎, 张安平, 章遏云, 张德俊, 荣蝶, 诸茹香, 程砚秋, 袁世海, 马连良, 陶玉芝, 马富禄, 金友琴, 周瑜, 茹富蕙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>童大强</mainName>
    <names>[张春孝, 杨修, 薛正康, 文天, 谭元寿, 赵志秋, 陆正红, 赵王, 陈朝红, 杨小佩, 朱春科, 李多芬, 李益, 朱紫国, 朱, 尚长荣, 魏朔峰, 赵国华, 童大强, 在逸夫, 穆柯寨, 王梦云, 徐策, 郭暧, 李世济, 李瑞环, 金, 何澍, 宋士杰, 张南云, 陈少云, 张少楼, 唐僧和, 刘佳拜, 霍小玉, 方小亚, 王桂卿, 刘秀荣, 曹操, 田伦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有童寿苓的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有童玉苓的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>童芷苓</mainName>
    <names>[尤, 唐韵笙, 王熙凤, 李盛斌, 白家麟, 王瑶卿, 梅兰芳, 李盛藻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>竺水招</mainName>
    <names>[竺云华, 梁, 徐龙, 张玉琴, 尹派, 孔雀胆, 尹, 桂芳, 柳毅, 戚雅仙, 尹桂芳, 双锤, 孙安, 孔雀东南, 尹竺, 范蠡, 陆文龙, 竺水招]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>笑嘻嘻</mainName>
    <names>[劝夫, 张樵侬, 姚慕双, 叶, 周柏春, 杨华生, 沈一乐, 李达, 江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>笑林</mainName>
    <names>[李国盛, 侯宝, 刘司昌, 马季, 赵学林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱丹桂</mainName>
    <names>[俞传海, 徐玉兰, 贾灵凤, 张春帆, 来沙尔, 马寡妇]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱侠影</mainName>
    <names>[陈录田, 秦香莲, 彭祖, 赖友旦, 朱侠影, 刘汉臣, 张笑影, 周信芳, 吴韵芳, 张艳霞, 崔文远, 程砚秋, 杨乃武, 陈玉秋, 郭砚芳, 张笑声, 杨蕴田, 靳, 赵松樵, 杨麟, 张汶祥, 张广才]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱兰芳</mainName>
    <names>[陈美根, 钱慧韵, 梅兰芳, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱凤彩</mainName>
    <names>[尤精, 张凤彩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱咪咪</mainName>
    <names>[袁, 姚公记, 王传璋, 丘老七, 林树桐, 房东, 邹笑笑, 张金生, 刘汉明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱快乐</mainName>
    <names>[张冶儿, 田丽丽, 朱良, 沈一乐, 米蛀虫, 刘快乐]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱文艳</mainName>
    <names>[金树英, 筱文艳, 潘风岭, 秦香莲, 张士勤, 张姓, 刘, 李玉梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱月英</mainName>
    <names>[胡凤莲, 习花旦, 王玉春, 梅合作, 庞天华, 沈月英, 丁赛君, 孔雀东南, 文成, 孔雀东南飞, 薄情郎, 越剧团, 吴天麒, 刘兰芝, 郑忠, 唐蕙仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱杨松</mainName>
    <names>[欧阳芳, 王德祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱桂桃</mainName>
    <names>[杨丹卿, 杨自幼, 张宝魁, 须生, 梅降雪, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱桂琴</mainName>
    <names>[桂, 秦英, 杨素珍, 宋, 桂桃, 法门寺, 丁果仙, 宋士杰, 张宝魁, 张万一, 琴10岁, 李子键, 赵廉, 盖天红, 李世芳, 梅绛亵, 宋巧娇, 丁果, 张美琴, 琴扮, 凤冠, 桂琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱桂花</mainName>
    <names>[李金顺, 萧军, 李腔, 奉天, 叶落空, 王少, 王华, 王彩云, 张丽云, 岳霄, 马振华, 李派, 马寡妇]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱樊春楼</mainName>
    <names>[徐策, 樊春楼, 屈原, 周信芳, 杨宝童, 郑亦秋, 荀慧生, 薛贵春, 董祀, 文武, 樊放]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱玉霜</mainName>
    <names>[凤仪, 梁山伯, 李, 金, 张羽, 李在雯, 毛, 花月, 郑巧, 王少, 李忆兰, 李在云, 李娃, 李月娥, 秦香, 马寡妇, 龚万]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱玲珑</mainName>
    <names>[陈元相, 李, 尤精, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱艳秋</mainName>
    <names>[孙悟空, 林慧娘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>筱高雪樵</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 高月秋, 白玉艳, 孙悟空, 鲍洛, 李如春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>管无灵</mainName>
    <names>[徐小英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>管绍华</mainName>
    <names>[王玉蓉, 管绍华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>管韵华</mainName>
    <names>[胡, 李桂春, 唐韵笙, 李少春, 曾任, 管韵华, 李桂, 李幼春, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>米喜子</mainName>
    <names>[米应生, 黄忠, 于临, 戴齐, 米喜子, 尤演]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>米玉文</mainName>
    <names>[丁永利, 赵燕侠, 诸连顺, 奚啸伯, 李盛斌, 叶盛章, 沈富贵, 迟月, 李洪春, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 张君秋, 荀慧生, 王连平, 米玉文, 曹玺彦, 宋德珠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>粉牡丹</mainName>
    <names>[蒋鼎文, 刘玉芳, 邴, 马健翎, 慕名, 艾云生, 文联特, 麻姑]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>粉菊花</mainName>
    <names>[孙柏龄, 孙国良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>红线女</mainName>
    <names>[何芙莲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>纪玉良</mainName>
    <names>[李长春, 李世芳, 王金璐, 张少甫, 李玉茹, 陈秀华, 毛世, 宋德珠, 四郎, 纪玉良, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>绿杨</mainName>
    <names>[欧阳, 绿杨, 杨美媚, 王美玉, 杨华生, 吴妈]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>缪以煊</mainName>
    <names>[陈佩斯, 缪以煊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗万金</mainName>
    <names>[罗万金]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗兰梅</mainName>
    <names>[罗兰梅, 卖苗郎, 梅捐, 班十八, 唐成, 崔兰田, 罗兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗品超</mainName>
    <names>[红花岗, 吕布, 罗品, 罗肇鉴, 梁山伯, 凤仪, 夏扶, 普及, 罗品超, 黄飞虎, 罗成, 梁山, 杨五郎, 宋意, 五郎, 张胜, 林肯, 欧阳予, 薛平贵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗燕臣</mainName>
    <names>[罗燕臣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗瘿公</mainName>
    <names>[尤与, 袁世, 程砚秋, 罗瘿, 罗瘿公, 王瑶卿, 东交民巷, 梅兰芳, 程对罗]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗盛公</mainName>
    <names>[王连平, 罗盛公, 郑家]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗福山</mainName>
    <names>[罗派, 李多奎, 陈文启, 班演出, 龚云甫, 梅兰芳, 朱痕记, 孙甫亭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗荣庭</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 刘邦, 梅兰, 李元瑞, 罗建昆, 程普, 高祖罗, 梅葆玖, 张玉禅, 吴素秋, 姚玉刚, 伍子胥, 梅兰芳, 刘连荣, 衡水, 李世英, 刘备, 宋王, 穆桂英, 罗荣庭, 苏小妹, 罗文森, 穆柯寨·穆天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗蕙兰</mainName>
    <names>[罗蕙兰, 苏武, 马连良, 马, 李鸣盛, 秦兰英, 梅兰芳, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>罗通明</mainName>
    <names>[罗通明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>羊兰芬</mainName>
    <names>[李双双, 刘胡兰, 李香莲, 张俊臣, 刘虹霞, 牛郎, 雷锋, 陈大娘, 羊兰, 刘派, 羊兰芬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>翁中芹</mainName>
    <names>[翁中芹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>翁偶虹</mainName>
    <names>[黄玉华, 李少春, 黄占彭, 吴素秋, 翁偶, 叶盛兰, 程砚秋, 袁世海, 李逵, 程茂亭, 翁偶虹, 赵, 童芷苓, 玉壶冰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>翁双杰</mainName>
    <names>[王兴, 姚慕双, 翁双杰, 周柏春, 鲍勃·霍甫之邀, 却利]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>翟燕身</mainName>
    <names>[翟小香, 翟燕身]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>翟爱云</mainName>
    <names>[翟爱云, 翟彦生, 常香玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>翟西园</mainName>
    <names>[张蓉华, 梁, 周仁, 罗成, 丁至云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>老舍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>耿世忠</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 钮骠, 阎世善, 荣翔, 耿世忠, 李世芳, 李元瑞, 毕生, 张世宽, 赵荣欣, 耿永峰, 耿世华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>耿其昌</mainName>
    <names>[李世霖, 王瑞芝, 赵泉生, 于世文, 黄忠, 薛仁贵, 宋继亭, 郭建光, 秦琼, 梁山, 刘秀, 刘曾复, 叶盛长, 鲁肃, 杨四郎, 李凤姐, 诸葛亮, 正德, 郭仲霖, 耿其昌, 刘彦昌, 宋江, 乌盆计, 四郎, 赵明诚, 王连平, 李玉和, 陈斌雨, 茹富兰, 刘备, 王金璐, 刘世昌, 杨子荣, 薛平贵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>耿喜斌</mainName>
    <names>[叶肖斋, 耿喜斌, 贾桂所, 侯喜瑞, 赵喜贞, 雷喜福, 法门寺, 王喜秀]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>耿巧云</mainName>
    <names>[沈世华, 张正芳, 李铁梅, 宋长荣, 袁世海, 李金鸿, 张逸娟, 秦雪玲, 刘长瑜, 陈国为, 王秀兰, 于玉蘅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>耿永奎</mainName>
    <names>[孔雀东南, 程砚秋, 王文华, 谭小培, 于京剧, 耿永奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>耿永峰</mainName>
    <names>[耿世忠, 汪笑侬, 耿永禄, 张连福, 耿少峰, 耿世华, 耿幼峰, 金福之]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>耿永清</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 胡, 葛绥之, 耿永清, 陈祥瑞, 鲍桂山, 吴炳璋, 李德山, 罗文翰, 王瑞芝, 高庆奎, 耿少峰, 赵冬生, 耿明昆, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>肖甲</mainName>
    <names>[肖甲, 二甲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡仲仁</mainName>
    <names>[胡仲仁, 胡钟伦, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡启明</mainName>
    <names>[唐, 魏寅初, 吴炳璋, 李瑞环, 胡启明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡小凤</mainName>
    <names>[胡, 凤凰, 帅字旗, 周恩来, 穆桂英, 陈毅, 郭沫, 梅花奖, 徐特立, 毛泽东, 胡小凤, 鲁豫, 毛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡小毛</mainName>
    <names>[鲍骆, 刘少泉, 赵胜利, 董文华, 周宗善]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡少安</mainName>
    <names>[胡宝安, 曾自组, 宋, 谭富英, 梅葆玖, 胡少安, 宋继亭, 刘, 马义救, 李盛藻, 胡少, 胡宝利, 叶盛兰, 李世芳, 马连良, 袁世海, 张少甫, 安文武, 马, 高庆奎, 林肯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡希和</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 朱强, 沈, 王蓉蓉, ，, 胡希和, 沈玉斌, 王呤秋, 陈俊杰, 李宏图, 吴素秋, 琴, 姜铁麟, 荀令莱, 杜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡文阁</mainName>
    <names>[胡文阁, 梅葆玖, 东玉三郎, 王姬, 陈香梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡晴云</mainName>
    <names>[胡晴云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡桂馨</mainName>
    <names>[白雪, 胡不归, 马来亚, 胡桂馨, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡沙</mainName>
    <names>[张玮, 李肖, 茅盾, 刘喜, 朱德, 金河乡, 邓小平, 阮文追, 冯霞, 胡沙, 向阳, 高琛, 万岁, 巴金, 丁玲, 陈有才, 鲁迅, 毛泽东, 徐家坮, 正气歌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡璇</mainName>
    <names>[李鸣岩, 杨门女, 李逵, 李多芬, 杨韵清, 王玉敏, 李金泉, 胡璇, 李妃, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡碧兰</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 侯喜瑞, 王瑶, 吴铁庵, 郝寿臣, 谭富英, 王, 奚啸伯, 柳迎春, 王瑶卿, 四郎, 周瑞安, 王凤卿, 王宝钏, 王云卿, 胡琴, 王少卿, 王少楼, 王幼卿, 郭仲衡, 胡碧兰, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>胡芝风</mainName>
    <names>[胡芝风, 李慧娘, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 南洋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>舒昌玉</mainName>
    <names>[真功夫, 魏莲芳, 梅门, 朱琴心, 东北返, 双CD, 刘, 梅兰芳, 东, 梅寓面, 汪道, 顾宝森, 舒昌, 刘占虚, 梅师, 赵松樵, 舒昌玉拉, 孙尚香, 宇宙锋, 红氍毹, 奚啸伯, 沈雁西, 王瑶卿, 梅派, 四郎, 王宝钏, 朱传茗, 茹富兰, 马富禄, 穆桂英, 聂荣, 王幼卿, 舒同寿, 沈燕西, 舒昌玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>舒茂林</mainName>
    <names>[舒茂林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>良小楼</mainName>
    <names>[盖坤, 李德全, 董存瑞, 刘, 刘派京韵, 华容, 金日成, 王洪利, 李炳卫, 双玉, 徐学惠, 刘宝全, 马褂儿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>艳桂荣</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 舒展, 广采, 薛家, 杨金花]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵桐珊</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 刘胡兰, 侯喜瑞, 李灵芝, 王熙凤, 李玉茹, 寿春, 狄英鸾, 赵桐珊, 陈和平, 刘长瑜, 汤小梅, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 赵君玉, 荀慧生, 张金凤, 崔秀英, 阎惜姣, 李永利, 高庆奎, 高旺, 周凤英, 艾美君, 王门, 诸葛亮, 崔灵芝, 孙尚香, 丁灵芝, 杨玉环, 杨秋玲, 阴狠, 梅玉配, 赵凌茹, 正乐, 陈彦衡, 谢锐青, 郎霞玉, 班后, 任灵, 王瑶卿, 田桂凤, 王小蓉, 薛金莲, 胡氏, 吕雉, 欧阳, 胡, 韩翠珠, 程砚秋, 马连良, 王氏, 王配演, 萧太, 刘秀荣, 赵庭玺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>花云宝</mainName>
    <names>[曹福庆, 梅花, 卢成, 钟吉铨, 花云宝, 小花四宝, 李元通, 钟吉瑞, 王文奎, 曲协, 卢派, 张雅琴, 谢瑞东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>花天成</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>花月仙</mainName>
    <names>[张淑桂, 向阳, 沈惠珍, 杨八姐, 张筠青, 李惟铨, 刘云, 刘淑萍, 赵月楼, 陈母一角]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>花淑兰</mainName>
    <names>[刘翠屏, 张秀云, 谢瑶环, 花淑兰, 吴丹阳, 曾拜, 刘翠霞, 冯玉萍, 赵俊芝, 谢郁文, 刘, 曾昭娟, 葛淑兰, 刘派, 郑桂芳, 田敬阳, 刘子西, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>花砚茹</mainName>
    <names>[王德斋, 费氏, 王氏, 刘巧儿, 刘媒婆, 王景明, 李忆兰, 赵丽蓉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>花筱宝</mainName>
    <names>[秋窗, 王二姐, 于京, 史文秀]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有苏世詹的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏兰芳</mainName>
    <names>[黄龙, 苏占奎, 凤仪, 杨藩, 苏兰, 卖苗郎, 苏兰芳, 汤兰香, 常香, 穆桂英, 彭, 阴阳, 苏金兰, 盛典, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏哲民</mainName>
    <names>[阎国斌, 陈德裕, 景龙, 苏上, 苏育民, 苏哲民, 苏长泰, 秦腔, 王外, 王德孝, 武功, 王勾践]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏宝荣</mainName>
    <names>[苏宝荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏富宪</mainName>
    <names>[苏富宪, 苏雨卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有苏富旭的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏少卿</mainName>
    <names>[陈彦衡, 杨宝忠, 徐筱汀, 刘仲秋, 王玉芳, 梅兰芳, 李可染, 程砚秋, 苏娥, 苏声社, 张伯英, 谭派须]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏广忠</mainName>
    <names>[苏广忠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏敬武</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 安平, 张世麟, 孟广禄, 习净, 李春恒, 杨光, 梁连柱, 舒桐, 宋富亭, 王紫苓, 苏维明, 厉慧良, 杨宝森, 苏敬武, 于津, 周啸天, 刘魁魁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏盛琴</mainName>
    <names>[陆宝琳, 苏富旭, 王晓棠, 赵韵秋, 王天柱, 李元芳, 叶盛章, 赵庆侠, 李门, 张春华, 苏富恩, 梅兰芳, 盛, 孙萍, 班世超, 王燕, 习胡琴, 李世芳, 刘元彤, 习老生, 李丽芳, 贾世珍, 徐兰, 王吟秋, 苏盛贵, 苏盛琴, 李鸣盛, 毛世来, 李超]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏盛轼</mainName>
    <names>[苏盛轼, 苏雨卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏连汉</mainName>
    <names>[益腔一气呵成, 侯喜, 苏连汉, 金连寿, 穆柯寨, 俞华庭, 苏始, 李少春, 李, 王斌芬, 班甚久, 姚, 徐碧, 荣春社, 张连福, 马连良, 袁世海, 何连涛, 叶福海, 焦赞, 刘喜益, 赵连升, 程永龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏雨卿</mainName>
    <names>[叶盛兰, 李世芳, 刘元彤, 苏, 邱富棠, 李元芳, 仲盛珍, 陈盛荪, 李喜泉, 高喜玉, 苏瑞莲, 苏雨卿, 李连贞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苏韵衡</mainName>
    <names>[苏韵衡]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苗喜臣</mainName>
    <names>[姚刚, 刘莲, 洪月, 苗娃, 张家, 李俊轩, 曹县城, 曹庄, 苗喜臣, 刘家班, 小苗娃, 年芳, 宇宙锋, 刘屯班, 马金凤, 李, 桑振君, 杨金玉, 杨蕃, 成武, 卖苗郎, 黄儒秀, 班及]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苗胜春</mainName>
    <names>[褚彪, 韩金奎, 宋, 赵春瑞, 白玉昆, 朱光祖, 苗胜春, 周信芳, 周如失, 周忽, 李始终, 周得, 张少甫, 李琴, 周不可, 金兰, 周同, 高庆奎, 苗跪拜, 苗二爷, 杨小楼, 苗配, 王平, 班解散, 海参崴, 黄派武, 王庆坨, 二哥, 苗离, 俞振飞, 苗所, 席散, 靳庆, 李琴仙, 叶之妙, 那正鑫, 周, 马连良, 苗饰, 马德成, 关平, 严嵩, 苗胜, 老乙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>苗阜</mainName>
    <names>[苗阜, 郑小山, 苗宏齐]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范元濂</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 王连平, 法门寺, 叶盛章, 谭元寿, 叶春善, 范元濂, 梅兰芳, 梁山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范克峻</mainName>
    <names>[包拯, 唐明皇, 梅兰, 杨修, 刘劲, 王允, 田小牛, 秦腔, 范克峻, 诸葛亮, 乔玄, 陈世美, 黄岘, 魏虎, 秦剧, 周仁, 四郎, 关羽月, 周仁瑞, 万谔, 张明, 刘备, 苏武, 薛炳坤, 田云山, 曹操, 杨家宁, 薛平贵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范哈哈</mainName>
    <names>[小李, 范哈哈, 杜宝林, 满清, 赵希希, 李]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范宝亭</mainName>
    <names>[范宝亭, 郝寿臣, 雷峰, 金福, 钱金福, 于洪, 林, 尚, 刘奎官, 谢, 红扎, 高庆奎, 许德义, 厉慧良, 赵, 许, 杨小楼, 刘郎, 范福泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范富喜</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 李维康, 秦腔小生, 俞振庭, 徐若英, 刘长瑜, 吴素秋, 毛世, 汤小梅, 刘琪, 尚小云, 陈国为, 鲍绮瑜, 秦腔, 樊富顺, 叶盛兰, 范富喜, 万凤姝, 郭君学, 张薇莉, 苏稚, 杨秋玲, 王道津]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范振钰</mainName>
    <names>[杨俊杰, 郭伯良, 彭华, 于志勇, 赵津生, 马腾翔, 张德起, 高英培, 王传林, 郭德, 范振钰, 何世铭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范瑞娟</mainName>
    <names>[贝尔, 梁来, 范派, 梁山伯, 李秀成, 周扬, 郑元和, 田汉, 万户, 黄炳文, 姚水娟, 卓别林, 诸暨, 孔雀东南飞, 上稳健, 越艺社, 高庆奎, 张珙, 全香, 范瑞娟, 李娃传, 邵文娟, 张志明, 吴凤花, 郭暧, 周恩来, 韩婷婷, 傅全香, 李, 袁雪芬, 张惠忠, 邢竹琴, 梁祝哀, 山伯, 章瑞虹, 吕瑞英, 孔雀东南, 周, 马连良, 越升, 四季春, 韩林根, 张桂凤, 正调腔, 梁祝, 毛泽东, 李娃, 金香琴, 史济华, 江瑶]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范福泰</mainName>
    <names>[彭福林, 王福寿, 范福泰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>范继信</mainName>
    <names>[徐凌云, 赵五娘, 范继信, 苏昆, 汪传铃, 李慧娘, 张驴儿, 华传浩, 徐于权, 周伟沧, 邵传镛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茅威涛</mainName>
    <names>[刘询, 唐伯虎, 茅威涛, 卖油郎, 尹桂芳, 白玉兰, 宋普南, 梅花奖, 索妻·露真, 贾宝玉, 尹小芳, 西欧, 孔乙己, 邹士龙, 曹禺, 尹派, 张珙, 邓颖超, 鲁迅, 荆柯, 百花越, 咸亨, 茅腔]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茅胜奎</mainName>
    <names>[卓文君, 秦楼月, 张堂, 梁如龙, 茅胜奎, 傅全香, 石榴红, 魏王, 袁雪芬, 张桂凤, 尹, 陆文龙, 徐天红, 屈原, 范瑞娟, 吕福奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茹元俊</mainName>
    <names>[赵福喜, 黄, 孙盛云, 李金鸿, 史若虚, 籍贯, 张学浩, 王志刚, 茹元俊, 叶盛兰, 王连平, 王旭东, 张德华, 马玉英, 马云良, 崔希庸, 王立军, 周龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茹富兰</mainName>
    <names>[徐元珊, 张春孝, 茹元俊, 郭自勤, 俞, 杨长秀, 叶盛兰, 茹富, 茹富兰, 李景德, 高牧坤, 杨, 宋锋, 武生, 李光, 黄元庆, 杨小楼, 费世威]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茹富华</mainName>
    <names>[茹富华, 茹富兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茹桂林</mainName>
    <names>[杨三姐, 朱丽叶, 孙大娘, 向阳, ，, 李, 罗密欧, 张, 杨乃武, 左连成, 刘巧儿, 李三娘, 毛泽东, 白玉霜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茹秀臣</mainName>
    <names>[梅艳, 刘奎官, 周信芳, 萧何, 吴汉, 徐达, 崔文远, 俞凤岗, 张美英, 张树堂, 徐策, 吴汉之母, 郑庄公, 茹把, 茹秀臣, 刘石麟, 康春京, 王兰英, 茹拿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茹莱卿</mainName>
    <names>[梅兰, 穆柯寨, 茹阿四, 金仲仁, 花木兰, 俞菊笙, 杨隆, 董凤岩, 贺仁杰, 姚, 梅兰芳, 茹莱卿, 胡琴, 茹氏, 马连良, 于织, 杨隆寿, 杨小楼, 范福泰, 张洪林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>茹锡九</mainName>
    <names>[朱德芳, 茹富华, 张世年, 杨隆, 余玉琴, 张氏, 茹富兰, 张德华, 茹锡九, 左旋, 朱湘泉, 莫逆之交, 杨小楼, 盖叫天, 茹德荣, 茹富蕙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>荀令文</mainName>
    <names>[曾习]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>荀令莱</mainName>
    <names>[吕伟, 李薇华, 荀慧, 荀令莱, 张丽丽]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>荀令香</mainName>
    <names>[王同炎, 荀皑, 荀令香, 荣, 李丽, 王瑶卿, 程玉菁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>荀慧生</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 侯喜瑞, 李玉茹, 李玉芝, 吴素秋, 冯子和, 程一起, 毛世, 梅兰芳, 尚, 周信芳, 辛亥革命, 金淑华, 张正芳, 冀中, 谭小培, 李寿山, 高庆奎, 朱桂芳, 吴昌硕, 荀慧, 宋德珠, 王钟声, 李苦禅, 杨小楼, 刘鸿升, 陈桐云, 尚明珠, 吴纪敏, 王瑶卿, 厉慧敏, 程继先, 舒舍予, 王凤卿, 李薇华, 杨乃武, 宋长荣, 周, 赵, 李妙春, 王雪涛, 荀令莱, 三小一白]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>荆玉堂</mainName>
    <names>[张, 罗汉拳, 孙悟空]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>荣剑尘</mainName>
    <names>[刘嘉昌, 王决, 金钱莲, 梅兰, 燕乐升平, 卓二, 娘劝夫, 刘元, 谢舒扬, 后起, 罗江怨, 王佐, 李志鹏, 李镒山, 杨宝升, 芮芝, 乔太守, 经德, 润田, 杨大钧, 卖油郎, 金, 红门寺, 明永顺, 荣剑, 黄荣培, 李吉安, 荣, 和顺, 罗章, 武大郎, 程学文, 荣剑尘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>荣蝶仙</mainName>
    <names>[程饰, 王, 文亮, 李洪春, 王嫂, 梅兰芳, 招郎, 程砚, 荣, 荣蝶, 程砚秋, 程演, 何玉凤, 师门, 王明华, 谢母, 荣蝶仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有萧世佑的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧楷成</mainName>
    <names>[金华, 康子林, 萧楷成, 唐德彝, 萧派, 刘育三, 舒徐, 吴, 刘谌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧永康</mainName>
    <names>[汪永泰, 杨月楼, 萧小兰, 长荣, 程长庚, 卢胜奎, 谢，并, 胡喜禄, 江都, 长华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧浩然</mainName>
    <names>[宋桐斌, 邹应龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧润增</mainName>
    <names>[孙忠廉, 于雷, 茹富兰, 杨门女, 徐策, 王魁, 周信芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧润年</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 徐疾, 李慧芳, 杨修, 李玉茹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧润德</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 叶盛兰, 陈, 李德彬, 诸小生, 江世玉, 萧长华, 罗成]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧盛萱</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 赵啸澜, 叶映衬, 谭富英, 奚啸伯, 杜近芳, 李, 尤精, 杨宝森, 张春华, 尚, 李盛藻, 苏白, 张君秋, 钮骠, 叶盛兰, 王连平, 黄德华, 程砚秋, 高盛麟, 郑岩, 谭韵寿, 习武丑]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧英翔</mainName>
    <names>[萧英翔, 侯喜瑞之子]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>萧长华</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 侯喜瑞, 李春城, 张春孝, 苏白见, 宋, 谭富英, 王, 周长顺, 法门寺, 叶盛章, 萧长华, 田汉, 金祥瑞, 尚小云, 程长庚, 梅兰芳, 卢胜奎, 钮骠, 叶盛兰, 朱焕然, 张文远, 李世芳, 吴赖, 苏丑, 郭春山, 咸, 徐文波, 王楞仙, 杨鸣玉, 杨小楼, 刘鸿升, 奚啸伯, 杨月楼, 贾桂, 蒋干, 四郎, 孙, 班演娃, 李盛藻, 周幽王, 张君秋, 胡, 刘海粟, 杨国忠, 黄润甫, 马连良, 袁世海, 马富禄, 曹文奎, 袁国林, 孙岳, 温文, 宋万泰, 刘秀荣, 谭鑫培, 孟小冬, 茹富蕙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有萧长荣的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>葛兰</mainName>
    <names>[罗婷, 梅兰芳, 蒋介石, 容远菁, 琴, 黄飞然, 徐家匯, 卜万苍, 高福全, 刘亮华, 祝寿, 俞振飞, 叶冷竹, 王宝钏, 李梦熊, 陈芸, 梅派神髓, 国际, 葛兰, 李嫱, 李活影]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>葛彤</mainName>
    <names>[汪本贞, 李慕良, 袁世海, 葛彤, 刘吉典, 周子厚, 冯志孝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>葛绥之</mainName>
    <names>[陈永玲, 孙毓, 董玉玲, 毛世, 胡少安, 李慕良, 荀慧生, 葛绥之, 许翰英, 李宗义, 吕铭康, 郭少衡, 葛彤, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>董俊峰</mainName>
    <names>[胡靓, 侯喜瑞, 刘四, 武汉京, 韩金奎, 郝寿臣, 王振, 刘斌昆, 陈鹤峰, 黄玉, 周信芳, 赵君玉, 董少英, 裘桂仙, 杨瑞亭, 黄润甫, 刘筱衡, 刘鸿声, 董俊峰, 李七, 杨善华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>董圆圆</mainName>
    <names>[阎世善, 刘罗锅, 谢锐青, 李金鸿, 穆桂英, 张世年, 董圆圆, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>董少英</mainName>
    <names>[马四派, 刘邦, 班汉皋, 董俊峰, 陈鹤峰, 江夏, 谭余麒, 董少, 董少英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>董文华</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 李少春, 梅葆玖, 梅派, 班进京, 梅兰芳, 董文华, 红生稳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>董春柏</mainName>
    <names>[柏师徒, 董春柏, 沈金波, 李贵华, 马少波, 王魁, 刘谨, 班进京, 周信芳, 秦基伟, 华容, 徐俊华, 马谡, 王佐, 程十发, 薛将军, 鲁肃, 董春, 董景芬, 邓小平, 宋江, 殷宝忠, 徐啸东, 马歇尔, 红净, 曹操等, 董, 裘丽琳, 王金璐, 汪, 李英, 周信, 艾世菊, 唐韵笙, 张群, 陆义萍, 王卓青, 高盛麟, 刘异龙, 于文, 诸葛亮, 李师彬, 张广才, 方荣翔, 琴师高, 黄正勤, 王梦云, 徐策, 周恩来, 杨延昭, 俞振飞, 邹应龙, 常演, 张少楼, 毛, 马连良, 马永安, 严嵩, 董达子, 张鑫海]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>董湘昆</mainName>
    <names>[孙桂珍, 刘文斌, 董湘昆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>董瑶阶</mainName>
    <names>[李, 卓具, 潘巧云, 李老五, 田汉, 董和, 梅兰芳, 董瑶阶, 曹瑞莲, 董, 返汉, 黎元, 董改, 李春森, 阎惜姣, 董学演, 沙宜, 董在, 陈伯华, 曹相公]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>董维贤</mainName>
    <names>[徐斌寿, 董维贤, 曾名, 文学任, 方颐珍, 仲仁, 李洪春, 董维仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蒋健兰</mainName>
    <names>[刘乃崇, 蒋, 蒋健兰, 李笑, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 俞琳, 李宗林, 蒋彝, 李笑非, 李紫贵, 温家宝, 华君武, 张晖, 谢锐, 陈至立, 李铭瑞, 郭泽民, 许德珩, 周仁, 王瑶卿, 刘厚生, 袁世海, 金开芳, 袁国林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蒋叔岩</mainName>
    <names>[蒋阵风, 王素砚, 李克用, 施压其母, 宋石男, 凤祥, 蒋, 张彦堃, 白玉昆, 须生, 胡等, 张恨水, 张腾辉, 王少泉, 张, 吕洞, 蒋瑞亭, 俞凤岗, 徐悲鸿, 孙雁鹏, 文武, 欧阳予, 樊家树, 蒋家班, 李劼人, 张燕华, 拿波, 张写得, 张腾, 寇准, 四郎, 蒋叔岩, 叔岩, 蒋宝, 张耀廷, 蒋君玉, 卢树田, 郑历如, 严曦, 金钱利诱, 段丽君, 严嵩, 孙庞, 汤姆, 武生, 曹, 蒋云甫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蒋君稼</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 臧, 陈德霖, 蒋君稼, 朱琴心, 杨小楼, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蒋宏翔</mainName>
    <names>[蒋宏翔]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蒋轸庭</mainName>
    <names>[曹枢林, 罗枢平, 蒋轸庭, 李枢勋, 蒋昆, 蒋, 蒋轸龚, 代拉, 蒋介磊, 张枢润, 秦枢宝, 马轸华, 聂枢林, 李枢信]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蒋锡武</mainName>
    <names>[蒋锡武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蒋霭秉</mainName>
    <names>[王玉璞, 蒋霭秉, 谢铁骊, 尤继舜, 陈秀华, 谢晋, 张鑫海]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蒙显德</mainName>
    <names>[蒙显德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蓝文云</mainName>
    <names>[孙玉祥, 王玉敏, 砺中顿, 李多奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蔡俊</mainName>
    <names>[徐兰沅, 蔡俊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蔡宝华</mainName>
    <names>[王天柱, 张定边, 武文华, 尚, 梁山, 徐俊华, 秦晋, 莫十三, 申斥鲁, 纪美华, 华因脚, 周啸天, 蒙戏即, 崔秀芸, 班世超, 刘连伦, 郭宏华, 袁世海, 郭少安, 王富华, 唐泽芊, 杨富忠, 尚和玉, 方继斌, 李永华, 夏京, 杨波, 韩富信, 张元志, 刘武华, 蔡导演, 华口齿, 蔡宝, 李少春, 刘汉臣, 张春华, 李世芳, 黄天霸, 汪野航, 金贵公社, 毛世来, 华云龙, 吴革, 蔡宝华, 贺永华, 张绣, 杨延昭, 李韵章, 郭少, 李鸿章, 张秀华, 陈友谅, 何文进一角, 毕生, 吴侯为子, 韩长宝, 王吟秋, 高材生, 田菊林, 陆文龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蔡正仁</mainName>
    <names>[俞振飞, 周传瑛, 太白, 项, 蔡正仁, 沈传芷]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蔡淑卿</mainName>
    <names>[杨门女, 蔡淑卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蔡瑶铣</mainName>
    <names>[赵五娘, 文华, 蔡瑶铣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>蔡荣贵</mainName>
    <names>[蔡荣贵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛传钢</mainName>
    <names>[苏昆, 梁山伯, 班及后, 沈月, 梁冀, 曲友, 于杭, 薛传钢, 向曲友, 张敏, 马陵道·孙诈, 沈传锟, 李过, 江阴, 庞涓, 董卓, 刘传蘅, 汪传钤, 苏, 华传浩, 沈斌泉, 周传瑛, 吴义生, 曾离, 方洋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛固久</mainName>
    <names>[薛固久]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛小飞</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 魏含英, 魏调, 薛小飞, 薛, 邵小华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛月秋</mainName>
    <names>[刘师亮, 于川剧, 梅兰芳, 薛月秋, 莫道伶界, 辛亥革命, 张衡之, 乔装错]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛正康</mainName>
    <names>[陈桐云, 于关, 薛正康, 李蔷华, 陈鹤峰, 俞振飞, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛永年</mainName>
    <names>[胡锦涛, 姜昆, 马季, 蒲公英, 周恩来, 王光英, 范志强, 薛永年, 韩子康, 胡必达, 李先念, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛永康</mainName>
    <names>[薛永康]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛浩伟</mainName>
    <names>[四人帮, 薛长发, 王瑞芝, 法门寺, 曾祖薛, 陈秀华, 梅兰芳, 薛, 王先生, 张飞诸行, 薛自幼, 赵云, 谭, 谭富, 薛浩伟, 康氏, 杨宝, 简谱, 黄, 杨宝忠, 李多奎, 张凤祥, 苏, 何谓, 贾桂, 四郎, 吴越, 汪派戏, 薛宝善, 李白, 谭派戏, 刘备, 马连良, 杨, 满江红, 王玉蓉, 卓著, 李释戡, 梁祝, 于京剧, 曹, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>薛静珍</mainName>
    <names>[姚澄, 薛静珍, 孔繁森, 苏南集, 姚派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>虞俊芳</mainName>
    <names>[虞俊芳, 文成, 李淑君, 梁山伯, 白云生, 张毓雯, 李慧娘, 洪雪飞, 秋江, 梁山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>虞化龙</mainName>
    <names>[虞化龙, 梅兰芳, 梅葆玖]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁一灵</mainName>
    <names>[滑稽, 梁, 王小毛, 连珠, 鲍勃·霍甫, 袁国良, 马甲滑稽, 赵希希, 包三, 沈一呆, 杨笑峰, 金铃塔, 袁一灵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁世海</mainName>
    <names>[黄盖, 王德元, 王, 法门寺, 李少春, 袁小三, 李逵观赏, 叶盛章, 萧长华, 田汉, 梁山, 孙洪勋, 裘桂仙, 叶盛兰, 袁世, 马谡, 李世芳, 吴彦衡, 李逵, 许德义, 孙盛文, 郝寿臣, 杜近芳, 吴素英, 焦炳媛, 李盛藻, 王连平, 马彦祥, 袁世海, 马连良, 袁盛钟, 刘瑾, 李和, 李金泉, 曹操, 曹韵清, 李逵纯, 李广, 郭根, 吴用]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁世涌</mainName>
    <names>[袁世涌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁凤霞</mainName>
    <names>[袁凤霞, 李亿兰, 高亢, 于桂派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁国林</mainName>
    <names>[苏宝童, 陈永玲, 侯喜瑞, 侯喜, 黄, 沈三玉, 李春恒, 法门寺, 梁连柱, 宋富亭, 张盛禄, 刘奎官, 袁维祥, 朱老忠, 柏之毅, 甘宁, 高盛麟, 张志伯, 雷喜福, 武里, 刘瑾, 袁国林, 马踏, 郭文龙, 赵荣欣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁子明</mainName>
    <names>[袁子明, 子明, 袁少奎, 王楞仙, 龚翠兰, 刘春喜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁杏宝</mainName>
    <names>[袁杏宝, 程志馨, 黄桂秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁杰英</mainName>
    <names>[宋天忠, 王杰魁, 王凤山, 三杰, 袁杰英, 袁杰亭, 赵, 双厚坪, 袁杰武, 袁氏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁金凯</mainName>
    <names>[袁振林, 唐韵笙, 袁金绵, 李洪春, 迟月, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 朱宝康, 方颐珍, 曹玺彦, 李苦禅, 诸连顺, 奚啸伯, 袁派, 于京, 于津, 马连良, 袁金凯, 李宗义, 周信]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁金绵</mainName>
    <names>[丁永利, 袁盛文, 范宝亭, 沈三玉, 李金鸿, 诸连顺, 袁氏昆, 金绵, 袁金绵, 武净, 李洪春, 金凯昆, 袁金凯, 朱玉康, 武功, 曹玺彦, 曾德, 袁氏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁雪芬</mainName>
    <names>[白杨, 梁山伯, 马樟花, 白玉兰, 崔, 许广平, 田汉, 袁雪, 梅兰芳, 胡风, 周信芳, 张云霞, 淳朴, 周柏龄, 许, 范瑞娟, 田钟洛, 袁派, 袁雪芬, 梅朵, 吕瑞英, 程砚秋, 鲍金龙, 王实甫原, 梁祝, 鲁迅名, 吴努]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>袁韵宜</mainName>
    <names>[荀慧生, 骆驼, 马金凤, 穆桂英, 梅兰芳, 袁韵宜, 安贞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>裘世戎</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>裘云飞</mainName>
    <names>[千夫, 范, 张羽煮, 范进, 越剧, 裘云飞, 梁祝, 任舞美]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>裘盛戎</mainName>
    <names>[安平, 王博（, 陈国光, 郝派, 董庆民, 郑灿义, 李芝纲, 李小培, 周信芳, 张韵斌, 吕得, 马凤良, 张卫, 吴钰璋, 孙庆, 王福山, 姬少戎, 刘玉祥, 穆祥斌, 王顺成, 杨燕毅, 李七, 徐威, 张国华, 颜承富, 姚盛昊, 丁成戎, 孙裘, 陈正宏, 尚小云, 王福义, 张祖光, 李永红, 王海波, 冯立坤, 马济生, 宋昌林, 常春生, 叶庆先, 孟俊泉, 夏韵, 杨殿玺, 王文祉, 李成玉, 陆有宽, 邓沐玮, 霍福庆, 解立强, 陈汉文, 何永茂, 曹, 刘大可, 赵志远, 苏昆, 法门寺, 陈俊杰, 赵燕, 翁思可, 马子强, 梅兰芳, 赵氏, 李磊, 唐元才, 孙爱华, 李大申, 杨小楼, 黄景春, 李梦雄, 张啸宇, 李国瑞, 李祖龙, 李雨森, 于裘派, 杨树荣, 魏积军, 姚憾岳, 戴永琪, 李荣威, 马传盈, 张君秋, 张志清, 王震威, 郝庆海, 周春光, 李连元, 奚延宏, 陈长庆, 刘嘉欣, 曲凤翔, 桂伟桢, 梁敏通, 裘盛戎, 宋宝奎, 陈宏钧, 崔永明, 康万生, 张达发, 张宝志, 谭富英, 赵平, 刘学礼, 田立, 李欣, 于鸣奎, 高俊喜, 刘勇, 陈宝奎, 王正屏, 马子俊, 侯, 李幼奎, 杨博森, 时维, 李长春, 方荣翔, 王嘉庆, 郭洪昌, 孟广禄, 马连良, 张志良, 李兵, 李长, 侯连英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>裘继戎</mainName>
    <names>[马名骏, 王福来, 杰克逊, 杨振刚, 迈克·杰克逊, 王正屏, 裘继戎, 杨博森, 裘少戎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>裘绿琴</mainName>
    <names>[裘绿琴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>裴艳玲</mainName>
    <names>[裴艳玲, 郭师, 郭景春, 郭结为]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>言少朋</mainName>
    <names>[曾自组, 玛拉特, 毕, 张少楼, 王朗, 马连良, 于授徒, 桑园, 鲁肃, 贺后骂, 常]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>言慧珠</mainName>
    <names>[梁, 梅, 赵绮霞, 梅兰, 梅重登, 顾正秋, 习武旦, 梅兰芳, 杨二位, 高盛麟, 朱桂芳, 孙尚香, 阎岚秋, 赵光义, 言慧珠, 正式拜, 万古流芳, 苏, 梅派, 徐兰沅, 俞振飞, 卢, 杨]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>言菊朋</mainName>
    <names>[孙毓, 玛拉特, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 徐碧, 谭派, 班争聘, 谭, 郁以终, 桑园, 宋湛清, 孔明, 满腹, 南天, 陈彦衡, 梅合演, 高亮, 皮二六, 金福, 林学身, 王瑶卿, 毕, 谭嗓, 四郎, 王长, 李家载, 张少楼, 王幼, 马连良, 谭上, 贺后骂, 王幼卿, 曹, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>訾睿</mainName>
    <names>[訾睿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>詹世辅</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 李世芳, 刘禄, 马富禄, 杨宝森, 詹世辅, 刘喜益, 尚小云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>詹剑峰</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 郑奕奏, 胡奇, 韩信, 十一郎, 唐, 左雄, 郭建光, 孟同哥, 赵文, 雍正, 王连举, 张品, 董小狐饰, 王莲莲, 焦裕禄, 李, 刘捷, 胡奇明饰, 徐世英, 满江红, 詹剑峰, 陈春轩, 赵勇刚, 陆文龙, 穆章阿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>詹维刚</mainName>
    <names>[詹维刚, 王金龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>许仁敬</mainName>
    <names>[李玉和, 李志田, 焦裕禄, 陈规, 许仁敬, 李玉, 曹操, 何健, 陈玩惜, 张弘范]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>许彩金</mainName>
    <names>[陈四, 沈寿林, 刘传蘅, 赵五娘, 朱传茗, 王天仙, 于苏, 苏, 李三娘, 田氏, 丁兰荪, 许彩金, 张传芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>许湘生</mainName>
    <names>[谢锐青, 许湘生, 刘秀荣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>许爱茹</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>许盛玉</mainName>
    <names>[许盛玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>许金修</mainName>
    <names>[许金修]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>许金彩</mainName>
    <names>[尹树春, 梁山伯, 尹桂芳, 卖油郎, 陈素娥, 傅全香, 姚水娟, 屈原, 徐玉兰, 芳华, 许金彩, 何文秀·哭牌, 华越]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有诸世勤的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢双寿</mainName>
    <names>[谢, 胡琴, 黄正旦, 王月芳, 王兰香, 谢双寿, 谭鑫, 吴菱仙, 张耔仙, 戴韵芳, 王瑶卿, 双寿, 赵二宝, 陈啸云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢宝云</mainName>
    <names>[谢, 田宝琳, 陈金爵, 周长顺, 谢宝云, 谭鑫, 龚云甫, 陈氏, 谢配]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢平安</mainName>
    <names>[谢平安]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢景莘</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 李克用, 王蕙芳, 谭富英, 袁国, 荣誉, 莘, 梅兰芳, 谢景, 吴汉, 王佐, 谢景莘, 李奇, 勾践, 陆炳, 海光, 马派, 陈德霖, 奚啸伯, 李蔷华, 宋士杰, 莫成, 俞振飞, 杨宝森, 王叔铭, 四郎, 苏富恩, 胡琴, 苏武, 马连良, 马元亮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢涛</mainName>
    <names>[谢涛, 范进, 杨逸明, 文华, 白玉兰, 丁果, 梅花奖]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢群英</mainName>
    <names>[谢群英, 梅花奖, 刘夫人]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢许萍苏</mainName>
    <names>[谢许萍, 苏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢讽声</mainName>
    <names>[王凤来, 范哈哈, 蓬莱什, 王笑, 谢讽声, 徐琴艳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢锐青</mainName>
    <names>[谢锐青, 江汉, 王瑶卿, 董小宛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谢黛林</mainName>
    <names>[毛世来, 谢世, 杨宝森, 袁世海, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 谢黛林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谭凤元</mainName>
    <names>[谭文成, 朱宝明, 张蕴华, 谭凤元, 程久, 祁永, 刘宝光, 赵玉琮, 张, 谭派, 金受申, 华容, 马介甫, 孔雀东南, 谭伯儒, 谭文祥, 阳平, 张喜林, 溥叔明, 毛泽东, 赵玉明, 刘宝全, 张玉林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谭富英</mainName>
    <names>[王又宸, 崔俊臣, 钱金福, 寿永, 利索, 萧长华, 宋继亭, 周瑞安, 尚, 杨广, 荀慧生, 陈椿龄, 谭, 鲁肃, 朱桂芳, 谢师, 赵盾, 谭德氏, 连良, 严寒, 陈, 黄凤冢, 陈丽芳, 燕侠, 陈秀, 马, 宋洁贞, 武生, 凤珠, 鲁, 赵燕侠, 王蕙芳, 马宅, 归林, 朱琴心, 寿康, 尚小云, 郑笺, 谭派, 姜妙香, 张淇林, 谭小培, 富英, 桑园, 容整齐, 文武, 南天, 陈德霖, 小英, 苏, 俞振飞, 郝, 章遏云, 江青, 宋氏生, 胡, 谭宅, 雷喜福, 马富禄, 徐斌寿, 孙唱, 王幼卿, 徐延昭, 马上作揖, 曹, 周瑜, 翟富魁, 班社, 马连昆, 董其昌, 王长林, ）, 伊立, 法门寺, 白玉昆, 广德, 李龟年, 薛琼英, 崔, 巴骆, 梅兰芳, 徐碧, 玉林, 张, 王佐, 赵氏, 谭富, 徐碧云, 孔明, 叶春善, 杨四郎, 张作霖, 谭家, 宇宙锋, 潘安, 荀, 梅伯, 穆柯寨, 杨淑贤, 谭门, 郝寿臣, 杨云友, 姜志昭, 柳金蝉, 四郎, 张君秋, 舒畅, 姜志, 高纳麟, 尚和玉, 宋母即, 叶福海, 赵, 程玉菁, 裘盛戎, 司马伦, 杨盛春, 伍建, 唐韵笙, 谭富英, 孙秀, 李少春, 黄忠, 朱光祖, 谭小, 陈秀华, 赵云, 凤霞, 骆洪勋, 胡碧兰, 陈会, 梁小鸾, 挽住谭, 张园, 程婴, 谭鑫, 王泉奎, 王连浦, 富连成, 孟景侯, 程砚秋, 刘备, 寿昌, 马连良, 武功, 王琦, 三哥, 叶, 胡碧, 卢生, 陆文龙, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谭小培</mainName>
    <names>[庸庸碌碌, 王则昭, 谭五爷, 郝寿臣, 谭富英, 周恩来, 谭鑫, 王焉, 刘少奇, 王瑶卿, 秦琼, 尚小云, 余叔岩, 梅兰芳, 谭余, 左为, 徐兰, 谭, 谭小培, 谭富, 谭家承, 吴, 王琴生, 毛泽东, 曹, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谭晓令</mainName>
    <names>[谭晓令, 谭婉华, 赵葆秀, 李, 谭世秀, 杨韵清, 正式拜, 徐母骂, 迈克, 刁丽, 四郎, 杜, 王晶华, 吴江, 李鸣岩, 杨门女, 高牧坤, 李逵, 王玉敏, 岳母, 李金泉, 刘桂欣, 曹, 刘莉莉, 曹韵清]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谭茗心</mainName>
    <names>[梅葆玖, 阎桂祥, 巴金铃, 马祥麟, 张学敏, 于玉蘅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谭鑫培</mainName>
    <names>[张瑞英, 谭凤云, 沈庄之妹, 谭淑诚, 谭婉华, 孙菊仙, 习武, 谭韵龙, 谭元寿, 康；六子, 谭起家, 李世琦, 刘, 梅兰芳, 陈其美, 谭寿永, 黄兴, 谭韵扬, 张毓庭, 王九龄, 王佐, 习文武, 汪桂芬, 叶盛长, 高庆奎, 谭淑英, 谭世安, 谭长友, 杨小楼, 钱富川, 连良, 谭嘉乐, 梁管, 谭世秀, 李秀玲, 习, 谭国, 谭凤英, 郭元汾, 荣, 谭寿, 习净, 李秀英, 谭嘉, 刘春喜, 谭嘉祥, 谭凤珠, 李金泉, 贾洪林, 武生, 李鑫甫, 谭嘉祜, 谭嘉瑞, 谭盛英, 谭嘉荣, 杨盛春, 谭淑瑜, 禄, 谭豫德, 谭富英, 李氏, 谭嘉善, 谭世英, 谭秋萍, 习武旦, 谭少, 督军, 卢胜奎, 谭娜, 辛亥革命, 谭派, 谭春桐, 许荫, 吴彦衡, 习老生, 谭小培, 卢胜, 桑园, 侯幼云, 文武, 谭小英, 夏月润, 谭韵寿, 南天, 习丑, 李吉才, 谭凤霞, 谭寿昌, 李玉英, 谭晓令, 王月芳, 谭喜寿, 谭世强, 黎元洪, 谭鑫, 谭豫, 袁世凯, 李英商, 杨元, 常明, 小东, 吴润衡, 习武生, 黄陂, 谭二, 大夫, 冯瑞祥, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谷文月</mainName>
    <names>[杨三姐, 张秀云, 袁雪芬, 田嫂, 王丽京]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谷春章</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 张春孝, 谭富英, 杜近芳, 李少春, 慕海, 叶盛章, 朱光祖, 徐良, 许瀚英, 常演, 张春华, 梅兰芳, 蒋干后, 叶盛兰, 翟韵, 武丑, 袁世海, 李逵, 习武丑, 曹操, 姜铁麟, 秋江, 袁后]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有谷玉兰的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>谷秀荣</mainName>
    <names>[荣, 谷秀, 帅旦, 李瑞环]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贡敏</mainName>
    <names>[妈祖, 宋, 郑成功, 聂光炎, 刘维斌, 项, 赵琦彬, 张永祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贯大元</mainName>
    <names>[李春城, 王, 谭富英, 法门寺, 金桐, 杨韵清, 林, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 张荣奎, 徐慕云, 洪林, 谭派, 许荫, 李鸣岩, 尹星三, 王荣增, 高庆奎, 孔明, 刘砚芳, 徐宝芳, 张古愚, 贾洪, 绪正泰, 宋江, 尹培玺, 姨夫, 陈增堃, 魏克虞, 王瑶卿, 杨宝森, 徐玉清, 姚增禄, 贾丽川, 吴联奎, 孔雁, 苏武, 马连良, 班唱, 刘春喜, 孙岳, 贾洪林, 李鑫甫, 谭鑫培, 程玉菁, 刘景然, 四杰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贯涌</mainName>
    <names>[尚富霞, 刘木铎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贯盛习</mainName>
    <names>[陈永玲, 黄忠, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 舌战, 李世芳, 孔明均, 叶春善, 朱桂芳, 吴, 林树森, 金合, 曾请雷, 李世济, 富连成, 四郎, 李盛藻, 王凤卿, 张君秋, 盛习, 王玉蓉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贯紫林</mainName>
    <names>[谭派, 张, 盛吉, 孙维忠, 张氏, 王蕙芳, 俞步兰, 陈桂亭, 孙惠廷, 武生, 王怀卿, 连泉, 谭鑫培, 茹富蕙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贵俊卿</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>费文治</mainName>
    <names>[曾操琴, 李玉茹, 吕瑞明, 索天静, 费文治, 吕, 任枫, 李全振, 荀慧生, 叶盛兰, 周金莲, 琴师全, 万瑞兴, 费, 孙安动, 迟天, 江新, 向费, 卓文君, 魏少平, 李, 李和曾, 琴韵, 陈少霖, 江, 梅腔, 胡琴, 袁世海, 周, 李慧芳, 金田, 王玉敏, 江世玉, 李金泉, 李效正, 刘兰芝, 杨荣环, 何顺信, 赵燕侠, 唐韵笙, 凤凰, 魏莲芳, 谭富英, 丁至云, 李玉芝, 吴素秋, 王君笙, 西欧, 程腔, 孔雀东南飞, 徐文英, 崔学全, 詹天, 江汉, 魏光, 李多奎, 侯玉兰, 王泉奎, 吴清泉, 张裕德, 徐兰沅, 杨宝森, 纪玉良, 费君文, 毛, 牛郎, 王少楼, 李宗义, 李和, 魏国平, 王琴生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贺世忠</mainName>
    <names>[贺孝忠, 陈飞, 贺世, 吴素英, 二哥, 袁雪芬, 贺富忠, 刘建宽, 贺世忠, 贺国忠, 胡, 贺惠忠, 贺仁忠, 陈云雄, 杭越, 陈晓红, 越剧团, 陆文龙, 范瑞娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贺永华</mainName>
    <names>[李玉茹, 周信芳, 贺永华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贺玉钦</mainName>
    <names>[陈永玲, 程树强, 王铁侠, 杨春生, 贺玉钦, 武净, 张春华, 巴骆, 钦加盟, 贺玉, 胡为之, 郭玉昆, 舒建础, 厉慧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾世珍</mainName>
    <names>[贾世珍, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾丽云</mainName>
    <names>[贾正云, 贾丽云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾凤麟</mainName>
    <names>[任武功, 李吉来, 汪晓峰, 汪饰, 白玉昆, 贾饰, 贾凤麟, 刘备, 刘宏亮, 汪, 贾风麟, 赵云, 红星剧社, 赵松樵, 贾因]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾华</mainName>
    <names>[贾华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾多才</mainName>
    <names>[贾氏, 贾华, 赵春亮, 尤搭, 贾少才, 黄玉华, 李多奎, 王多寿, 魏虎, 寿春, 沈燕林, 吴素秋, 韩成, 陈母, 汪荣汉, 尚小云, 孙小华, 梅兰芳, 凤承东, 荀慧生, 曾搭, 孔雀东南, 刘鸣才, 荣春社, 贾多才, 高庆奎, 华歆, 荣春, 宋德珠, 玉壶冰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾少棠</mainName>
    <names>[贾少棠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾廷聚</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 唐派, 唐喜成, 朱元璋, 寇准, 张如岭, 张富相, 贾廷聚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾文龙</mainName>
    <names>[万金, 李天成, 贾文龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾普智</mainName>
    <names>[梁花侬, 奉天, 法门寺, 贾全家, 贾普智, 张学良, 贾鸿德, 石月明, 于京剧, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾有福</mainName>
    <names>[贾有福, 罗笑锋, 金华, 贾好笑]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾松龄</mainName>
    <names>[贾松龄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾祥瑞</mainName>
    <names>[贾丽川, 胡琴, 梅巧玲, 陈金雀, 贾洪林, 陈氏, 贾祥瑞, 胡琴著, 贾三, 贾祥凤, 刘兆奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾贤英</mainName>
    <names>[贾贤英, 王和霖, 刘炳权, 紧拉, 李]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾连芳</mainName>
    <names>[王杰魁, 杨家, 杨子, 宣武, 薛刚, 李鑫荃, 王起胜, 贾连芳, 雍正剑, 贾少芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>贾骏威</mainName>
    <names>[贾骏, 子龙, 曹俊麟, 郑派鼻祖, 李少春, 小白玉昆, 张派, 盛, 马猴, 郑派, 幸有贤, 王建斌, 张畹秋, 张派猴, 贾凤麟, 赵化南, 郑法祥, 贾骏威, 孙悟空]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赓金群</mainName>
    <names>[叶盛兰, 袁世海, 汪子, 杜近芳, 李玉茹, 李少春, 白玉薇, 尤熟, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵世忠</mainName>
    <names>[赵世忠, 张永熙, 谭伯儒, 赵振铎, 苏文茂]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵世璞</mainName>
    <names>[艾世菊, 李万春, 詹天, 尹月樵, 唐韵笙, 法门寺, 李, 焦麟昆, 汤晓梅, 毛世, 周仲博, 尚, 李春元, 赵世璞, 李麟童, 李世芳, 毕生, 袁世海, 李逵, 管韵华, 曹, 李七, 秦香, 陈世美]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵世璞</mainName>
    <names>[郑成功, 李岩, 四郎, 李盛藻, 梁山, 郑国, 陈喜兴, 赵世璞, 马连良, 王少楼, 曹, 胡盛岩]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵丽蓉</mainName>
    <names>[杨三姐, 乔太守, 刘姥姥, 程雪艳, 李, 杨母, 刘巧儿, 吴, 赵丽蓉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵俊良</mainName>
    <names>[赵俊良, 刘淑贞, 连珠, 彭子富, 汪忠直, 蔡芳, 刘罗锅, 杨乃武, 张木匠, 忆江南, 赵云, 琴腔, 赵文波, 侯世全, 明光, 王老虎, 曲剧, 夹竹桃, 普天乐]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵啸澜</mainName>
    <names>[赵啸澜, 王瑶卿, 尚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵培忠</mainName>
    <names>[卓浮, 赵培忠, 郝德元, 赵氏, 徐文缃]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵培鑫</mainName>
    <names>[魏莲芳, 赵, 赵培鑫, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵小星</mainName>
    <names>[赵小星, 曾获得, 穆桂英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵希希</mainName>
    <names>[刘春山, 赵希希, 赵玲, 赵云亭, 赵收徒, 丁怪怪, 盛呆呆, 范哈哈, 赵, 鲍乐乐, 袁一灵, 赵麟童]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵德勋</mainName>
    <names>[赵德勋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵文奎</mainName>
    <names>[于2007, 赵文奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵春芳</mainName>
    <names>[赵云鸣, 赵春芳, 陈化成, 杨飞飞, 丁国斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵晓岚</mainName>
    <names>[赵晓岚, 吕布, 袁小楼, 唐韵笙, 唐芝芳, 杨立贝, 冯秀红, 陈鹤峰, 李玉麟, 周推荐, 张文艳, 周信芳, 周啸天, 李秋萍, 尤擅, 阎惜姣, 雷喜福, 李占华, 厉慧良, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵桂元</mainName>
    <names>[朱琴心, 赵桂元, 王]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵桐光</mainName>
    <names>[赵桐光, 桑红林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵桐珊</mainName>
    <names>[李维康, 刘胡兰, 侯喜瑞, 李灵芝, 王熙凤, 李玉茹, 寿春, 狄英鸾, 赵桐珊, 陈和平, 刘长瑜, 汤小梅, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 赵君玉, 荀慧生, 张金凤, 崔秀英, 阎惜姣, 李永利, 高庆奎, 高旺, 周凤英, 艾美君, 王门, 诸葛亮, 崔灵芝, 孙尚香, 丁灵芝, 杨玉环, 杨秋玲, 阴狠, 梅玉配, 赵凌茹, 正乐, 陈彦衡, 谢锐青, 郎霞玉, 班后, 任灵, 王瑶卿, 田桂凤, 王小蓉, 薛金莲, 胡氏, 吕雉, 欧阳, 胡, 韩翠珠, 程砚秋, 马连良, 王氏, 王配演, 萧太, 刘秀荣, 赵庭玺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵正</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 张素英, 赵海俊, 曹宝荣, 魏寅初, 李亦平, 张可来, 赵正, 吴炳璋, 李逵, 王鹤文, 燕守平, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵炳啸</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 法门寺, 刘, 班进京, 胡传葵, 周信芳, 梁山, 马玉良, 荀慧生, 李砚秀, 张焕亭, 白家麟, 花月兰, 吴钰璋, 李, 伍子胥, 吴松岩, 柴野, 马长礼, 陈云超, 李慧芳, 徐东明, 厉慧良, 李七, 赵炳啸, 张润城, 赵燕侠, 谭富英, 吴述卿, 叶盛章, 孙毓敏, 张春华, 李洪春, 李元春, 钟, 梁再胜, 金少臣, 翁偶虹, 孟俊泉, 李长春, 吴子岩, 赵秉孝, 奚啸伯, 张继, 李多奎, 梅葆玖, 王泉奎, 金, 祁野耘, 李韵秋, 李世章, 杨宝森, 纪玉良, 李炳淑, 赵德芝, 刘建, 马德成, 李良, 李宗义, 赵松年, 杨家将, 孟良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵燕侠</mainName>
    <names>[班进, 赵燕侠, 里乡, 王, 谭富英, 赵燕, 梅兰芳, 赵小楼, 荀慧生, 李凌枫, 何佩华, 荀, 燕鸣京, 刘少奇, 班晋京, 杨宝森, 四郎, 褚玉香, 诸慨, 诸茹香, 马连良, 张雏燕, 赵, 诸, 毛泽东, 曹子]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵盛璧</mainName>
    <names>[赵盛璧, 于后台, 王连平, 王君连, 王喜秀, 武生, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵砚奎</mainName>
    <names>[米玉文, 秦玉良, 赵砚奎, 尚小云, 子赵, 张长林, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵继羹</mainName>
    <names>[赵济羹, 赵继羹, 王, 谭富英, 孙佐臣, 谭小培, 徐碧云, 李宗义, 蒋君稼, 朱琴心, 赵喇嘛, 赵, 梅雨田, 纪玉良, 张文涓]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵绮霞</mainName>
    <names>[朱凤桐, 孙毓敏, 董玉苓, 王晓临, 许翰英, 赵绮霞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵美英</mainName>
    <names>[赵美英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵芝香</mainName>
    <names>[赵芝香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵荣琛</mainName>
    <names>[程派后, ，, 郭际湘, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 程派, 程砚, 许伯明, 孙怡, 程砚秋, 赵荣琛, 贺后骂, 孙尚香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵贞玉</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 罗敷恨, 赵贞玉, 陈素真, 杜近芳, 宋淑云, 桑振君, 花木兰, 尚小云, 罗敷女, 红珊, 袁世海, 李素芹, 陈妙常]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵鸣深</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 赵彪, 赵鸣深, 李南, 李盛斌, 赵刚, 赵云升, 赵飞, 张鸣禄, 赵忠, 荀慧生, 吴彦衡, 杨宠尚, 李永利, 李桐春, 刘宗杨, 姜铁麟, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>赵鹏</mainName>
    <names>[薛宝琨, 周仓偷, 赵鹏, 马志明, 郑, 郑文昆, 王派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>路三宝</mainName>
    <names>[荀, 于连泉, 梅兰, 郝寿臣, 王瑶卿, 矫健, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 尚, 王派, 荀慧生, 邱庆, 臧岚光, 马德成, 邓霞姑, 谭鑫培, 黄润卿, 梅玉配]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>车锡伦</mainName>
    <names>[倪锺之, 赵景深, 蒋寅, 栋, 王欣夫, 曾冲破, 任中敏, 曲苑, 束缚, 王运熙, 鲍正鹄, 蒋天枢, 姜彬, 周正良, 明清各, 姜昆, 文本同, 关德, 朱东润, 徐沁君, 谢真茀]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>载涛</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 梁, 安天, 徐世, 张勋, 张淇林, 任翊卫, 王衔, 杨小楼, 国民]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>辛宝达</mainName>
    <names>[张荣兴, 李, 四郎, 鲁斎郎, 辛宝达, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>辜振甫</mainName>
    <names>[辜振, 叶光, 李宝春, 辜振甫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>达子红</mainName>
    <names>[苏武, 徐策, 马前, 黎明, 李月, 曹操, 高亢, 孟丽君]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>连丽如</mainName>
    <names>[康熙, 程咬, 李鑫荃, 唐, 朱元璋, 田连元, 贾建国, 单田芳, 程咬金, 刘兰芳, 宣武, 金大闹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>连笑昆</mainName>
    <names>[柳活, 昆, 连笑昆, 笑昆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>迟子俊</mainName>
    <names>[迟子俊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>迟小秋</mainName>
    <names>[王, 梁山伯, 于柔, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 迟小秋, 程派, 文联, 荣, 孔雀东南, 程砚秋, 程腔, 王吟秋, 贺后骂]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>迟景荣</mainName>
    <names>[荣, 张伯驹, 蓬莱, 杨小楼, 梅兰芳, 迟景荣, 秋江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>迟月亭</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 阎岚秋, 沈三元, 俞振庭, 张春孝, 孙毓堃, 梁连柱, 经奎, 马岱, 丁俊, 贾丽川, 万昭君, 柏之毅, 习老生, 王金璐, 迟月亭, 迟遇泉, 谭小培, 刘鸿声, 叶衬托, 红花之美, 富光, 孙悟空, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>逗乐</mainName>
    <names>[杨子春, 刘兰芳, 罗扬, 史琳, 井岗]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>逗笑</mainName>
    <names>[杨子春, 刘兰芳, 罗扬, 史琳, 井岗]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>逯兴才</mainName>
    <names>[周信芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邓笑灵</mainName>
    <names>[邓少白, 韩国庆, 邓笑灵, 邓波儿, 程笑亭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邓细</mainName>
    <names>[邓细, 梁, 姜志良, 荣生, 陆云飞, 邓细应, 罗品超, 白驹荣, 罗家宝, 廖侠怀, 罗家树, 林小群, 红线女, 何非凡, 马师曾, 邓树荣, 薛觉先, 谭玉真]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邢威明</mainName>
    <names>[唐韵笙, 李春城, 于西城, 唐, 白玉昆, 林, 谭派, 颜伯龙, 刘岩朋, 苏武牧, 李满天下, 诸葛亮, 王君直, 尤受, 李苦禅, 姜后, 胡女, 孙盛文, 尹月樵, 陈彦衡, 蔺相如, 赵桐栅, 迟滞, 罗汉收, 陈师, 边远, 田文玉, 李玉书, 姚, 王长, 苏武携, 陈远亭, 王晶华, 杨开慧, 袁寒, 王连平, 孔雁, 苏武, 于戏楼, 冯志孝, 孙岳, 杨韵青, 赵, 李鑫甫, 关雅侬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邢松岩</mainName>
    <names>[马派, 邢松岩, 苏武, 马连良, 王吟秋, 张仲翰, 刘盛通, 谦逊, 李洪春, 李金声, 李慕良, 王世续, 曹, 王吟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>那正鑫</mainName>
    <names>[孙权, 赵燕侠, 关正明, 傅饰, 唐韵笙, 赵桐珊, 邵林童, 裴元庆, 周信芳, 刘备由, 姜妙香, 王富刚, 李元霸, 赵云, 高登, 李如春, 苗先, 李万春, 叶赫那, 黄正勤, 宋宝罗, 孙明珠, 孙柏龄, 徐策, 言慧珠, 王泉奎, 杨宝森, 傅德, 胜春, 王正龙, 杨演出, 那正鑫, 王玉蓉, 李鸣盛, 马四立, 庞煜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邱凤翔</mainName>
    <names>[邱凤翔, 邱炳泉, 周凤文, 常演, 王小三, 周凤林, 于清]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邱富棠</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 赵喜魁, 郝寿臣, 宋起山, 经姐夫, 沈富贵, 刘连湘, 张连庭, 梅兰芳, 荀慧生, 姜妙香, 茹富兰, 秦腔郭, 马连良, 何连涛, 邱富棠, 贾顺成, 高庆奎, 尚和玉, 曾协助, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邱正坚</mainName>
    <names>[黎伙觉, 赵贯一, 周小燕, 王瑞芝, 陈圣杰, 马革顺, 马骏呜, 田磊, 陈大濩, 余叔岩, 李家载, 葛朝祉, 余慧清, 邱正坚, 刘曾复, 张少甫, 赵化南, 邱, 王珮瑜, 张桐, 陆富安]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邵增涛</mainName>
    <names>[孟祥光, 邵增涛, 顾存德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邵滨孙</mainName>
    <names>[于生计, 杨桂英, 刘英, 刁德一, 刘, 邵文滨, 周信芳, 罗汉, 孙创造, 唐寿, 杨乃武, 骆驼, 小念慈, 孙幼年, 孙成名]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邹功甫</mainName>
    <names>[陈志兰, 李世霖, 凤凰, 谭富英, ，, 李少春, 叶盛章, 张春华, 徐和才, 叶盛兰, 王旗, 习文武, 孙悟空, 李光, 玉皇大帝, 曹世才, 王颂忱, 张淑桂, 邹功甫, 周恩来, 李, 李和曾, 刘雪涛, 王泉奎, 四郎, 张元智, 李盛藻, 娄振奎, 王泊生, 张君秋, 江, 祥, 经马彦, 李慧芳, 冯志孝, 金田, 李宗义, 张岚, 江世玉, 李金泉, 徐和, 刘兰芝, 曹韵清]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>邹忠新</mainName>
    <names>[贾瞎子, 李月秋, 邹忠新, 孙洪云, 杨永昌, 邹忠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郎德沣</mainName>
    <names>[李培基, 郭荣起, 李金斗, 姜昆, 侯伯照, 陈文海, 蒋清奎, 贾鸿彬, 侯宝林, 侯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郎筠玉</mainName>
    <names>[聂莹, 梁山伯, 郎筠玉, 梅兰芳, 周信芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郑亦秋</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 谭富英, 李少春, 吉安直, 田汉, 梅兰芳, 刘奎官, 叶盛兰, 倩, 毛剑秋, 吉安, 李紫贵, 毛韵珂, 欧阳予, 江汉, 杜近芳, 刘奎童, 杜, 郑亦秋, 张君秋, 杨门女, 马连良, 袁世海, 郭沫若, 刘筱衡, 穆桂英, 王秀庭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郑岩</mainName>
    <names>[萧盛萱, 郑岩, 郑天宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郑文喜</mainName>
    <names>[张杰尧, 郑文喜, 郑平安]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郑星垣</mainName>
    <names>[侯永, 郑星垣, 尚小云, 郝寿臣, 郑每次]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郑永春</mainName>
    <names>[裴艳玲, 李兰亭, 张世麟, 郑永春, 郑玉华, 李元春, 郑承盛, 王金璐, 梁慧超, 于原籍, 赵云, 武生, 厉慧良, 李派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郑永蘅</mainName>
    <names>[李凌枫, 诸茹香, 郑曼晶, 赵绮霞, 何喜春, 李慧琴, 郑永蘅, 冯金芙, 焦菊隐, 林金, 吴富琴, 杨宝义]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郑玉华</mainName>
    <names>[林树森, 徐策, 周恩来, 关系特, 白玉昆, 郝少华, 刘少奇, 黄飞虎, 郑父, 林, 四郎, 梅兰芳, 郑玉华, 周信芳, 郑协助, 此白玉昆, 朱德, 郑饰, 文武, 郑和林, 郭志祥, 毛泽东, 孟小冬, 唐佩雯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郑秀兰</mainName>
    <names>[姚桂芳, 郑秀兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郝寿臣</mainName>
    <names>[郝寿山, 郝寿臣, 郝派, 郝寿, 梅兰芳, 王永昌, 黄润甫, 马连良, 袁世海, 王德正, 周和桐, 勾脸, 高庆奎, 李连仲, 李幼春, 曹, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郝德元</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 王春泰, 茅盾, 蒋, 王光美, 法门寺, 沈玉斌, 彭真请, 郝派, 曹操一角, 梅兰芳, 郝德元, 赵培忠, 元致信, 杨小楼, 王福来, 郝寿臣, 曹操改, 张伯苓, 吴幻荪, 吴晓铃, 梅葆玖, 王文俊, 刘少奇, 郝宅, 毛, 郝, 彭真, 袁世海, 周, 郝家, 马连良, 郝德, 卓孚, 丁秉鐩, 马小曼, 曹操, 李七, 顾维钧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郝秀洁</mainName>
    <names>[甄三, 薛仁贵, 郝派, 甄翠莲, 郝秀, 郝艳霞, 郝, 鲁班, 马, 郝秀洁, 马氏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郝莹</mainName>
    <names>[罗慧兰, 白玉玲, 郝莹, 张逸娟, 张振芳, 孙悟空, 宋丹菊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郝超</mainName>
    <names>[郝少宝, 郝超]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭三增</mainName>
    <names>[厉家班, 郭三增, 孟慧志, 郭三, 于武功, 孟燮卿, 武净, 张家口, 黄福天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭中昌</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 李世霖, 郭中昌, 张世麟, 丁至云, 王燮, 李, 王紫苓, 刘长瑜, 李少楼, 张春华, 邓沐玮, 王晶华, 周啸天, 孟, 石晓亮, 张克, 陈强, 郭立昌, 辕门, 魏伟, 马少良, 朱玉良, 王延庆, 袁世海, 张鸣起, 郭少安, 程正泰, 齐淑芳, 丁胜, 刘少, 王新玲, 厉慧良, 李莉, 张森林, 王立军, 王忠, 周铁豪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭云涛</mainName>
    <names>[郭效卿, 周恩来, 赵松樵, 骂杨, 郭春申, 于京剧, 郭韵申, 郭云涛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭仁鹏</mainName>
    <names>[郭仁鹏, 杨家, 李俊岚, 薛家, 梁山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭仲英</mainName>
    <names>[郭仲英, 王正屏, 郭坤泉, 李玉茹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭仲衡</mainName>
    <names>[王帽戏, 王琴侬, 侯喜瑞, 王瑶卿, 汪派, 王凤卿, 贺后骂, 董俊峰, 贾洪林, 黄中, 程玉菁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭仲钦</mainName>
    <names>[郭仲钦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭元汾</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 郭元汾, 谭富英, 奚啸伯, 黄钟大吕, 杨派须生, 郭春山, 杨宝森]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭元祥</mainName>
    <names>[郭元祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭坤泉</mainName>
    <names>[郭张, 郭仲英, 白玉艳, 武旦, 郭仲丽, 子郭, 郭秀, 张德俊, 杨瑞亭, 杨, 李逵, 郑法祥, 罗通, 曾用名, 郭坤泉, 仲春, 郭蝶, 周瑜, 李仲林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭培鑫</mainName>
    <names>[薛斌, 郭培鑫, 王振华, 杨珀, 王谦, 李鑫泉, 王慧斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭德纲</mainName>
    <names>[郭德纲, 侯耀文]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭效卿</mainName>
    <names>[高庆奎, 王瑶卿, 郭效卿, 梅兰芳, 郭效青, 郭云涛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭文龙</mainName>
    <names>[郭凤莲, 郭文龙, 郭锦华, 习武净]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭明霞</mainName>
    <names>[杨兴, 赵月蛾, 武则天, 法门寺, 舌, 王大夫, 郭腔, 杨安民, 秦腔, 张有弛, 淳朴, 赵梦桃, 郭韵, 田寿, 秦香莲, 习仲勋, 夏顶, 赵月娥, 李慧娘, 郭明霞, 张虹, 王宇雄, 屈原, 明霞, 王宝钏, 郭派, 李三娘, 张丽娜, 李玉梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭春山</mainName>
    <names>[艾世菊, 程继仙, 郭元祥, 陈德霖, 梅兰, 曹二庚, 刘斌昆, 萧长华, 皮黄, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 王龙, 荣春社, 张居, 唐玉, 张和元, 杨小楼, 张子, 孙安问]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭景春</mainName>
    <names>[裴艳玲, 郭, 郭景春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭正发</mainName>
    <names>[黄盖, 郭少亭, 郭正达, 郭坤, 魏虎, 赵高, 郭槐, 郭少, 郭正发, 郭蝶仙, 马谡, 孙家班, 张飞, 文武, 鲍自安, 郭家, 曹操, 宇宙锋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭玉昆</mainName>
    <names>[关正明, 郭玉琨, 李兰亭, 桂汉, 陈鹤峰, 江南美, 高德明, 郑子玉, 郭玉昆, 高盛麟, 郭永福, 董月山, 孙悟空, 杨菊萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭睿玥</mainName>
    <names>[许美玲, 张正芳, 李丽芳, 杨修, 张洵澎, 穆桂英, 马小曼, 王芝泉, 刘秀荣, 四郎, 曹操, 舒昌玉, 秦香, 郭睿玥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭立昌</mainName>
    <names>[郭立昌, 杨宝森, 王凤朝, 周子厚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭自勤</mainName>
    <names>[郭自勤, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭荣起</mainName>
    <names>[帅, 刘宝瑞, 郭瑞林, 朱相臣, 郭荣起, 王长友, 古董, 于俊波, 罗荣寿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭蓬莱</mainName>
    <names>[郭蓬莱, 樊志清, 庄子, 子弟会, 郭蓬, 郭达子, 王树云, 邱惠亭, 恩荣, 双绝, 王瑞常, 魏庆林, 冯茂]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭际湘</mainName>
    <names>[郭际湘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>郭鹭</mainName>
    <names>[郭鹭]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金不换</mainName>
    <names>[金灿灿, 钮骠, 东著名, 马金凤, 金不换, 穆桂英, 唐喜成, 金]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金仲仁</mainName>
    <names>[满汉, 王蕙芳, 张春孝, 洪维良, 金仲仁, 韩彦, 赵桐珊, 曹心泉, 李洪春, 柳湘莲, 朱维斌, 张, 荀慧生, 高吊, 谢世, 东交民, 尤金, 赵辅弼, 王世霞, 许德义, 张珙, 关维芳, 金维正, 安骥, 王楞仙, 胡同, 于维章, 苏维明, 董维贤, 王瑶卿, 杨廷顺, 姚增禄, 杨再兴, 荣, 荣蝶, 王维秋, 马连良, 马富禄, 马, 李德彬, 张春彦, 周维俊, 武功, 王维筠, 王金龙, 陈世科]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金佩芳</mainName>
    <names>[钱浩梁, 李维康, 金佩芳, 金玉林, 郭根森, 杨开慧]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金少山</mainName>
    <names>[李世民, 侯喜瑞, 王振, 伊立, 法门寺, 白玉昆, 周瑞安, 梅兰芳, 尚, 杨七郎, 张荣奎, 谢世, 马谡, 刘永, 吴广志, 迟急顿, 高旺, 李密, 杨淑英, 杨小楼, 茅庐, 司马懿, 郝寿臣, 王福山, 双斧, 陈少霖, 王瑶卿, 杨香翠, 娄振奎, 荣蝶, 黄润甫, 马武, 刘瑾, 王伯党, 何通, 李春林, 金少, 武生, 李七, 赵炳啸, 裘盛戎, 孟小冬, 包拯, 李刚, 黄盖, 李克用, 谭富英, 姚刚, 罗成, 韩乐卿, 姜妙香, 马趟子, 谢宝, 李逵, 翁偶虹, 李寿山, 侯, 于庆, 张飞, 姜尚, 张天龙, 赵文奎, 金大力, 李多奎, 谭鑫, 高何九, 王泉奎, 金霸王, 罗汉像, 郝（, 金终生, 杨氏为, 马连良, 朱素云, 屈兆, 韦久峰, 徐延昭, 焦赞, 谭鑫培, 孟良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金少臣</mainName>
    <names>[唐韵笙, 谭富英, 简净, 唐, 杨宝森, 刘, 张君秋, 王玉蓉, 金少臣, 蓝洪顺, 李宗义]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金幼实</mainName>
    <names>[杜国芝, 孙大伟, 李伯祥, 毛威, 范伟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金开芳</mainName>
    <names>[文联, 金开芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金慧君</mainName>
    <names>[帅, 白凤岩, 金慧君, 薛君良, 刘宝, 燕乐, 韩德泉, 华容, 刘派, 刘宝全]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金月梅</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金福田</mainName>
    <names>[金福田, 金, 马派, 李金泉, 苏武, 马连良, 王金璐, 金玉田]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金秀山</mainName>
    <names>[黄盖, 李克用, 王振, 法门寺, 西皮二, 穆派之俗, 颜怒, 徐彦昭, 刘瑾, 一朝龙, 何桂山, 郭厚斋, 裘派, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金素秋</mainName>
    <names>[金素秋, 鲁凝, 吴枫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金运贵</mainName>
    <names>[金运贵, 梁山伯, 金星扬, 王继芬, 刘秀卿, 姚恭林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金金奎</mainName>
    <names>[金铃, 郭兰英, 王桂兰, 张垣, 苏三, 卢世宽, 法门寺, 金喜京, 赵科甲, 金金奎, 蔡炳, 苏三唱, 盖天红, 尤金, 铡赵, 董士元, 牛桂英, 金金, 刘媒婆, 王久晨, 马武黑, 刘胜, 丁果仙, 苏, 梅降亵, 金铃魁, 太平红, 刘玉婵, 李子健, 赵步桥, 董士, 吉仙, 刘明山, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>金锡华</mainName>
    <names>[艾世菊, 王英, 阎世喜, 金锡华, 李玉茹, 孙正阳, 扈三娘, 李盛佐, 俞振飞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>鑫艳玲</mainName>
    <names>[刘翠屏, 王贵, 花淑兰, 海伦拜, 韩少云, 李香香, 打狗劝夫, 张振东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钟吉铨</mainName>
    <names>[钟吉铨, 王文川]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钟荣</mainName>
    <names>[关东, 尤彩云, 李玉茹, 师方昌, 梅兰芳, 荣芳, 钟荣, 祝英, 李丹林, 陈, 李世济, 周恩来, 程派琴, 王吟秋, 周斌秋, 赵荣琛, 熊承旭, 贺后骂, 毛泽东, 程玉菁, 朱企, 郑大同, 秦香, 于情]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钟鸣岐</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 梁, 侯喜瑞, 唐韵笙, 马超, ，, 刘炳文, 薛礼, 张靖祥, 杨元树, 刘连荣, 周信芳, 钟, 姜妙香, 张少春, 郭学文, 赵云, 张飞, 马（即, 王二鹏, 马技艺, 经钟, 钟鸣歧, 张振荣, 徐策, 奚啸伯, 王长荣, 李多奎, 刘斌昆, 丁占军, 慕名, 俞振飞, 王永运, 杨玉华, 钟喜玖, 程砚秋, 马连良, 王少楼, 王玉蓉, 钟鸣岐, 赖志宏, 李鸣盛, 宋国大, 薛平贵, 王宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钮凤华</mainName>
    <names>[钮凤华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钮承华</mainName>
    <names>[钮承华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钮淮华</mainName>
    <names>[朱光祖, 白清脆, 钮凤华, 鲁智深, 刁小三, 钮荣亮, 钮承华, 小云, 钮, 钮淮华, 茹耀秋, 栾平, 茹膝下]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钮荣亮</mainName>
    <names>[刁钻蛮, 钮荣亮, 尚小云, 李四广, 张驰, 钮, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钮骠</mainName>
    <names>[周贻白, 西德, 双职, 史若虚, 王瑶卿, 田汉, 洪母骂, 梅兰芳, 牛郎, 钮骠, 沈世华, 黄芝冈, 钮, 王传淞, 盖叫天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有钱元通的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钱吟梅</mainName>
    <names>[南别样, 滑稽, 周, 姚慕双, 玲玲, 曲协, 周柏春, 姚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钱启明</mainName>
    <names>[何顺信, 曾拜, 钱启明, 沈幼良, 沈玉斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钱培荣</mainName>
    <names>[钱培荣, 赵培鑫, 孟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钱妙花</mainName>
    <names>[陆长胜, 黄忠, 钱妙英, 袁雪芬, 吴汉, 卞学道一角, 吴昌顺, 张嘉祥, 盘夫索夫, 正德, 唐七, 李娃, 薛平贵, 宋江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钱浩梁</mainName>
    <names>[关正明, 李世霖, 沈三玉, 李少春, 李少, 李洪, 钱浩梁, 周信芳, 张正芳, 叶盛兰, 魏营, 孙正阳, 赵云, 钱正伦, 刘砚芳, 乔玄, 杜近芳, 李盛斌, 傅德, 李玉和, 茹富兰, 甘宁, 袁世海, 迟月亭, 卓著, 程正泰, 尚和玉, 武生, 武功, 和玉, 李玉, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钱玉寿</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 王琴侬, 钱金福, 刘雪涛, 钱元通, 陈氏, 王世续, 王寿常, 王凤卿, 陈嘉梁, 贾丽川, 张淇林, 梅巧玲, 王少卿, 洪, 谢宝云, 李砚侬, 洪轩, 钱世仪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钱英郁</mainName>
    <names>[钟泯, 班，并, 马, 吴琛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钱金福</mainName>
    <names>[刘砚亭, 安天, 钱金福, 谭鑫, 吴, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>钳韵宏</mainName>
    <names>[叶荫章, 侯喜瑞, 郭荣, 解宝, 桂伟, 马少波, 李世琦, 刘佳欣, 惠玉雯, 顾森, 郭妃, 胡传魁, 爱华, 李仲林, 孙盛文, 孙庆, 李瑞环, 宋富亭, 孙, 解珍, 李志民, 刘长, 孙敬修, 裘盛戎, 孙新, 秦香, 陈永玲, 姚刚, 叶盛章, 李砚萍, 张春华, 孙立, 裘桂仙, 刘秀, 何盛清, 马·连环套, 钳韵, 董春伯, 张飞, 韩小楼, 荣翔, 方荣翔, 李玉英, 郑文, 薛广福, 李德奎, 李多奎, 孙毓堃, 夏韵, 富连成, 裘, 欧阳, 徐戎奎, 张元奎, 孟广禄, 归韵, 夏韵龙, 徐延昭, 刘大可]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>锡子刚</mainName>
    <names>[杨宝忠, 王]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>闵玲娣</mainName>
    <names>[赵荣樵, 闵玲娣, 孙花满, 王玉敏, 王晓临, 田汉, 梅兰芳, 毛, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阎世善</mainName>
    <names>[阎世善, 于连泉, 凤凰, 谭富英, 郝喜伦, 李少春, 赵桐珊, 叶盛章, 东方红, 梅兰芳, 阎金福, 阎庆珍, 徐天元, 苏稚, 杨秋玲, 阎岚秋, 谢锐青, 武旦, 于京, 章遏云, 阎岚亭, 张君秋, 马连良, 刘喜益]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阎世喜</mainName>
    <names>[阎岚秋, 马宝刚, 魏莲芳, 法门寺, 陈彤, 李盛泉, 阎, 萧长华, 陈秀华, 华传浩, 张盛禄, 阎世, 朱光福, 阎庆林, 王龙, 陈富瑞, 阎世喜, 阎金福为旦角, 勾脸, 李盛佐]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阎宝泉</mainName>
    <names>[陈永玲, 魏莲芳, 李祥云, 张春孝, 叶盛章, 郑文科, 李洪春, 梅兰芳, 姜妙香, 叶盛兰, 谭小培, 王传淞, 王凤朝, 李吉来, 谢锐青, 江汉, 郝寿臣, 奚啸伯, 陈少霖, 马宗慧, 刘连香, 于京, 牛郎, 李桂春, 张德俊, 阎宝泉, 马德成, 雷喜福, 郭少安, 袁国林, 尚和玉, 松文明, 刘喜奎, 刘秀荣, 刘友林, 周子厚, 李克明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阎岚秋</mainName>
    <names>[阎岚秋, 高庆奎, 俞振庭, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阎庆林</mainName>
    <names>[阎庆林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阎秋霞</mainName>
    <names>[阎秋霞, 赵学义, 刘志光, 李世明, 韩德荣, 韩桂芬, 孙世甲, 白云鹏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阎笑儒</mainName>
    <names>[宋玉清, 马三立, 阎麻子, 连兴, 朱相臣, 双簧, 侯长喜, 陈永清, 骆玉笙, 曲艺杂, 阎笑儒, 陈永忠, 阎鸿斌, 班社]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阚永生</mainName>
    <names>[阚永生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阮兆辉</mainName>
    <names>[裴艳玲, 黄涛, 阮兆, 刘兆荣, 袁小田, 习武, 须生, 万幸, 恩, 赵氏, 李小龙, 孙悟空, 丁香耀]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阳友鹤</mainName>
    <names>[陈, 曹俊臣, 张德成, 文武, 陈翠屏, 秋江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>阿甲</mainName>
    <names>[凤凰, 谭鑫, 梁山, 高僧怀舟, 鲁迅, 宋景诗, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆义萍</mainName>
    <names>[赵晓岚, 魏莲芳, 李玉茹, 马宗慧, 陆义萍, 罗成, 程玉菁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆喜才</mainName>
    <names>[陆富来, 陆喜明, 武丑, 林工昆, 罗燕臣, 叶德风, 叶福海, 童，翻, 陆洪瑞, 韩乐卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆地园</mainName>
    <names>[马超博, 穆宇]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆希希</mainName>
    <names>[张樵侬, 朱培声, 周柏春, 鲍乐乐, 陆奇奇, 江笑笑, 吕笑峰, 王亚森, 张幻尔, 姚慕双, 红姑娘, 吴侬软, 唐笑飞, 杨笑峰, 杨华生, 陆希希, 袁一灵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆恺章</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆景春</mainName>
    <names>[荣春社, 陆景春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆杏林</mainName>
    <names>[张淇林, 陈德霖, 王金龙, 陆杏林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆素娟</mainName>
    <names>[马连昆, 阎岚秋, 朱千岁, 陆素娟, 法门寺, 汤勤, 梅剧, 卢沟桥, 徐兰沅, 于梅派, 贾桂, 贾宝玉, 梅兰芳, 赵宠, 刘连荣, 盛, 姜妙香, 穆居易, 朱桂芳, 梅剧团, 王金龙, 廉锦枫, 朱四十, 王少亭, 宇宙锋, 小生, 桂芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆金桂</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆锦娟</mainName>
    <names>[沈爱莲, 吕胜奎, 朱依萍, 袁浩, 姚水娟, 沈爱, 梁玉书, 李惠康, 陈芎据, 陈丕显, 越艺社, 金玉鉴, 路华, 潘伟异, 陈必华, 陆锦, 李蓉, 陆锦娟, 姜斌, 陈伯和, 叶琴芳, 徐汇, 胡凤英, 裴少俊, 潘祖德, 李蓉芳, 郑传鉴, 袁雪芬, 陈芎, 孙江林, 孟姜, 张数, 牛郎, 肖维璋, 李明任, 越剧团, 金龙, 盛燮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆锦花</mainName>
    <names>[百歌, 张福奎, 袁雪芬, 王魁, 张茵, 盘夫, 马樟, 张云霞, 荣, 余姚, 曾荣, 许金彩, 吕蒙正, 盘夫索夫, 王文娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陆长通</mainName>
    <names>[耿鸣义, 朱盛, 陆长通]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈世鼎</mainName>
    <names>[孟元伟, 陈世鼎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈书君</mainName>
    <names>[陈书君, 马少波, 俞振飞, 红叶富, 刘海粟, 马, 尹派, 张庚, 郭汉城]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈书舫</mainName>
    <names>[李, 谢文新, 陈书舫, 周企, 秋江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈仁义</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 陈仁义, 袁派, 李, 袁克勤, 刘易平]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈伯华</mainName>
    <names>[董瑶, 陈派, 胡小石, 何减, 刘本玉, 秦殿, 陈伯华, 李彩云, 赵女来, 宇宙锋, 梅家]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈光耀</mainName>
    <names>[陈光耀, 袁崇焕, 程婴, 赵氏, 王佐, 雷刚, 朱元璋, 郭建光, 张长城, 刘智远, 刘闯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈剑声</mainName>
    <names>[韩燕明, 陈杏葵, 卢轼, 谭珊珊, 许君汉, 叶少兰, 王小玲, 陈剑声, 朱庆祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈吟秋</mainName>
    <names>[陈, 李世济, 张派, 四郎, 梁山, 于玉蘅, 罗蕙兰, 李蔷, 陈吟秋, 赵荣琛, 贺后骂]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈喜兴</mainName>
    <names>[张九, 陈喜光, 陈喜兴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈四文</mainName>
    <names>[陈昌集, 陈, 陈昌明, 陈四文, 陈文, 二哥, 其二哥, 陈昌显, 陈妹然]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈圻</mainName>
    <names>[陈圻, 杨三姐, 金华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈增智</mainName>
    <names>[赵永刚, 陈增智, 李]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈士和</mainName>
    <names>[马八辈儿, 毛大福, 蒲松龄, 张擅长, 陈德本, 辛亥革命, 金受申, 张致兰, 陈士, 陈士和]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈大濩</mainName>
    <names>[黄祖, 黄祖宴, 王, ，, 李玉茹, 黄祖所, 何德能, 杨超, 陈友, 江夏见, 朱贪, 梅兰芳, 刘便遣, 郜氏, 陈福奎, 陈所利诱, 缪斌, 于花云, 孙安动, 朱元, 朱文逊, 刘表归, 李玉声, 刘伯温, 唐诗, 于谦, 陈大濩, 罗网, 陈宝琛, 刘表, 孙安, 陈友谅, 孙氏, 洪福齐, 王金璐, 王琏, 朱却, 陈友杰, 赵, 高音i, 曹, 郜氏两]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈娟娟</mainName>
    <names>[陈娟娟, 高甲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈宪章</mainName>
    <names>[陈宪章, 常香玉, 花木兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈富瑞</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 张达发, 钟馗, 张飞为, 吴大军, 陈松龄, 陈玉申, 吴洪发, 尚小云, 王世杰, 钟维德, 荀慧生, 陈治平, 苏盛义, 陈富瑞, 黄泥冈, 王少楼, 雷喜福, 高庆奎, 张飞, 丁俊学, 叶福海, 王群, 刘喜益, 路宽]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈寒柏</mainName>
    <names>[陈佩斯, 陈, 陈寒柏, 王敏, 侯宝林, 陈裕德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈小虬</mainName>
    <names>[四清, 刘月峰, 寿铭, 薛觉明, 陈, 白寄萍, 陈醒章, 富家公子, 郭禧志, 马鞭, 江话, 班主赖, 连篇累牍, 朱添, 韦剑芳, 马, 马师曾, 陈泰龙, 小木兰, 韦剑, 陈小虬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈少云</mainName>
    <names>[张信忠, 陈少云, 陈琳, 侯育臣, 明毓昆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈少五</mainName>
    <names>[陈少五]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈少棠</mainName>
    <names>[陈少棠, 薛腔, 黄玉奎, 赵氏, 梁荫棠, 雷刚, 武生, 师卢华, 卢启光]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈少舫</mainName>
    <names>[李文芳, 罗汉, 仇维仁, 辛俊德, 孙庞斗, 王传淞, 陈少舫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈少霖</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 李香匀, 侯喜瑞, 陈德霖, 魏莲芳, 王月芳, 谭富英, 奚啸伯, 李玉茹, 李, 陈少霖, 吴素秋, 陈秀华, 毛世, 于京, 四郎, 章遏云, 盛戎, 荀慧生, 孙盛武, 李世芳, 马连良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈平</mainName>
    <names>[郑兰香, 吴光煜, 马前, 陈平, 金华, 罗汉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈庆增</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 曾名, 雷京, 陈喜增, 陈少五, 徐盛昌, 徐兰沅, 杨宝森, 张盛禄, 梅兰芳, 王盛, 陈庆增]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈彦衡</mainName>
    <names>[谭及其, 陈彦衡, 杨宝忠, 王长林, 梅兰, 李佩卿, 陈彦, 钱金福, 谭伴奏, 梅雨田, 谭腔, 范秀轩, 谭外, 梅兰芳, 谭派, 胡琴, 王少卿, 孙春山, 谭, 陈设计, 陈门徒, 谭之神, 谭鑫培, 梅编]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈德霖</mainName>
    <names>[王琴侬, 高亮, 陈德霖, 王蕙芳, 班解散, 金福, 王瑶卿, 梅兰芳, 卢胜奎, 姜妙香, 田宝琳, 刘赶三, 陈金翠, 王楞仙, 杨小楼, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈志清</mainName>
    <names>[赵贯一, 陈德霖, 王瑞芝, 陈少霖, 陈志清, 梅兰芳, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈斌雨</mainName>
    <names>[周正荣, 俞振庭, 陈斌雨, 宋玉庆, 陈正岩, 程正泰, 汪正寰, 陈承荫, 郑正学, 陈世英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈智林</mainName>
    <names>[吴国前, 梅花奖, 吴, 陈智林, 勾践]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈松龄</mainName>
    <names>[陈富瑞, 陈松龄]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈桂寿</mainName>
    <names>[陈桂寿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈梁杰</mainName>
    <names>[陈三五, 陈梁杰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈楚蕙</mainName>
    <names>[杨廷芳, 任剑辉, 李少华, 董永, 周文伟, 曾荣, 孙安动, 陈楚蕙, 平中有奇, 罗剑郎, 正良, 孔雀东南, 曹翠娥, 张木津, 王金龙, 刘璋, 薛平贵, 红书宝, 范天鹏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈正柱</mainName>
    <names>[陈正柱, 孙悟空, 郑法祥, 李玉茹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈永玲</mainName>
    <names>[陈永玲, 王芸芳, 杨树伟, 吴海伦, 谭富英, 李玉茹, 朱世慧, 朱琴心, 魏海敏, 毛世, 张春华, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 尚, 吴美兰, 荀慧生, 许翰英, 马少良, 李世芳, 毛头, 宋德珠, 宇宙锋, 杨玉环, 荀, 朱胜丽, 穆柯寨, 孙毓堃, 梅葆玖, 李, 潘巧云, 梅派, 四郎, 张君秋, 赵金蓉, 王金璐, 陈志坚, 李宗义, 尚派, 薛亚萍, 秦香, 汪明荃]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈沫潮</mainName>
    <names>[刘庆, 梅安, 陈易永, 莫越, 莫叶, 梅安里, 陈抹潮]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈涌泉</mainName>
    <names>[李金斗, 陈涌泉, 侯宝, 禹婷杯, 谭伯儒]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈琦</mainName>
    <names>[金月升, 孔雀东南, 刘金定, 郭暧, 梁山伯, 丁赛君, 夏梦, 范瑞娟]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈盛泰</mainName>
    <names>[郑元, 陈金爵, 谭富英, 曾祖, 萧长华, 毛世, 王显, 陈寿峰, 李世芳, 陈富涛, 习老生, 陈寿彭, 孙男辈, 于万, 叶少兰, 张永远, 宋德珠, 夏永泉, 陈文瑞, 奚啸伯, 杨宝森, 赵慧笙, 李盛藻, 孙敬民, 陈嘉梁, 张君秋, 赵延寿, 梅巧玲, 马连良, 刘泽寰, 孙宝铭, 盛泰, 陈盛泰, 马玉琪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈盛荪</mainName>
    <names>[陈盛荪, 陈德霖, 陈君授]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈秀华</mainName>
    <names>[李桂春, 贾丽川, 周正荣, 陈喜奎, ，, 李少春, 陈秀华, 杨宝森, 刘宗杨, 梅葆玥, 孟小冬, 陈啸云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈笑风</mainName>
    <names>[李亚仙, 陈啸风, 李离, 郑元, 陈笑风]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈素真</mainName>
    <names>[樊粹庭, 陈素真, 叶含嫣, 陈玉亭, 梅兰芳, 王若瑜, 樊粹, 富平, 孙延德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈绍武</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 杨再兴, 陈绍武, 叶盛长, 徐良, 马嵬, 厉慧良, 赵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈美兰</mainName>
    <names>[陈美兰, 金华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈育明</mainName>
    <names>[陈育明, 徐德强, 陈素, 马师, 梁祝, 陈一帆, 陈素珍, 符祥辉, 陈德彬, 红线女]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈自强</mainName>
    <names>[刘胡兰, 荣, 陈, 范蠡献, 张弛, 梅暗香, 南唐, 肖十三, 魏超仁, 李后主, 鲁迅, 陈自强, 荣辱, 陈文达, 吴汉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈若梅</mainName>
    <names>[张海迪, 刘胡兰, 陈若梅]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈荫荣</mainName>
    <names>[杨家, 双厚, 吕梁, 黄巢, 唐, 曲协, 鲍福闯, 陈荫荣, 宣武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈蓉芳</mainName>
    <names>[陈嘉麟, 陈蓉芳, 梅兰芳, 陈正葆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈金莲</mainName>
    <names>[贾似道, 戚雅仙, 尹桂芳, 傅全香, 陈金莲, 越华, 张云标, 曾演, 姚水娟, 宋康王, 鲁智深, 张, 诸暨, 毕春芳, 何廷忠, 王老虎, 李艳芳, 刘秉义, 王文娟, 翁同龢, 张广才]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈金雀</mainName>
    <names>[陈煦棠, 梅巧玲, 陈寿峰, 陈连儿, 梅巧, 李翥刚, 陈金雀, 陈氏, 梅雨田]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈青远</mainName>
    <names>[帅, 脆, 安公子, 唐, 曹家, 曲协, 陈丽洁, 陈青远, 陈文起, 肖飞, 程咬金, 曹访, 陈平, 曹, 金断玉, 勾]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈颖</mainName>
    <names>[李亚仙, 李娃传, 武则天, 梁山伯, 越剧, 贾宝玉, 陈颖, 孔雀东南, 薛宝钗, 颜秀, 陈妙常, 李娃, 红娘, 刘兰芝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈鸣志</mainName>
    <names>[邓继增, 陈鸣志, 郑福山, 张永久]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈鹤峰</mainName>
    <names>[张翼鹏, 陈鹤峰, 周信芳, 周, 陈自荐, 陈结婚, 金镖, 荣记]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈鹤昆</mainName>
    <names>[徐建定, 张达发, 唐韵笙, 张远亭, 刘承祐, 高占祥, 周信芳, 王承恩, 陈鹤昆, 刘异龙, 刘韵芳, 燕饰, 董明艳, 魏朔峰, 张国斌, 李吉来, 吴君玉, 乌龙, 陈, 徐策, 班晋京, 刘斌昆, 柳瑞莲, 李桂春, 欧阳德, 董小宛, 陈三公, 赵老开]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陈鹤鸣</mainName>
    <names>[陈鹤鸣, 胡]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陶德安</mainName>
    <names>[荣明祥, 陶德安, 李雅樵, 杨少华, 陶德, 张巧珍, 惠然]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陶显庭</mainName>
    <names>[范, 郝振基, 王益友, 侯益隆, 李龟年, 钱宝珍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陶湘九</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 齐信英, 陶湘如, 马三立, 杨子, 郭瑞林, 唐, 荣舌战, 林海雪, 陶湘九, 秦琼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陶湘如</mainName>
    <names>[陶湘如, 张寿臣, 高德明]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>陶钝</mainName>
    <names>[文联, ，, 杨桂香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>雪艳琴</mainName>
    <names>[陈出新, 侯喜瑞, 杨宝忠, 黄世骧, 李少春, 王瑶卿, 周瑞安, 四郎, 雷峰塔, 梅兰芳, 杜丽云, 金笛仙, 张彩林, 马连良, 马旦, 谭富, 黄咏霓, 郭仲衡, 荀慧, 杜近, 得畹华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>雷喜福</mainName>
    <names>[方春, 侯喜瑞, 李春城, 谭富英, 金桐, 谭元寿, 张九抚, 蔡荣贵, 雷喜, 尚, 梅兰芳, 苏移, 荀慧生, 姜妙香, 于雷, 后昆, 叶春善, 赵松樵, 逯兴, 张九, 李十, 谭春仲, 仲皆故, 李, 雷振春, 陈国卿, 叶世长, 盛, 李盛藻, 程砚秋, 马连良, 雷喜福, 冯志孝, 李十父, 钟鸣岐, 孙岳, 董玉苓, 叶福海, 张喜福, 朱秉谦, 孟丽君]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>雷宁</mainName>
    <names>[张小吟, 曲靖, 金, 淄博国际, 雷宁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>霍德瑞</mainName>
    <names>[霍德瑞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>霍文元</mainName>
    <names>[霍文, 霍文元, 李庆喜, 霍明亮, 苏, 尚小云, 杨小楼, 梅兰芳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>露兰春</mainName>
    <names>[薛某, 严绮兰, 张文艳, 荣, 露兰春, 露兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>靓少佳</mainName>
    <names>[马福龙, 马超, 谭杰南, 苏, 赵子龙, 班当正, 严嵩, 叶田, 何芙莲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>靳学斌</mainName>
    <names>[袁慧琴, 叶少兰, 周仁, 罗成, 万春, 靳学斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>靳文山</mainName>
    <names>[叶派, 赵文奎, 沈玉才, 杜近芳, 沈玉, 黎秋觉, 王玉兰, 费文治, 曾收徒, 梅兰芳, 陈永珍, 张君秋, 胡, 彭世基, 叶盛兰, 杨门女, 李砚秀, 张吟滨, 李德山, 周, 陈盛荪, 李玉, 王凤朝, 盛兰, 夏永泉, 杨秋玲, 潘永玲, 沈曼华, 周文贵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有靳斌桐的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韦九峰</mainName>
    <names>[张宝, 韦九峰, 孙菊仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韦九峰</mainName>
    <names>[张宝, 韦九峰, 孙菊仙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韦雪生</mainName>
    <names>[玉林, 左右, 胡不归, 四功, 梁德阶, 韦雪生, 李炳峰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韩丽萍</mainName>
    <names>[韩丽萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韩乐卿</mainName>
    <names>[侯喜瑞, 韩金福, 韩乐卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韩俊卿</mainName>
    <names>[孔雀东南飞, 韩派, 韩月恒, 韩俊卿, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韩子康</mainName>
    <names>[关公战, 张杰尧, 韩稽祖, 阎王, 曲协, 韩子康, 秦琼, 梁山点, 韩康]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韩富信</mainName>
    <names>[张献忠, 从武戏, 侯喜瑞, 韩富, 董凤岩, 丁俊学, 杨小楼, 梅兰芳, 韩富信, 于春]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韩恩华</mainName>
    <names>[韩仲明, 王少卿, 梅, 韩恩华, 梅兰芳, 张君秋, 张学津]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韩盛信</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 黄, 韩盛信, 何冠奇, 李少春, 梁益鸣, 叶盛章, 韩明德, 武净, 张关正, 叶盛兰, 王连平, 舒畅, 李景春, 刘金泉, 李广仁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>顾传澜</mainName>
    <names>[沈斌泉, 金, 李渔原, 吴义生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>顾兆琳</mainName>
    <names>[顾兆琳]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>顾存德</mainName>
    <names>[顾存德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>顾正秋</mainName>
    <names>[关正明, 周正荣, 宋德, 谭富英, 梅兰芳, 张正芳, 宋德珠, 宇宙锋, 郑传鉴, 魏莲, 吴继兰, 胡少安, 四郎, 纪玉良, 吴富琴, 于金骅, 张君秋, 王宝钏, 董, 朱传茗, 马连良, 李金棠, 黄桂秋, 李宗义, 程正泰, 林肯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>顾竹君</mainName>
    <names>[张双勤, 王汝刚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>顾聆森</mainName>
    <names>[柯军, 宋河杯, 崔素, 苏剧, 顾聆森, 黎明, 唐伯虎智救, 吴石, 沈璟, 吴门, 李笠]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>顾铁华</mainName>
    <names>[俞门, 周志刚, 顾曲周郎, 甘贡, 西德, 郑传鉴, 蔡瑶铣, 薛正康, 张澍声, 李蔷华, 刘长瑜, 俞振飞, 张继青, 顾铁华, 俞派, 顾兆琳, 金兰, 张学津, 尚长荣, 倪传钺, 穆藕初]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>顾锡东</mainName>
    <names>[郭沫, 朱, 田歌, 顾锡东, 孙悟空, 毛泽东]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马兰鱼</mainName>
    <names>[尚小云, 李正敏, 马建翎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马勇</mainName>
    <names>[刘茂发, 陈永玲, 李鸣岩, 阎宝泉, 张火丁, 高牧坤, 马勇, 王金璐, 郑子, 杨春霞, 杨少春, 厉慧良, 刘越, 王凤朝, 茹, 刘玉泉, 马玉璋, 杨秋玲, 王晶华, 俞]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马博敏</mainName>
    <names>[马博敏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马增祥</mainName>
    <names>[陈荣启, 马岐, 马增祥]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马增蕙</mainName>
    <names>[刘洪元, 蒋月泉, 胡宝钧, 马增蕙, 马]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马季</mainName>
    <names>[马季, 刘宝瑞, 郭全宝, 马季相, 郭启儒, 侯宝林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马宗慧</mainName>
    <names>[鲍绮瑜, 杨月楼, 金碧艳, 白玉昆, 马宗慧, 王瑶卿, 安东, 刘琪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马富禄</mainName>
    <names>[包拯, 于连泉, 仲仁, 王, 谭富英, 法门寺, 赵桐珊, 白流利, 朱光祖, 王婆, 尚小云, 梅兰芳, 荀慧生, 叶盛兰, 高庆奎, 富禄, 文武, 刘媒婆, 班报散, 郭春山, 姜尚, 杨小楼, 梅玉配, 吴国太, 郝寿臣, 李多奎, 李, 贾桂, 陈氏, 蒋干, 四郎, 万氏, 马连良, 马富禄, 张春彦, 刘喜益, 孟良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马小曼</mainName>
    <names>[连良, 万寿无疆, 小曼, 梅兰, 马连良, 贾世珍, 李金鸿, 马, 梅葆玖, 葛沽, 马小曼, 赵德勋, 梅兰芳, 毛, 连里]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马少山</mainName>
    <names>[姜妙香, 金少, 后半生]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马少波</mainName>
    <names>[陈列室, 李瑞环, 马少波, 马志远, 苏扬, 马少]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马少良</mainName>
    <names>[马玉良, 曹世嘉, 李万春, 马少良, 马, 李少春, 程正泰, 郭仲麟, 徐盛昌, 厉慧良, 王伦, 李授]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马崇仁</mainName>
    <names>[马连良, 马崇仁, 何连涛, 马铮, 马伟民, 马俊男]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马师曾</mainName>
    <names>[马师曾]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马彦祥</mainName>
    <names>[洪深, 孟小茹, 李秀成, 周恩来, 卢沟桥, 田汉, 梁山, 马彦祥, 马彦, 曹禺, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马德禄</mainName>
    <names>[李德钖, 刘宝瑞, 马恩禄, 马, 郭荣起, 张寿臣, 马德禄, 玉德龙, 赵佩茹, 孙少林, 李所]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马志存</mainName>
    <names>[马志存, 赵传真, 杨少华, 王宏, 赵佩茹, 马洪升, 苏文茂, 刘亚津]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马慕容</mainName>
    <names>[慕荣, 阎秋霞, 刘派, 阎, 阎腔儿, 杨凤杰, 马慕容]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马敬伯</mainName>
    <names>[于春早, 马三立, 尤善, 马景伯, 马, 马敬伯]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马明捷</mainName>
    <names>[文联, 马明捷]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马最良</mainName>
    <names>[马氏五, 马派, 马最良, 史若虚, 安云武, 马连良, 马鸿良, 马, 鲁肃, 安居平, 李万, 白登云]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马樟花</mainName>
    <names>[郁, 田玉川, 马樟华, 梁山伯, 许仕林, 赵香佬, 徐元宰, 袁雪芬, 梁祝, 文武, 童生, 薛平贵]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马祥麟</mainName>
    <names>[荣庆, 马祥麟, 韩世昌, 刘美君, 侯, 马凤彩, 侯永奎, 徐惠如, 张毓文, 侯书田, 荣庆社, 张文娟, 王西征, 张美玲, 曲谱, 崔承喜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马秀英</mainName>
    <names>[王宝钏, 秦香莲, 马麟童, 顾凤英, 马秀英, 王玉环, 李翠莲, 王玉莲, 黄秀兰, 郑巧娇, 吴汉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马秋仙</mainName>
    <names>[晋剧, 王银柱, 郭兰英, 马秋仙, 四郎, 张家口]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马聚泉</mainName>
    <names>[牛振华, 曲艺, 马聚泉, 石富宽, 刘派, 马, 刘宝, 于乐亭, 包惠申, 刘宝全]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马莉莉</mainName>
    <names>[石筱英, 朱唇微启, 白杨, 归林, 柳腰, 马莉莉, 孙, 陈白露, 王盘声, 丁是娥, 马, 曹禺, 凌爱]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马超博</mainName>
    <names>[杨汝震, 袁世海, 蔡宝杰, 马, 穆宇, 祝元昆, 孙毓敏, 王如昆, 李金声, 尹培玺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马轸华</mainName>
    <names>[王枢祥, 于枢海, 蒋轸庭, 张寿臣, 张枢润, 马轸华, 焦德, 李金鳌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马连昆</mainName>
    <names>[连良, 马连昆, 马少昆, 雷喜, 周德威, 迟宝林, 杨演, 马连良, 王少, 马, 周济, 严嵩, 谭富, 侯渊, 连昆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马连良</mainName>
    <names>[王长林, 陈规陋, 良京, 孙菊仙, 秦琼, 茹莱卿, 周信芳, 蔡, 鲁肃, 叶春善, 连良, 马派, 令箭, 梁祠石, 双龙, 方拟, 梁益鸣, 王瑶卿, 张君秋, 马长礼, 苏武, 许田, 王和霖, 于唱, 冯志孝, 马, 贾洪林, 安居平, 马崇延, 马小曼, 马腔, 王慧如, 秦香, 赵燕侠, 谭富英, 马莉, 陈慧琏, 马萍秋, 谭派, 张宝玺, 乔玄, 周恩来, 金福, 谭鑫, 马崇恩, 王朗, 马连良, 宋庆龄, 张学津, 马崇智, 曹, 尤素福, 谭鑫培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马金凤</mainName>
    <names>[常青树, 翟彦身, 马金凤, 卢金凤, 杨八姐, 穆桂英, 太乙新]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马长礼</mainName>
    <names>[马连良, 谭富英, 马, 李少春, 荣春, 刘盛通, 杨子荣, 刁德一, 杨派]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马阿龙</mainName>
    <names>[杨门女, 陈真治, 李逵, 李良, 马阿龙, 张连祥, 贾君祥, 赵晶旋, 王德富, 李天王]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>马韵甫</mainName>
    <names>[马韵甫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>骆玉笙</mainName>
    <names>[于1989年, 骆玉笙, 刘派, 金嗓, 曹, 刘宝全]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高一帆</mainName>
    <names>[马连良, 周, 马, 关肃霜, 高一帆, 刘静影, 梁山]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高一鸣</mainName>
    <names>[李军, 成龙, 杨振言, 王瑞芝, 杨修, 陈平一, ，, 宋玉庆, 杨春霞, 孙毓敏, 陈秀华, 李慕良, 蔡正仁, 贾贤英, 尚长荣, 高一鸣, 查长生, 贾, 杨宝忠, 赵继羹, 蒋云仙, 陈立中, 夏慧华, 沈雁西, 徐兰沅, 曹雪芹, 宋长荣, 蒋大六子, 武正豪, 张学津, 杨友鹤, 蒋月泉, 汪本贞, 曹操, 吕剧, 陈伯华, 沈福庆, 郑板桥, 胡伴]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高三奎</mainName>
    <names>[高三奎, 刘汉臣, 赵广顺]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高世泰</mainName>
    <names>[高世泰, 张连廷]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高义龙</mainName>
    <names>[赵志刚, 高义龙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高元升</mainName>
    <names>[孙盛文, 杨宗保, 阎岚秋, 许蔼臣, 魏莲芳, 明奎, 郝喜伦, 李盛泉, 王喜秀, 薛丁山, 张收为, 冯富昆, 四郎, 王连平, 张师, 张连福, 张仲瀚, 雷喜福, 姚元秀, 张春彦, 高元升, 刘盛通, 李奇, 曹元弟, 刘秉义]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高华</mainName>
    <names>[吴小如, 沈云, 梁山伯, 唐, 曾拜, 柳迎春, 王瑶卿, 杨宝森, 周长华, 马昭仪, 梅兰芳, 程砚, 高华, 赵荣琛, 王克]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高喜玉</mainName>
    <names>[高喜玉, 罗燕臣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高士杰</mainName>
    <names>[刘砚芳, 孙高, 高士杰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高宝贤</mainName>
    <names>[李多, 朱砂痣, 谭富英, 谭鑫, 黄忠, 杨淑蕊, 谭元寿, 刘长江, 张君秋, 常代替, 马长礼, 张, 谭派, 张克, 郝庆海, 富英先, 赵氏, 宝贤, 谭, 富英, 高宝贤, 李七]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高家兰</mainName>
    <names>[高家兰, 文新, 曲协, 黄荣培]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高富权</mainName>
    <names>[班为, 李演, 马富禄, 方荣慈, 王后扮, 尚小云, 李甫春, 李盛藻, 弘门寺, 茹富蕙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高富远</mainName>
    <names>[寇, 张康侯, 高德禄, 张启洪, 李盛藻, 刘长生, 张君秋, 王龙, 钮骠, 叶盛兰, 张文远, 赵德芝, 李世芳, 荣春社, 马连良, 郑岩, 严嵩, 李寿山, 郑癫仙, 华歆, 饰驴夫, 高富远, 张士贵, 杨小楼]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高少亭</mainName>
    <names>[唐赛儿, 张世麟, 奉天, 唐, 方鸣珍, 孙伯岩, 高丽君, 梁山, 唐派, 李曾春, 刘俊文, 吴, 惠民, 冯荣焕, 胡鸣忠, 焦麟昆, 荣久, 盛戎之韵, 金碧玉, 张宝仲, 钟改, 王云, 袁世海, 马, 裘盛戎, 沈阳传, 秦香, 洪儒老, 陆战, 袁, 高大魁, 张天保, 王, 董跃青, 李德春, 王富岩, 谭派, 安东, 崔蕴芳, 李富友, 关鸣林, 高少亭, 高亭, 孙俊生, 随赵, 平（京, 李少楼, 江青, 田老, 马连良, 唐韵, 赵家]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高庆奎</mainName>
    <names>[俞振庭, 须生, 谭派, 刘生有, 晋林, 高盛麟, 晋昌, 高庆奎, 龚云甫, 晋涛, 高世泰, 沈华轩, 郝寿臣, 李, 谭鑫, 红肿, 富连成, 晋元, 李盛藻, 虞, 马连良, 高士杰, 刘鸿声, 马少襄, 范钧宏, 李鑫甫, 王仲亭, 曾]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高建礼</mainName>
    <names>[曾拜, 刘斌昆, 耿明义, 陈富瑞, 荣春社, 李甫春, 秦香, 刘斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>梨园百年琐记目前还没有高德松的介绍。如果您有其介绍</mainName>
    <names>[]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高文翰</mainName>
    <names>[刘俊英, 程玉英, 丁果仙, 张元秀, 孙膑, 秦琼, 高门九, 刘秀, 刘玉柱, 刘备, 盖天红, 马连良, 乔玉仙, 高文翰, 诸葛亮, 张家口, 唐寅, 宋江]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高明亮</mainName>
    <names>[李万春, 富连成, 李洪春, 汪子良, 奚啸伯, 王玉蓉, 盖叫天]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高步云</mainName>
    <names>[周立, 宋词, 唐, 小泉, 毛泽东, 任华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高永琦</mainName>
    <names>[杨荣环, 狄青, 田鸿, 衡水军, 李铁英, 孙荣蕙, 李玉茹, 刘英堃, 文天, 李洪春, 曹艺斌, 尚小云, 毛朋, 李庆春, 范进, 鲁肃, 宋德珠, 李仲林, 徐策, 奚啸伯, 班与, 刁德一, 奚, 时荣章, 马又良, 满江红, 吴小亭, 金刚]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高玉倩</mainName>
    <names>[于连泉, 高亮, 凤凰, 李, 王瑶卿, 韩世昌, 程玉菁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高百岁</mainName>
    <names>[关正明, 李正义, 洪深, 徐策, 陈鹤峰, 田汉, 梅兰芳, 周信芳, 汪派戏, 欧阳, 华容, 郭玉昆, 刘派戏, 高盛麟, 欧阳予]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高盛虹</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 高盛虹, 朱盛, 宋起山, 郝喜伦, 李少春, 韩昌, 叶盛章, 徐天, 梅兰芳, 李盛藻, 王连平, 袁世海, 贾顺, 高庆奎, 刘喜益]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高盛麟</mainName>
    <names>[杨盛春, 帅, 唐韵笙, 倪海天, 丁震春, 郑成功, 谭富英, 李玉茹, 李少春, 叶盛章, 谭元寿, 杨少春, 茹元俊, 李洪春, 尚, 梅兰芳, 苗胜春, 苏移, 周信芳, 华容, 梁斌, 高盛麟, 赵云, 王鸿寿, 刘砚芳, 邹婉华, 杨小楼, 盛字科, 盖叫天, 高世泰, 李万春, 刘慧, 武汉京, 奚啸伯, 杜近芳, 李盛斌, 杨宝森, 杨派, 刘子蔚, 俞, 江, 王连平, 袁世海, 马连良, 马富禄, 吴小如语, 李可, 杨亲自, 厉慧良, 武生, 程永龙, 裘盛戎, 任, 刘于]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高福安</mainName>
    <names>[高福安]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高秀敏</mainName>
    <names>[丁香, 高秀敏, 刘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高秀英</mainName>
    <names>[吴蕙明, 李, 祝荣娟, 范春奎, 徐秀芳, 高亢, 徐秀, 高秀英]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高红梅</mainName>
    <names>[王继珠, 杨门女, 马帅, 张洵澎, 杨春霞, 王芝泉, 刘秀荣, 舒昌玉]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高绍清</mainName>
    <names>[高绍清, 杨立德]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高维儒</mainName>
    <names>[吴铁庵, 李忆兰, 于维章]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高维廉</mainName>
    <names>[荀慧, 高维廉, 武汉京, 金仲仁, 李少春, 张君秋]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高美芬</mainName>
    <names>[逸夫, 高美芬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高联奎</mainName>
    <names>[琴音雄, 唐韵笙, 高联奎, 刘鸿声, 高庆奎, 贾洪林, 曹, 谭鑫培, 王凤卿]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高聘卿</mainName>
    <names>[艾世菊, 谭富英, 李少春, 吴素秋, 毛世, 韩世昌, 高亲自, 荀慧生, 姜妙香, 李世芳, 高聘卿, 王金城, 周喜增, 顾珏荪, 慎昌洋, 宋德珠, 赵佩茹, 南天, 刘宝全, 杨菊秋, 郦缦云, 秦凤云, 李万春, 吴喜年, 孟广亨, 李妙兰, 奚啸伯, 李多奎, 王泉奎, 陈少霖, 徐兰沅, 万啸甫, 陈远亭, 南铁生, 周啸天, 王佩臣, 周大文, 陈丽芳, 诸茹香, 马连良, 马德成, 雷喜福, 马富禄, 马桩, 张吾翼, 茹富蕙]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高英培</mainName>
    <names>[四人帮, 高英, 周德山, 孟凡贵, 高英培, 赵佩茹, 常宝霖, 范振钰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高连甲</mainName>
    <names>[秦腔, 韩昌, 何连涛, 王福寿, 姚增禄, 李]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高雪樵</mainName>
    <names>[唐韵笙, 李吉瑞, 高庆奎]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高韵笙</mainName>
    <names>[王连平, 高氏, 高盛麟, 高庆奎, 郭金光]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>高鹤年</mainName>
    <names>[张蓉华, 赵, 梁一鸣, 李玉, 林海雪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏喜奎</mainName>
    <names>[柳树井, 越红, 奉天, 曹保禄, 曹宝禄, 刘宝, 魏喜奎, 马少波, 李大成, 金万昌, 罗汉, 王佩臣, 魏派大鼓, 杨乃武, 成奉天, 曲当, 魏永富, 曹, 刘宝全]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏小云</mainName>
    <names>[柳文俊, 刘军, 袁绍庆, 尹树春, 梁山伯, 袁师督, 袁雪芬, 竺焕泉, 林黛英, 张, 魏小云, 越艺社, 陈苗仙, 金大郎, 张秋萍, 全香, 陈世美]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏希云</mainName>
    <names>[乔玉泉, 于连泉, 王景福, 魏希云, 魏三, 王派, 章晓珊, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏承武</mainName>
    <names>[魏承武]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏振山</mainName>
    <names>[马派, 梅派戏, 陈永玲, 华乐, 陈, 谭富英, 马最良, 王震, 梅派, 张派, 尚小云, 张君秋, 张, 金兰京, 魏振山, 苏武, 马连良, 赵氏, 马, 诸葛亮, 魏庆坡]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏文亮</mainName>
    <names>[广采, 魏文亮, 张文斌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏文华</mainName>
    <names>[杨八姐, 魏文华, ，, 张文彬, 曹]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏朔峰</mainName>
    <names>[魏朔峰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏筱灵</mainName>
    <names>[红豆子, 魏筱灵, 林, 红线女, 袁小田, 马师]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏莲芳</mainName>
    <names>[荀慧生, 李万春, 于连泉, 蓝月春, 魏莲芳, 王少楼, 杨春霞, 王瑶卿, 杨宝森, 经梅, 梅兰芳, 杨小楼, 魏永发, 李炳淑, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏连升</mainName>
    <names>[魏连升, 南天, 何达子, 金钢钻]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>魏龙豪</mainName>
    <names>[吴兆南, 王静波, 周志泉, 魏龙豪, 孙玉鑫]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>鲍吉祥</mainName>
    <names>[刘喜魁, 法门寺, 金仲仁, 梅兰芳, 鲍吉祥, 张苍, 谭小培, 鲍秋文, 杨隆寿, 杨小楼, 杨合录, 宋国士, 郝寿臣, 华慧, 阎兰秋, 王瑶卿, 鲍福山, 杨宝森, 四郎, 陈唐, 王世英, 王凤卿, 潘必, 贾丽川, 张德俊, 刘备, 马连良, 马德成, 宋王, 迟月亭, 钟鸣岐, 李宗义, 尚和玉, 刘秉义, 薛平贵, 马云樵, 孟小冬]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>鲍桂山</mainName>
    <names>[乔玉泉, 杨伴奏, 沈大, 郝玉庆, 崔又春, 刘, 郝春年, 鲍锟, 罗文瑞, 侯双印, 张长保, 鲍锐, 杨小楼, 鲜克, 杜兆培, 胡保立, 胡同, 鲍代打, 安天, 班小, 沈立, 李, 万寿, 俞菊笙, 荣丽娟, 靳文清, 杨猴演, 刘喜恩, 桂恒, 路西, 鲍桂山, 杨司击, 成竹, 鲍振山子, 马连良, 谭竹坡, 徐桂明, 张得林, 白登云, 崔禄, 鲍盛]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>鲍绮瑜</mainName>
    <names>[鲍绮瑜, 赵桐珊, 鲍绮, 萧太, 乌兰夫, 巴林怒火, 程玉菁, 于玉蘅, 梅林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>鲜牡丹</mainName>
    <names>[戴国恒, 戴福铸, 张学良, 吴芷香, 唐福广]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>麦炳荣</mainName>
    <names>[陈塘, 于氏, 刘亚葵, 于利, 于素, 陈秀云, 谭兰卿, 梁钟, 梁醒]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄三雄</mainName>
    <names>[沙二巴, 黄三雄, 双奎, 戴四, 刘赶三, 叔敏, 和春, 高腔恩, 杨鸣玉, 王松林]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄丽珠</mainName>
    <names>[李鸣岩, 杨门女, 李逵, 吕艳霞, 赵葆秀, 郑子, 张岚, 茹, 黄丽珠, 王晶华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄俊卿</mainName>
    <names>[黄俊雄, 黄俊卿, 黄文郎, 黄海岱]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄儒秀</mainName>
    <names>[李双双, 陈素真, 韩信, 寇准, 孙喜旺, 郑金玉, 鲁西南, 赵义庭, 胥, 伍子, 黄娃, 赵云, 帅生, 于希同, 周瑜]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄元庆</mainName>
    <names>[阎岚秋, 秦英, 马剧团, 叶盛章, 萧长华, 焦菊隐, 武松, 杨宝森, 叶盛兰, 王连平, 茹富兰, 马连良, 田演, 尚和玉, 刘喜益]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄兆欣</mainName>
    <names>[孟月, 罗敷, 田氏, 刘三妹, 中正, 杨顺清, 程砚秋, 国立, 李文敏, 于以腔, 李孟云, 金刚, 曹, 朱锦荣, 王紫稼, 黄兆欣]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄吉安</mainName>
    <names>[岳飞, 晏娥逾, 周恩来, 马邈, 凌云, 黄吉, 罗贯中, 辛亥革命, 毛泽东, 黄吉安, 黄本]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄天麟</mainName>
    <names>[黄天麟, 李慧芳, 徐兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄孝慈</mainName>
    <names>[关正明, 李香匀, 赵桐栅, 杜近芳, 周恩来, 黄孝慈, 梅花奖, 张世兰, 师承华, 班进京, 骆驼, 文华, 红菱艳, 董小宛, 陈伯华]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄小秋</mainName>
    <names>[黄正勤, 朱楚善, ，, 黄小蝶, 徐小玉, 廉锦枫, 甘乃迪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄异庵</mainName>
    <names>[金石俱佳, 黄异庵, 刘介玉, 周, 黄易安, 易安, 朱兰庵, 苏]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄德华</mainName>
    <names>[艾世菊, 郭元祥, 梅兰, 法门寺, 梅葆玖, 谭元寿, 罗文奎, 汪荣汉, 梅兰芳, 张, 孙盛武, 黄德华, 冯玉增, 袁世海, 张学津, 叶少兰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄文俊</mainName>
    <names>[黄文俊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄月山</mainName>
    <names>[黄胖, 宋, 李吉瑞, 李巧林, 巴骆, 田际, 李桂春, 马德成, 陈芳水, 李嫁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄柏雪</mainName>
    <names>[梅兰芳, 黄柏雪]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄正勤</mainName>
    <names>[黄正勤, 尤, 王玉蓉, 宋士杰, 俞振飞, 王魁, 田伦]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄润甫</mainName>
    <names>[马踏, 张飞, 董俊峰, 黄, 李逵性, 李佩, 黄润甫, 贾家楼, 郝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄玉华</mainName>
    <names>[徐佩玲, 黄玉华, 宋, 赵琳, 叶盛章, 黄老之亲, 王瑶卿, 黄克, 后凡, 周企何, 欧阳慧, 李世英, 周和桐, 王倍, 黄调, 朱桂芳, 黄掌柜, 朱斌, 秋江, 李凌峰]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄益安</mainName>
    <names>[黄益安, 宋益, 梁益鸣, 宋益俊]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄粦传</mainName>
    <names>[田汉, 曲终, 梅兰芳, 龙岩, 韩文公, 班纷纷, 刘少奇, 许瑞伯, 黄粦, 叶剑英, 毛泽东, 李祝三, 云遮月, 黄粦传, 朱德, 谢宝, 黄仪, 诸葛亮, 齐王点, 勾践, 罗恒报, 黄育华, 李祝, 黄桂珠, 洪亮, 周恩来, 曹炳进, 隆文, 欧阳, 马连, 蔡楚生, 马连良, 范思湘, 郭, 曹, 红书宝]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄良冬</mainName>
    <names>[黄良冬, 文华, 符传杰, 吴多东, 吴多军, 韩文华, 韩海萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄超伦</mainName>
    <names>[秦香莲, 巴音像, 徐九, 霍光, 夏里, 王允, 黄粦传, 王丞相, 黄超伦, 范开盛, 黄派, 宋王, 黄粦, 孔明, 太平洋, 曹, 杨令公]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄金陆</mainName>
    <names>[梁小鸾, 张素英, 沈玉, 李慧娘, 曹宝荣, 杨宝森, 赵建华, 洪母骂, 杨派, 周啸天, 张君秋, 胡琴, 马连良, 赵荣琛, 陈琪, 黄金陆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄铁良</mainName>
    <names>[张弛, 黄铁良]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黄静慧</mainName>
    <names>[梅兰珍, 双达杯, 黄静慧, 姬获无, 王品素]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黎中城</mainName>
    <names>[成龙, 梁波, 扈三娘, 王涌石, 董绍渝, 王炼, 王树元, 刘梦德, 文华, 谢雨青, 杨毓珉, 陈文华, 王祖鸿, 程惟, 史碑鉴, 王英, 周玑璋, 郑, 赵莱静, 周, 汪, 曹禹, 程惟湘]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>黎花英</mainName>
    <names>[刘胡兰, 黄, 文英, 杨圩梨, 黎花英, 曲调婉, 彭金花, 负心郎, 杜十娘, 邬成香, 高安, 高安采, 李甲, 乐之筐格, 王骥德, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>齐信英</mainName>
    <names>[陈荣启, 吕梁, 赵英颇, 郭启儒]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>齐和昌</mainName>
    <names>[宋德, 梅兰, 沈三玉, 王铁侠, 田荣芬, 李洪春, 郭庆鹏, 张永禄, 武花脸, 童葆苓, 齐和昌, 曹玺彦, 宋德珠, 荀慧, 宋江, 杨家, 诸连顺, 李盛斌, 昌仍, 钱荣顺, 奚延宏, 郭盛亭, 袁世涌]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>齐啸云</mainName>
    <names>[包拯, ，, 李少春, 吴素秋, 尚小云, 张学良, 梅兰芳, 李勇奇, 云吟, 王海波, 中寄托, 刘磊, 包龙, 郝寿臣, 李书记, 钱宝森, 张君秋, 马连良, 袁世海, 习练, 马佥, 马, 马料里, 巴凯, 秋胡, 燕京]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>齐花坦</mainName>
    <names>[裴艳玲, 桂兰, 李淑惠, 燕赵, 杨排风, 庞家佐, 孙玉姣, 茅庐]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>龚云甫</mainName>
    <names>[徐母骂, 龚云甫, 陈德霖, 曹, 杨小楼, 梅兰芳, 刘桂庆, 刘鸿声]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>龚传华</mainName>
    <names>[马传菁, 龚传华, 吴义生, 龚仁]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>龚苏萍</mainName>
    <names>[杨二嫂, 孙毓敏, 马前, 龚苏萍]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>朱凤桐</mainName>
    <names>[赵燕侠, 杨丽丽, 赵绮霞, 王熙凤, 樊, 苏三, 法门寺, 汪伪, 朱慧芳, 王紫苓, 吴素秋, 张派, 王多芬, 荀慧生, 徐凌云, 何玉凤, 狄云鸾, 张艳秋, 俞步兰, 朱, 刘媒婆, 朱所授, 张金, 荀, 宋巧姣, 奚啸伯, 朱凤桐, 吴富琴, 薛金莲, 王宝钏, 胡, 万氏, 程砚秋, 霍小玉, 苏武, 汪精卫, 萧太, 杨素贞, 孙玉姣, 朱老]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>林懋荣</mainName>
    <names>[侯梦兰, 杨宝忠, 魏莲芳, 李玉泰, 谭富英, 朗, 梅兰芳, 孟庆惠, 姜妙香, 李崇善, 孔雀东南, 岳惠玲]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>温宇航</mainName>
    <names>[吕布, 凤仪杯, 传马玉森, 蔡正仁, 沈世华, 于逸夫, 王泰琪, 温宇航, 张毓文, 双语昆, 汪世瑜, 张世铮, 张洵澎, 洪雪飞, 林肯, 白兔, 朱世藕, 刘国庆]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>王紫苓</mainName>
    <names>[荀慧生, 马旦, 尤擅, 王紫苓]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>裴艳玲</mainName>
    <names>[裴艳玲, 郭师, 郭景春, 郭结为]</names>
  </person>
  <person>
    <mainName>韩俊卿</mainName>
    <names>[孔雀东南飞, 韩派, 韩月恒, 韩俊卿, 秦香]</names>
  </person>
</root>
